<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><?xml-stylesheet href='http://www.blogger.com/styles/atom.css' type='text/css'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/">
    <id>hydromatic-ggro</id>
    <updated>2010-12-05T14:01:19.917-0800</updated>
    <title type="text">GGRO daily hawkwatch update</title>
    <link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml" rel="next" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml" rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#feed" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <author>
      <name>GGRO</name>
      <uri>http://www.ggro.org</uri>
      <email>ggro@parksconservancy.org</email>
    </author>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101205</id><published>2010-12-05T14:01:19.917-0800</published><updated>2010-12-05T14:01:19.917-0800</updated><title>Sunday, December 05, 2010</title><content type="html">Determined and defiant, the Sunday II team was not about to let a little wind and rain stop us from spending at least some of the 2010 season's final day up on Hawk Hill. And so we scaled the hill one last time, arriving to sheets of rain billowing down from above. After counting a few raptors here and there, we decided we had endured for as long as we could and descended to 1064 for a potluck feast. Fittingly enough, the season's last bird turned out to be an adult Redtail spotted stilling over South Slacker around 11 a.m. just before the rain washed us off the hill. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;A big thank you goes out to all our hawkwatchers who made this sometimes trying but altogether memorable 2010 season a success. Hope to see you all up top next fall.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 24&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 1.5&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 16&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 15&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101205" rel="alternate" title="Sunday, December 05, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101205" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jonathan Stein</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101204</id><published>2010-12-04T16:12:14.258-0800</published><updated>2010-12-04T16:12:14.258-0800</updated><title>Saturday, December 04, 2010</title><content type="html">Saturday II rounded out its season with a tasty potluck featuring homemade grape leaves, quesadillas, veggie platters, many baked goods, and a variety of fine beverages (alas, no mulled wine). After a morning rain shower, a drizzle threatened the douse the day when the team arrived at Hawk Hill at 10:30. However, conditions improved to an ambient gray with faint winds and interesting cloud formations. There is not much in this entry about hawks because there were not many to be seen. After two hours of counting, the total stood at a whopping three. Though this improved to 60 by the end of the day, not much was moving in the Headlands today. The first Turkey Vulture didn't show up until 1:00, though the banders reported sighting a Ferruginous Hawk in the direction of the FM tower. Despite the low raptor numbers, what was to be had was a good time and good company as the season came to a close. Thanks to everyone for making hawkwatch a blast!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 60&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 4.75&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 12.63&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 17&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 33&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101204" rel="alternate" title="Saturday, December 04, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101204" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Lindsay Addison</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101203</id><published>2010-12-03T16:06:32.203-0800</published><updated>2010-12-03T16:06:32.203-0800</updated><title>Friday, December 03, 2010</title><content type="html">A slow but jubilant last day for Friday II! Highlights included a juvenile Red-shouldered hawk, a beautiful glimpse of a male American Kestrel, and a few Accipiters. We enjoyed our time together and with the hawks this season. Congratulations to the newlyweds in the 2 o'clock hour. That was the HawkWatch cheering for you.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 72&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 5&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 14.4&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 7&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 28&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 31&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 7&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101203" rel="alternate" title="Friday, December 03, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101203" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Anastasia Ennis</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101202</id><published>2010-12-02T16:04:19.544-0800</published><updated>2010-12-02T16:04:19.544-0800</updated><title>Thursday, December 02, 2010</title><content type="html">Thursday II's final hawkwatch of 2010 took place under gray skies and ended half an hour early, thanks to the weatherman's promised rain showers. In between, however, the team treated itself to a fine potluck meal, fine drink, and a whopping 67 raptor sightings. A distinct lack of wind and the dropping barometer seemed to keep the raptors, including even those in Kirby Cove, perched and out of the skies. Although the hawks were almost uniformly high and distant, some lucky watchers got to take in an adult Cooper's Hawk before it disappeared behind Middle Kingdom, and a Northern Harrier was spotted in the North Saddle hanging out with two Turkey Vultures. Outside of raptors, the team diligently tallied tweets, including a charming Hermit Thrush, and nine different types of ocean-going vessels. It might have been a slow day, but spirits were high, and the season ended with good cheer.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 67&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 5.5&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 12.18&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 44&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 17&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101202" rel="alternate" title="Thursday, December 02, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101202" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Lindsay Addison</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101201</id><published>2010-12-01T16:10:30.219-0800</published><updated>2010-12-01T16:10:30.219-0800</updated><title>Wednesday, December 01, 2010</title><content type="html">The Wednesday II team ended its season on a high note today, rounding out the year with great food, great drink and great looks at one fabulous juvenile Ferruginous Hawk during our last-day potluck. After soup and salad, the ferrug decided to interrupt desert by rising up in front of Hill 88 and proceeding to meander around the Headlands for 15 long, luscious minutes, offering everyone up on Hawk Hill the opportunity to affix their gaze upon its gleaming white breast and pointed wings for as long as they liked. Truly a wonderful bird to end our season on. In addition to the Ferruginous Hawk, the day also featured the close inspection of a lovely White-tailed Kite and several head-turning looks at some swift Peregrine Falcons.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 132&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 5.5&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 24&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 9&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 46&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 68&lt;br/&gt;
Ferruginous Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101201" rel="alternate" title="Wednesday, December 01, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101201" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jonathan Stein</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101130</id><published>2010-11-30T16:02:07.067-0800</published><updated>2010-11-30T16:02:07.067-0800</updated><title>Tuesday, November 30, 2010</title><content type="html">Tuesday II's season ended with a potluck smorgasbord, a chilly wind, and 105 hawks. While the team feasted on chili, crab dip, coleslaw, cornbread, crackers, chips, and tasty hot drinks and deserts that did not begin with the letter "C" some raptors did pass through the headlands. At least three juvenile Red-tailed Hawks were seen flapping across the Golden Gate, and several juvenile Northern Harriers coursed the hills in search of prey. However, the only the Accipiter spotted by hawkwatch today had to be presented in the form of an ID study by Hawk Blind. Perhaps the haze that lingered all day will lift later in the week and more late hawks will pass through. As the end of another season for Tuesday II drew to a close, the resident ravens were circling, hoping to find some crumbs left behind from another good day on Hawk Hill.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 105&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 5.67&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 18.52&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 39&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 51&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101130" rel="alternate" title="Tuesday, November 30, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101130" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Lindsay Addison</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101129</id><published>2010-11-29T16:50:46.470-0800</published><updated>2010-11-29T16:50:46.470-0800</updated><title>Monday, November 29, 2010</title><content type="html">The Monday II Hawkwatch team observed some fantastic birds today on Hawk Hill!  Early on, a hawkwatcher in South quadrant spotted an enormous brown raptor over Conzelman Road. The bird was missing random flight feathers and had a scruffy appearance overall. Almost immediately after the bird appeared, an adult Red-tailed Hawk, who was perched nearby, sounded its battle cry and flew up to stoop on the mystery bird.  However, in terms of size, the Red-tailed Hawk was miniscule by comparison!  As the dark raptor flew right by Hawk Hill, the hawkwatchers looked up and saw white axillary feathers on the bird's underwing, which allowed us to identify the bird as a juvenile Bald Eagle!  But the fun didn't end there.  The hawkwatchers also were treated to great looks at a low flying Peregrine, a juvenile Red-shouldered Hawk, and a light-morph Swainson's Hawk.  Finally, in the late afternoon, a magnificent bird with an exceedingly long neck was spotted over the ocean.  The bird turned out to be a Sandhill Crane, a species that is rarely seen in the Bay Area (these birds can be viewed in large numbers around the Central Valley and Delta during the winter)!  Overall, a fantastic day to be up on Hawk Hill!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 171&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 6&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 28.5&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 10&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 53&lt;br/&gt;
Bald Eagle: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Swainson's Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 88&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 3&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101129" rel="alternate" title="Monday, November 29, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101129" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Genevieve Rozhon</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101128</id><published>2010-11-28T16:53:28.084-0800</published><updated>2010-11-28T16:53:28.084-0800</updated><title>Sunday, November 28, 2010</title><content type="html">The Sunday I Hawkwatchers finished the season in style, with a respectable total of two hundred and eight hawks counted.  This included your garden variety raptors as well as twelve Northern Harriers, a White-tailed Kite, seven Peregrine Falcons, and an intermediate-morph Swainson's Hawk.  The Swainson's Hawk was first spotted over Wolfback Ridge, and stuck around long enough for many of the Hawkwatchers to observe it in a spotting scope.  Of the adult Peregrine Falcons counted, several swept right over the top of Hawk Hill, allowing those Hawkwatchers with cameras to snap some excellent ventral shots of the birds.  One of the Peregrines flew so low over the hill that we could make out its enormous bulging crop with our naked eye!  Talk about a serious snack!  The count ended with two juvenile Northern Harriers who were spotted having a comical play-fight above Rodeo Valley Trail.  Thanks for a fantastic season Sunday I!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 208&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 6&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 34.7&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 9&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 80&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 12&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Swainson's Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 91&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 10&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 7&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 4&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101128" rel="alternate" title="Sunday, November 28, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101128" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Genevieve Rozhon</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101127</id><published>2010-11-29T12:32:17.001-0800</published><updated>2010-11-29T12:32:17.001-0800</updated><title>Saturday, November 27, 2010</title><content type="html">Saturday's team was rained out, the hawkwatch was called off that day.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 0&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 0&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 0&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101127" rel="alternate" title="Saturday, November 27, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101127" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jill</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101126</id><published>2010-11-26T16:43:41.153-0800</published><updated>2010-11-26T16:43:41.153-0800</updated><title>Friday, November 26, 2010</title><content type="html">Friday I finished its season with a hazy but beautiful day on the hill. Quite a few Red-tailed Hawks flew close by overhead, and a juvenile White-tailed Kite flew by at close range early in the morning. Other birds spotted included several Northern Harriers, a few male American Kestrels, and a speedy Merlin which was being attacked by an adult Red-tail. It had no trouble evading the bigger bird. Then, at nearly 3:30 the banders reported seeing a Rough-legged Hawk on Middle Kingdom; however, it was perched on the opposite side of the hill from hawkwatch, and when it flew, the hawkwatchers could not spot it. A thorough and excited scour of the petri dish field found only one juvenile Northern Harrier and two dueling juvenile Red-tails. They alternately sulked in coyote bushes and tangled on the ground, one on its back, the other standing on top. Although it was fun to watch the wrestling match the team would have preferred to snag the pizza bird. Despite the lack of luck in that department, the hawkwatchers are going to enjoy an end-of-season meal at Dario's anyway.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 145&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 5.83&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 24.86&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 9&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 40&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 87&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101126" rel="alternate" title="Friday, November 26, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101126" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Lindsay Addison</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101125</id><published>2010-11-25T16:14:14.951-0800</published><updated>2010-11-25T16:14:14.951-0800</updated><title>Thursday, November 25, 2010</title><content type="html">The Thursday I Thanksgiving Day hawkwatchers went out with a bang when a juvenile Golden Eagle was spotted in the last half hour. West had it first, then it made its way over to Middle Kingdom and Slacker, showing off its golden head and bright white tail. Everyone on the hill was able to enjoy great looks at this spectacular bird. Earlier in the day, the team had a field day with Northern Harriers, spotting nine all told including a female and several pumpkin-breasted juveniles. Few Accipiters were to be had, with one adult Sharp-shinned paying a morning visit followed by a few juveniles. However, the Red-tailed Hawks were in fine form. Two adults took turns stooping on a juvenile in Kirby Cove, and several soared over the hill. Other notable raptors included a there-and-gone Merlin and a White-tailed Kite. Fun non-raptors included a group of Glaucous-winged Gulls and a floatilla of Surf Scoters. The 175 hawks--and assorted tweets--that graced Hawk Hill today made it a fine end to Thursday I's season.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 175&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 6&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 29.17&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 9&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 68&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 9&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 82&lt;br/&gt;
Golden Eagle: 1&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 2&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101125" rel="alternate" title="Thursday, November 25, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101125" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Lindsay Addison</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101124</id><published>2010-11-24T16:31:33.294-0800</published><updated>2010-11-24T16:31:33.294-0800</updated><title>Wednesday, November 24, 2010</title><content type="html">A strong morning push of migrating raptors and great looks at a juvenile Bald Eagle brought smiles to the faces of a delighted Wednesday I team today. During the early going, a sizable number of juvenile Red-tailed Hawks were joined by a few juvenile Cooper's Hawks and a wonderful juvenile Ferruginous Hawk who showed off a bit for the onlookers below before making its way toward the city. Later on in the day, the juvenile Bald Eagle graced us with its presence circling up high well over our heads before gliding away. Additionally, there was some speculation that a pair of large raptors flying steadily over San Francisco were in fact Golden Eagles but the birds were first sighted at a great distance and identification could not be confirmed. They both went down as unidentified raptors.        &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 142&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 6&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 23.7&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 10&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 40&lt;br/&gt;
Bald Eagle: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 74&lt;br/&gt;
Ferruginous Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 6&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101124" rel="alternate" title="Wednesday, November 24, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101124" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jonathan Stein</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101123</id><published>2010-11-23T15:50:59.880-0800</published><updated>2010-11-23T15:50:59.880-0800</updated><title>Tuesday, November 23, 2010</title><content type="html">A cold and gusty day with hawks few and far between. We did have some distant Red-tailed hawks about and some acrobatic Peregrines dancing around the Golden Gate Bridge. We felt fortunate that the clouds cleared after an initial shower so that our team could be up on the hill for its last day.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 74&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 5&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 14.8&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 35&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 30&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 4&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101123" rel="alternate" title="Tuesday, November 23, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101123" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Anastasia Ennis</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101122</id><published>2010-11-22T16:38:21.888-0800</published><updated>2010-11-22T16:38:21.888-0800</updated><title>Monday, November 22, 2010</title><content type="html">Rain threatened to run Monday 1 off the hill early today, but luckily for us, the rain subsided and we were able to spend a full day counting hawks. Red-tailed Hawks were fairly active throughout the day and a few American Kestrels, a lone Cooper's Hawk and a Peregrine Falcon were also seen. The day's highlight proved to be a distant White-tailed Kite repeatedly diving at a Redtail that must have been doing something exceedingly irritating.  &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 58&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 6&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 9.7&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 17&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 34&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101122" rel="alternate" title="Monday, November 22, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101122" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jonathan Stein</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101121</id><published>2010-11-21T16:11:55.833-0800</published><updated>2010-11-21T16:11:55.833-0800</updated><title>Sunday, November 21, 2010</title><content type="html">Fearful of a third consecutive rain out, the Sunday II team was delighted to find mostly blue skies and a light breeze up on the hill for most of the day today. Red-tailed Hawks dominated the count but Peregrine Falcons stole the show. Peregrines were spotted circling up over Hawk Hill, shooting through the clouds over Alcatraz and, on several occasions, diving at Red-tailed Hawks who had the misfortune of wandering into their airspace. They proved to be quite the spectacle on this day.    &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 91&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 5.5&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 16.6&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 7&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 26&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 51&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101121" rel="alternate" title="Sunday, November 21, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101121" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jonathan Stein</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101120</id><published>2010-11-20T15:13:16.464-0800</published><updated>2010-11-20T15:13:16.464-0800</updated><title>Saturday, November 20, 2010</title><content type="html">Saturday II spent a blustery day on Hawk Hill, counting in conditions best described as "cold." The day started with a drizzle and ended with looming storm clouds. The south winds did not bring many hawks, either. A total of 73 were tallied, and among those birds were only two Accipiters (two Sharp-shinned Hawks). However, four Peregrine Falcons came overhead, and a pair of Red-tailed Hawks--one adult and one juvenile--put on a show of dog fighting for several minutes with spectacular stoops and rolls. With a dark, menacing cloud approaching from the north, the watch was called an hour early.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 73&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 5&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 14.6&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 30&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 35&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 4&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101120" rel="alternate" title="Saturday, November 20, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101120" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Lindsay Addison</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101119</id><published>2010-11-20T15:16:02.548-0800</published><updated>2010-11-20T15:16:02.548-0800</updated><title>Friday, November 19, 2010</title><content type="html">Hawkwatch was rained out today. The team took a walk around the Lagoon and decided there would be no clearing. As it turned out, they were right. It rained almost all day in the Headlands.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 0&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 0&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 0&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101119" rel="alternate" title="Friday, November 19, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101119" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Anastasia</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101118</id><published>2010-11-18T16:19:37.790-0800</published><updated>2010-11-18T16:19:37.790-0800</updated><title>Thursday, November 18, 2010</title><content type="html">A good number of hawks today! Mostly Turkey Vultures and Red-tailed Hawks in the cloud-speckled skies, but we had some nice White-tailed Kite sightings, a few Peregrines, and a smattering of Accipiters. These sightings along with 3 juvenile Northern Harriers kept us warm on a brisk late autumn day.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 267&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 6&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 44.5&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 8&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 116&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 115&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101118" rel="alternate" title="Thursday, November 18, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101118" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Anastasia Ennis</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101117</id><published>2010-11-17T15:26:24.342-0800</published><updated>2010-11-17T15:26:24.342-0800</updated><title>Wednesday, November 17, 2010</title><content type="html">Raptors were few and far between for the Wednesday II team today. A White-tailed Kite here, a Peregrine Falcon there, a couple Northern Harriers, a few accipiters and a bunch of Turkey Vultures and Red-tailed Hawks were all the team could muster. The rapidly encroaching fog eventually swallowed us whole at 2 p.m. at which point the watch was called.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 86&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 5&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 17.2&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 8&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 22&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 41&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101117" rel="alternate" title="Wednesday, November 17, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101117" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jonathan Stein</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101116</id><published>2010-11-16T16:10:37.239-0800</published><updated>2010-11-16T16:10:37.239-0800</updated><title>Tuesday, November 16, 2010</title><content type="html">It was a warm day on Hawk Hill with light winds out of the north to northwest. The Tuesday II team also found it to be a slow day for hawks, counting a total of 155 raptors at a rate of about 26 hawks per hour. However, the team was rewarded with some good looks at Merlins. One obligingly perched on a snag in the pines and another shot up out of Kirby Cove and then circled--slowly for a falcon--in full view for a few minutes. Some White-tailed Kits and a handful of dark-morph Red-tailed Hawks (all juveniles) were also seen, to lend an air of variety to the count.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 159&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 6&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 26.5&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 9&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 63&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 10&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 62&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101116" rel="alternate" title="Tuesday, November 16, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101116" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Lindsay Addison</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101115</id><published>2010-11-15T16:38:14.378-0800</published><updated>2010-11-15T16:38:14.378-0800</updated><title>Monday, November 15, 2010</title><content type="html">It was a blustery day for the Monday II Hawkwatch team on Hawk hill.  With north winds reaching almost twenty miles an hour, it was a chore simply to keep our spotting scopes upright!  In contrast, the hawks migrating through the Headlands were definitely making use of the strong winds. The team saw great variety of raptors today, including several Ferruginous Hawks, a Swainson's Hawk, a handful of dark morph Red-tailed Hawks, and two White-tailed Kites. Although Rough-legged Hawks have yet to be seen from Hawk Hill this season, perhaps tomorrow's Hawkwatch team will count one!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 214&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 6&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 35.7&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 12&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 71&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 29&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Swainson's Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 80&lt;br/&gt;
Ferruginous Hawk: 3&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 9&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101115" rel="alternate" title="Monday, November 15, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101115" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Genevieve Rozhon</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101114</id><published>2010-11-14T16:57:12.015-0800</published><updated>2010-11-14T16:57:12.015-0800</updated><title>Sunday, November 14, 2010</title><content type="html">What do dark morph Red-tailed Hawks, White-tailed Kites, and Peregrine Falcons make?  A fantastic day for the Sunday I Hawkwatch team!  North winds, visibility all the way to San Jose, and mild temperatures also served as great weather conditions for migratory raptors.  The Hawkwatch team counted a fairly steady stream of raptors all day long.  Several raptors including a male Northern Harrier, a White-tailed Kite, and a beautiful dark brown Red-tailed Hawk right sailed right past the Hawkwatch (to our delight!).  At the end of the day, the team also was able to see GGRO's new telemetry bird, a juvenile female Red-tailed Hawk, released from Hawk Hill.  The GGRO telemetry team will track this bird in order to collect data on Red-tailed Hawk migration/dispersal patterns in California.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 346&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 6&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 57.7&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 10&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 44&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 11&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 44&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 34&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 164&lt;br/&gt;
Ferruginous Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 12&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 11&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 10&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 2&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101114" rel="alternate" title="Sunday, November 14, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101114" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Genevieve Rozhon</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101113</id><published>2010-11-13T16:20:46.628-0800</published><updated>2010-11-13T16:20:46.628-0800</updated><title>Saturday, November 13, 2010</title><content type="html">Best day ever for Saturday I's team! In the clear blue sky with some light breeze we had an adult Bald Eagle heading south along the coast. We also spotted a dark morph Swainson's Hawk, four dark morph Red-tailed Hawks, two White-tailed Kites, six Peregrine falcons, five Merlins, and eight Northern Harriers, including an adult male. We had some great looks at juvenile Red-shouldered Hawks and adult Accipiters. After a long string of foggy Saturdays, we couldn't have asked for a more pleasant day to watch hawks.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 287&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 6&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 47.83&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 12&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 113&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Bald Eagle: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 18&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 20&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Swainson's Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 93&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 9&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101113" rel="alternate" title="Saturday, November 13, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101113" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Anastasia Ennis</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101112</id><published>2010-11-12T16:13:44.837-0800</published><updated>2010-11-12T16:13:44.837-0800</updated><title>Friday, November 12, 2010</title><content type="html">The skies were blue, the winds were light, the temperatures were mild, and there were not very many hawks for today's hawkwatch team to count. The hawks that were seen seemed to come in small clusters of activity interspersed with periods of watching a painted lady butterfly or two blimps circle the Bay. Several Sharp-shinned Hawks again paid the hill a close visit, rising out of Kirby Cove and circling at close quarters. Juvenile Northern Harriers also provided some entertaining looks out over the valley and a handful of Merlins shot the Golden Gate, southbound. Finally, a Cooper's Hawk thrashed energetically around a coyote bush on the slope of Rocky Ridge, frenetically trying to flush a small bird. It eventually succeeded but its prey and it escaped out of the hawkwatchers' sight.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 136&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 5.8&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 23.3&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 7&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 31&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 17&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 9&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 64&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 2&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101112" rel="alternate" title="Friday, November 12, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101112" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Lindsay Addison</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101111</id><published>2010-11-11T16:16:05.788-0800</published><updated>2010-11-11T16:16:05.788-0800</updated><title>Thursday, November 11, 2010</title><content type="html">The Thursday I hawkwatch team made it to Hawk Hill bright and early and was greeted with a juvenile Northern Harrier and strong winds that gusted up to twenty miles per hour. Fortunately, the wind died down after an hour or so, leaving the team with a beautiful day. The count was good for the first several hours, and some Sharp-shinned Hawks were spotted at close quarters as they wrapped around the hill, pushed by the wind. But the day's highlight was watching a juvenile Red-shouldered Hawk stoop on one of the blinds and be captured successfully. As the day went on, the raptor flow died down: hawks, it seems, do not change their clocks, so by 3:00 the skies were pretty empty. At the end of the day four species had reached double-digit numbers--Red-tailed Hawks, Turkey Vultures, Sharp-shinned Hawks, and Cooper's Hawks--and nine species had been seen.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 270&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 6&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 45&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 9&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 92&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 35&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 11&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 119&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101111" rel="alternate" title="Thursday, November 11, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101111" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Lindsay Addison</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101110</id><published>2010-11-10T16:39:13.809-0800</published><updated>2010-11-10T16:39:13.809-0800</updated><title>Wednesday, November 10, 2010</title><content type="html">Back up on our regular hill, the Wednesday I team spent six hours scouring the sky for raptors on this clear, crisp November day. Red-shouldered Hawks were the spectacle early as a handful of birds, including a brightly red-breasted adult, were seen here and there during the morning. Red-tailed Hawks and Cooper's Hawks dominated the midday hours before a few furious falcons entered the fray and grabbed the attention of the group near day's end when a 2:00 Merlin blasted through the sky and a smattering of adult Peregrine Falcons circled up over the hill, delighting the pleased onlookers below.   &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 175&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 6&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 29.2&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 9&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 51&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 15&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 80&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 2&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101110" rel="alternate" title="Wednesday, November 10, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101110" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jonathan Stein</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101109</id><published>2010-11-09T16:00:56.982-0800</published><updated>2010-11-09T16:00:56.982-0800</updated><title>Tuesday, November 09, 2010</title><content type="html">The day started off great! Our first sighting was an Osprey, and then a juvenile Peregrine passed right by the hill. The skies were clear, the wind was just a light breeze and off in the distance to the northwest we saw a juvenile Bald Eagle! It came closer as it headed south, passing by us and heading over the Gate into San Francisco. We were able to tell from its plumage that it was likely in its first year. We saw the usual suspects for the rest of the day, most of them up high. We had several Merlins come by, always exciting. The clouds rolled in at around 2:30 and we started to feel some rain drops, so we high-tailed it off the hill.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 178&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 5.58&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 31.88&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 10&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 49&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Bald Eagle: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 27&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 66&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 3&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101109" rel="alternate" title="Tuesday, November 09, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101109" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Anastasia Ennis</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101108</id><published>2010-11-08T17:17:03.215-0800</published><updated>2010-11-08T17:17:03.215-0800</updated><title>Monday, November 08, 2010</title><content type="html">It was quality over quantity for the Monday I team today as a handful of interesting sightings helped to keep the team alert and engaged for most of the day. The morning was dominated by Peregrine Falcon activity with several adult and juvenile birds seen. At one point, the team was split between watching two adult Peregrines circling high in the clouds overhead and a juvenile Peregrine slashing through the sky over Slacker Hill. Later on after the Peregrine show came to an end, a trio of tantalizing birds created quite a lot of buzz up on the hill. The first was a juvenile Swainson's Hawk making a rare early November appearance in the Headlands. Next was an adult female Northern Harrier who rose up right in front of the hill offering up splendid looks. And last was a bird still being discussed by hawkwatchers hours after it was spotted, a possible light morph Harlan's Hawk that circled up and then made a beeline for Kirby Cove.        &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 209&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 6&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 34.8&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 11&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 48&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 29&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 17&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Swainson's Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 76&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 12&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101108" rel="alternate" title="Monday, November 08, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101108" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jonathan Stein</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101107</id><published>2010-11-07T08:55:21.786-0800</published><updated>2010-11-07T08:55:21.786-0800</updated><title>Sunday, November 07, 2010</title><content type="html">The rain started early and kept on coming resulting in another hawkwatch wash out for the Sunday II team. Here's hoping next time out showers us with raptors instead.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 0&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 0&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 0&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101107" rel="alternate" title="Sunday, November 07, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101107" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jonathan Stein</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101106</id><published>2010-11-06T14:00:48.649-0700</published><updated>2010-11-06T14:00:48.649-0700</updated><title>Saturday, November 06, 2010</title><content type="html">Although there is still road work being done, Conzelman and McCullough opened to the public on November 6. (For more see the ggro.org main page.) The Saturday II team made it to the hill, sans construction hats and vests for the first time in 2010 only to find that a thick bank of fog had rolled in. After sticking it out for about three hours, they headed back down and took a walk on the Bobcat Trail. There a Kestrel was harassing a Red-tailed Hawk and a coyote was hunting rodents. The fog did eventually clear, revealing a beautiful day, but only after the hawkwatchers' day had been called. However, everyone enjoyed the return to "normalcy" on Hawk Hill.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 0&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 0&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 0&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101106" rel="alternate" title="Saturday, November 06, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101106" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Lindsay</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101105</id><published>2010-11-05T16:25:07.351-0700</published><updated>2010-11-05T16:25:07.351-0700</updated><title>Friday, November 05, 2010</title><content type="html">We waited out the fog and were rewarded with some birds in the early afternoon! The fog moved in and out and the temperature dropped as the wind picked up but we saw a few Peregrines, some Merlins, distant Northern Harriers, and adult Accipiters.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 112&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 3&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 37.33&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 9&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 14&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 35&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 35&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101105" rel="alternate" title="Friday, November 05, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101105" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Anastasia Ennis</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101104</id><published>2010-11-04T16:30:23.742-0700</published><updated>2010-11-04T16:30:23.742-0700</updated><title>Thursday, November 04, 2010</title><content type="html">Lately the flow of hawks has picked up, and today's hawkwatch team continued that trend with 329 sightings, 10 species, and 54.8 hawks per hour. The day started off with strong northeast winds which slowly backed off throughout the afternoon and eventually swung around to the north. Leading the species count were Red-tailed Hawks, followed closely by Turkey Vultures. Cooper's Hawks and Sharp-shinned Hawks were also on tap all day. The Sharpies in particular had to fight the morning's wind and many shot around the hill with wings tucked. Rarer hawks seen included Northern Harriers, one of which was a male, seven Peregrine Falcons, and one dark-morph Swainson's Hawk, which was escorted by two adult Red-tails and one disgruntled Peregrine. The team picked up its tenth species in the last fifteen minutes of watching--a juvenile Red-shouldered Hawk that winged in from Mt. Tamalpais.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 329&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 6&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 54.83&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 10&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 104&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 67&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 20&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Swainson's Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 105&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 7&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 3&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101104" rel="alternate" title="Thursday, November 04, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101104" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Lindsay Addison</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101103</id><published>2010-11-03T16:54:24.077-0700</published><updated>2010-11-03T16:54:24.077-0700</updated><title>Wednesday, November 03, 2010</title><content type="html">The Sharp-shinned Hawks were on the move in a big way today. Buoyed by a bountiful early November Sharpie flight that included a good-sized number of blue-backed, rufous-barred adults, the Wednesday II team tallied the largest hawks per hour total in a little over two weeks during a pleasant near six hour day up on the hill. In addition, the team was also treated to a wonderfully close encounter with a juvenile Ferruginous Hawk who rose up from the valley and circled the hill before departing in the direction of San Francisco. And before that Ferruginous Hawk made its presence felt, the team got to glimpse an adult Peregrine Falcon making a spectacular dive on a juvenile Peregrine most unwelcome in its airspace. &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 394&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 5.8&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 67.9&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 9&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 98&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 141&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 21&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 101&lt;br/&gt;
Ferruginous Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 11&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 9&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 3&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101103" rel="alternate" title="Wednesday, November 03, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101103" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jonathan Stein</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101102</id><published>2010-11-02T16:32:24.131-0700</published><updated>2010-11-02T16:32:24.131-0700</updated><title>Tuesday, November 02, 2010</title><content type="html">Today's hawkwatch saw high surf at the lagoon, clear skies overhead, and a fair flow of hawks. At the end of the afternoon, the team had tallied 249 hawks representing 7 species. The day's highlight by far were the 15 Merlins seen from the hill. Four seen in the morning were supplemented by 11 in the afternoon, by which time "Merlin, schmerlin" jokes were in order. Not only were they plentiful, several passed close by, affording good looks, and at least one was seen nabbing a dragonfly in midair and it eating on the wing. Also exciting was a group of 4 White-tailed Kites that winged up the valley, showing off their beautiful plumage. Other birds seen included early-morning large flocks of Band-tailed Pigeons, and--of more importance--good numbers of Accipiters and Red-tailed Hawks.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 249&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 5.75&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 43.3&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 10&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 56&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 62&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 20&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 73&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 15&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101102" rel="alternate" title="Tuesday, November 02, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101102" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Lindsay Addison</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101101</id><published>2010-11-01T16:43:58.704-0700</published><updated>2010-11-01T16:43:58.704-0700</updated><title>Monday, November 01, 2010</title><content type="html">The raptors are still on the move!  Another day of clear skies, mild easterly winds, and moderate temperatures served as perfect conditions for our taloned migrants to move through the Headlands.  Red-tailed Hawks still dominated the count, with juveniles outnumbering adults.  Blue-backed accipiters, White-tailed Kites, an adult male Northern Harrier, and numerous Merlin also were "oooohed and aaaahed" over by the Hawkwatch team today.  However, the creme de la creme for the day was a juvenile Ferruginous Hawk.  It was spotted riding a thermal above Hawk Hill.  I think it's safe to say that no GGRO hawkwatcher gets tired of seeing those milky giants!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 272&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 5.75&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 47.3&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 11&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 84&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 41&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 29&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 95&lt;br/&gt;
Ferruginous Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 4&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101101" rel="alternate" title="Monday, November 01, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101101" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Genevieve Rozhon</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101031</id><published>2010-10-31T16:50:26.766-0700</published><updated>2010-10-31T16:50:26.766-0700</updated><title>Sunday, October 31, 2010</title><content type="html">Sunny skies this morning were a welcome change from the wet weather the Headlands experienced over the last few days.  Apparently, the hawks thought so too, because they were out and about in full force.  Today's Hawkwatch team counted ten species of raptors for a total count of nearly three hundred birds.  White-throated Swifts and Violet-green Swallows also filled the skies in the early morning, catching bugs and performing loop-de-loops in the air.  Adult and juvenile Red-tailed comprised the majority of raptorial birds counted.  Several groups of these adult Red-tails were spotted talon grappling during the day.  Peregrines, Merlins, and White-tailed Kites were also observed powering on through the Headlands.  If the nice weather keeps up, tomorrow's Hawkwatch team should get to observe some great birds as well.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 299&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 6&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 49.8&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 10&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 65&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 11&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 17&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 165&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101031" rel="alternate" title="Sunday, October 31, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101031" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Genevieve Rozhon</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101030</id><published>2010-10-30T13:15:37.105-0700</published><updated>2010-10-30T13:15:37.105-0700</updated><title>Saturday, October 30, 2010</title><content type="html">Clear skies in the morning gave us hope and we did indeed see some accipiters in the mist! A pair of ravens kept us company while we gazed into the haze in hopes of seeing some raptors. We had to suspend our count for an hour while we waited for some squalls to pass, but the continued fog and eventual downpour chased us off the hill.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 16&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 2&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 8&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 2&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101030" rel="alternate" title="Saturday, October 30, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101030" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Anastasia Ennis</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101029</id><published>2010-10-29T16:07:14.066-0700</published><updated>2010-10-29T16:07:14.066-0700</updated><title>Friday, October 29, 2010</title><content type="html">It was another cloudy, overcast day at hawkwatch, and one where the hawks were few and far between but some good sightings were to be had. A small team of four braved the predictions for rain and inclement weather--which never fully materialized--to see a juvenile rufous-morph Red-tailed Hawk, two adult Peregrine Falcons, and a Merlin. All four birds flew near or directly over the hill, providing nice looks. Other birds seen included a smattering of Accipiters, both juveniles and adults. They tended to pop up from Kirby Cove and power quickly across the Golden Gate, looking for sunny skies to the south. As the afternoon progressed, fewer hawks were sighted, but two Common Ravens appeared and croaked sweetly to each other, providing entertainment for the hawkwatchers.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 65&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 5.75&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 11.3&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 7&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 26&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 10&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 18&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 2&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101029" rel="alternate" title="Friday, October 29, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101029" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Lindsay Addison</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101028</id><published>2010-10-28T16:27:42.028-0700</published><updated>2010-10-28T16:27:42.028-0700</updated><title>Thursday, October 28, 2010</title><content type="html">It has been said that on days before frontal systems arrive, hawk counts are either really good or really poor, and today it was the later. Thursday I's hawkwatch team anticipated the possibility of a rainy day, but found only gray skies and peculiar cloud formations on the hill. The team also found hawks, but had only 110 total sightings. Leading the coolness pack, however, were two dark-morph birds: an adult Red-tailed Hawk and a juvenile Swainson's Hawk. Both provided good looks. Sharp-shinned Hawks beat out Cooper's Hawks by far, at 30 to 4, and in an unusual move, the team sighted more Red-tailed Hawks than Turkey Vultures. The weather cooperated all day long, with not a single drop of rain falling, all four bridges in view to the south, and the wind only picking up in the last hour or so. &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 110&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 6&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 18.33&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 9&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 14&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 30&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Swainson's Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 34&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 10&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 2&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101028" rel="alternate" title="Thursday, October 28, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101028" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Lindsay Addison</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101027</id><published>2010-10-27T16:15:25.649-0700</published><updated>2010-10-27T16:15:25.649-0700</updated><title>Wednesday, October 27, 2010</title><content type="html">The Wednesday I team enjoyed a breezy, laid-back day up on the hill today with a sprinkling of intriguing sightings--including a late Swainson's Hawk, the fourth seen this season--keeping the team engaged throughout. The Swainson's Hawk, first sighted low against the rolling hills of the Headlands, eventually rose up and sailed right over a delighted group of hawkwatchers offering up spectacular looks. The day was also a good one for Northern Harriers, adult Sharp-shinned Hawks and especially Merlins, several of whom sped by the hill for up close and personal encounters. Songbird-wise, Varied Thrushes continue to be seen in greater numbers and a few more Evening Grosbeaks also graced us with their presence.       &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 144&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 5&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 28.8&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 9&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 39&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 28&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 10&lt;br/&gt;
Swainson's Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 43&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101027" rel="alternate" title="Wednesday, October 27, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101027" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jonathan Stein</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101026</id><published>2010-10-26T17:08:24.977-0700</published><updated>2010-10-26T17:08:24.977-0700</updated><title>Tuesday, October 26, 2010</title><content type="html">Another great count day on Hawk Hill!  Although the Hawkwatch team was not inundated with thousands of birds in the sky, we did count eleven raptor species today!  Clear skies and westerly winds for most of the day served as the perfect conditions for a raptor flight.  Everyone was particularly delighted to see a beautiful juvenile Golden Eagle rise up in front of Mt. Tamalpais.  The Hawkwatch team also spotted several Merlin powering through the Headlands today.  One of them was catching dragonflies on the wing and eating them like popcorn!  For all those birders out there, a handful of Pine Siskins, a Red Crossbill, and two dozen Greater White-Fronted Geese were also observed from Hawk Hill. &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 196&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 5.75&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 34.1&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 11&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 58&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 10&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 16&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 81&lt;br/&gt;
Golden Eagle: 1&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 4&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101026" rel="alternate" title="Tuesday, October 26, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101026" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Genevieve Rozhon</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101025</id><published>2010-10-25T17:14:52.285-0700</published><updated>2010-10-25T17:14:52.285-0700</updated><title>Monday, October 25, 2010</title><content type="html">It took a little while but eventually the raptors arrived for the Monday I team today. A slow morning turned into a wild afternoon as the team attempted to juggle several groups of birds during an end of day flurry. Multiple Merlins darted through the sky. A host of Red-tailed Hawks, several dark morphs included, came in out of the clouds. Two Northern Harriers bobbed and weaved near Slacker Hill. A far-off Peregrine Falcon buzzed the FM tower. And a lone juvenile Golden Eagle popped up from behind the pines--all in the last two hours of the watch. Happy after such a great rush of birds, the team descended the hill at 3:30 p.m. &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 166&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 5.5&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 30.2&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 10&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 34&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 16&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 30&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 59&lt;br/&gt;
Golden Eagle: 1&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101025" rel="alternate" title="Monday, October 25, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101025" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jonathan Stein</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101024</id><published>2010-10-24T09:54:24.062-0700</published><updated>2010-10-24T09:54:24.062-0700</updated><title>Sunday, October 24, 2010</title><content type="html">A steady, hard-driving rain got the better of the Sunday II team today. With little chance of let up, the decision was made to call the watch early and head on home. &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 0&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 0*&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 0&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101024" rel="alternate" title="Sunday, October 24, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101024" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jonathan Stein</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101023</id><published>2010-10-23T12:32:41.155-0700</published><updated>2010-10-23T12:32:41.155-0700</updated><title>Saturday, October 23, 2010</title><content type="html">In the immortal words of Allen Fish, "It's never a good idea to second guess the weather." As Saturday II discovered today, the weather does not stand for second-guessing. So while the team was expecting rain, they found a clear hill beneath gray skies. However, hawkwatch was still not possible today because, in slightly less famous words, it's also never a good idea to second guess  construction sites. Somehow, both points of access to Hawk Hill were blocked or locked off from the hawkwatchers. Stymied but not defeated, the group did some headlands birding, found an adult Red-tailed Hawk and a floatilla of Western Grebes, and adjourned to Mill Valley where additional birds were to be found, including a large flock of Willets and a bridge Peregrine--just not &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; bridge Peregrine. It is hoped that following the forecast rains this weekend, the skies will fill with raptors to entertain next week's hawkwatchers.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 0&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 0&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 0&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101023" rel="alternate" title="Saturday, October 23, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101023" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Lindsay Addison</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101022</id><published>2010-10-22T12:40:15.748-0700</published><updated>2010-10-22T12:40:15.748-0700</updated><title>Friday, October 22, 2010</title><content type="html">Fog and rain today! We tried to wait it out, visiting the Marine Mammal Center and the Native Plant Nursery, but when we went up to the Annex at noon, there was still misting and a heavy fog.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 0&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 0&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 0&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101022" rel="alternate" title="Friday, October 22, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101022" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Anastasia Ennis</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101021</id><published>2010-10-21T16:30:22.424-0700</published><updated>2010-10-21T16:30:22.424-0700</updated><title>Thursday, October 21, 2010</title><content type="html">Thursday II dodged the bullet with encroaching fog and lowering gray clouds and completed a successful hawkwatch. Despite some threatening weather moments, including some fog in the valley, visibility remained good for the balance of the day, and conditions were moderate on the hill. The raptor flow was slow, with only 218 counted in nearly six hours, but adult Accipiters have been coming through, and they continued today. Good looks were to be had at several that flew right overhead. Other highlights included eight male American Kestrels, one of which perched at the top of a tree and showed off, and a pumpkin-orange juvenile Northern Harrier. &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 218&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 5.67&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 38.47&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 8&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 71&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 18&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 12&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 97&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101021" rel="alternate" title="Thursday, October 21, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101021" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Lindsay</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101020</id><published>2010-10-20T16:41:55.423-0700</published><updated>2010-10-20T16:41:55.423-0700</updated><title>Wednesday, October 20, 2010</title><content type="html">Wednesday II's Hawkwatch team seems to have all the luck!  Today they were the first weekday team to make it back up on Hawk Hill. (NOTE: The road is still closed to the general public, so there is no access to Hawk Hill.)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Although there was heavy fog at the level of the hill in the early morning, the fog lifted around 11 a.m., so the team was still able to count for more than four hours.  We saw some fantastic birds today, including a juvenile Peregrine Falcon that attacked a Cooper's Hawk and then flew right over the Hawkwatch team, and a juvenile Broad-winged Hawk that popped up around the north tower of the Golden Gate Bridge.  Several White-tailed Kites and adult accipiters also materialized out of the fog.  Evening Grosbeaks and Red Crossbills were also spotted on the hill today.  Overall, today turned out to be a fantastic day to see hawks in the headlands.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 302&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 4.3&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 70.2&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 11&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 66&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 75&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 44&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 80&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 10&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101020" rel="alternate" title="Wednesday, October 20, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101020" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Genevieve Rozhon</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101019</id><published>2010-10-19T15:39:49.188-0700</published><updated>2010-10-19T15:39:49.188-0700</updated><title>Tuesday, October 19, 2010</title><content type="html">The hawkwatch team divided its day between birdwatching around the lagoon while waiting out some thick fog and hawkwatching at the alternate site. Although the team was pushed off the hill by fog shortly before 3:00, the day's tally came to a respectable 214 birds at 71.3 hawks per hour, with eight species seen. A couple of Broad-winged Hawks paid the hill a visit, as did a White-tailed Kite and many adult Accipiters. Toward the end of the day's count, the fog in the bay caused the migrants to stack up and form confused kettles among the ever-present Turkey Vultures.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Meanwhile, at the lagoon, ninety minutes of birdwatching yielded 41 species, including such highlights as an Elegant Tern, excellent looks at songbirds including a pair of Common Yellowthroats, a dive-bombing Brown Pelican, a juvenile Black-crowned Night Heron, and three species of raptor.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 214&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 3*&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 71.3&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 8&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 47&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 57&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 38&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 44&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 14&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 4&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101019" rel="alternate" title="Tuesday, October 19, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101019" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Lindsay Addison</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101018</id><published>2010-10-18T13:49:05.028-0700</published><updated>2010-10-18T13:49:05.028-0700</updated><title>Monday, October 18, 2010</title><content type="html">Today started off well for the Monday II Hawkwatch team.  The early morning fog blanketing the alternate Hawkwatch site dispersed fairly quickly, and we were able to spot several adult accipiters and juvenile Broad-winged Hawks early in the day.  In particular, one adult Sharp-shinned Hawk seen today was the color of lapis lazuli.  However, when thicker fog started to roll in around noon, the Hawkwatch team decided to call it a day.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 54&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 2.75*&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 19.64&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 8&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 22&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 12&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101018" rel="alternate" title="Monday, October 18, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101018" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Genevieve Rozhon</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101017</id><published>2010-10-17T12:35:34.467-0700</published><updated>2010-10-17T12:35:34.467-0700</updated><title>Sunday, October 17, 2010</title><content type="html">The Sunday I Hawkwatch team was confident that we could suffer through a little precipitation today if hawks were moving about.  However, the intermittent periods of dense fog, persistent heavy rain, and the overall lack of hawks in the sky, gradually wore away our resolve.  A few Song Sparrows, Band-tailed Pigeons, and one Red-shafted Flicker kept us entertained for the brief period of time we were on Hawk Hill. Heavy rain forced us to retire from Hawk Hill around 10:30am.  Back at Fort Cronkhite, The Hawkwatch team decided that a field trip was in order, so we all headed up to the Marine Mammal Center.  It was fascinating to see the Elephant seals Mirounga angustirostris) and California Sea Lions (Zalophus californianus) in the rehabilitation pens and learn about the typical species that annually cycle through the center.  &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 0.83&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 1.2&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101017" rel="alternate" title="Sunday, October 17, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101017" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Genevieve Rozhon</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101016</id><published>2010-10-16T14:02:02.214-0700</published><updated>2010-10-16T14:02:02.214-0700</updated><title>Saturday, October 16, 2010</title><content type="html">Today Saturday I's team finally made it to Hawk Hill! For one hour! We had been waiting out the fog at the Annex and then took a trip to the base of the bridge when we saw some clearing on the Hill. We hurried to the top only to find the fog was closing in again. The Annex reported Peregrine and Broad-wing sightings but all we saw was fog and a few other birds. The ravens were happy to see us.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 16&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 1&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 16&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 3&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101016" rel="alternate" title="Saturday, October 16, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101016" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Anastasia Ennis</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101015</id><published>2010-10-15T13:41:21.779-0700</published><updated>2010-10-15T13:41:21.779-0700</updated><title>Friday, October 15, 2010</title><content type="html">Friday I's dubious luck carried over only marginally from the team's last count, when it was possible to count for an entire day. On this occasion, fog below and sun above morphed into fog everywhere. Winds were fairly strong, but topped out at less than 20 miles per hour. Before visibility completely closed up, the team was treated to fogtastic views of the bay and several kettles of Turkey Vultures, who were showing off their flying abilities above the clouds. The local Red-tailed Hawks spent their morning hunting the hill above Kirby Cove, in and out of the fog tendrils.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 55&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 3*&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 18.3&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 51&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 4&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101015" rel="alternate" title="Friday, October 15, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101015" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Lindsay Addison</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101014</id><published>2010-10-14T16:23:22.961-0700</published><updated>2010-10-14T16:23:22.961-0700</updated><title>Thursday, October 14, 2010</title><content type="html">The hawkwatchers spent another hot day at the alternate hawkwatch site, staying hydrated and tallying a total of 396 hawk sightings over the course of the day. Since it was Thursday I's first day of counting, the team was relieved to be free of the fog--though it meant dealing with inhospitable temperatures it was finally possible to count hawks. The team was rewarded with good looks at multiple Red-tailed Hawks and Cooper's Hawks that soared close overhead, as well as sightings of two Osprey and a handful of American Kestrels and Northern Harriers. The day's highlight, though, was a pair of falcons: a magnificent adult Peregrine Falcon on its way south, and an unusually late Prairie Falcon that came roaring through the headlands on a beeline for San Francisco.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 396&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 5.58*&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 70.96&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 11&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 156&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 2&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 32&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 58&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 124&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Prairie Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 9&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101014" rel="alternate" title="Thursday, October 14, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101014" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Lindsay Addison</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101013</id><published>2010-10-13T16:54:31.114-0700</published><updated>2010-10-13T16:54:31.114-0700</updated><title>Wednesday, October 13, 2010</title><content type="html">It was variety over volume for the Wednesday I team during a shortened outing today. Arriving at our alternate hawkwatching site at approximately 12 pm due to construction-related delays, the team managed to spot 12 different species before adjourning at our normal time. Broad-winged and Ferruginous Hawks continued to be seen and four more White-tailed Kites were spotted, bringing our season total to 33.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 146&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 3.75*&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 38.9&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 12&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 62&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 19&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 10&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 35&lt;br/&gt;
Ferruginous Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 2&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101013" rel="alternate" title="Wednesday, October 13, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101013" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jonathan Stein</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101012</id><published>2010-10-12T16:26:52.467-0700</published><updated>2010-10-12T16:26:52.467-0700</updated><title>Tuesday, October 12, 2010</title><content type="html">Today was hot without a lot of wind and the birds were trying to stay cool, so our numbers were on the low side. The morning was still pretty busy, and we did see a good number of Broad-winged hawks, a few adult Accipiters and a White-tailed Kite, and an adult Red-shouldered hawk. One of the juvenile Broad-winged hawks came in very close to the hill and we had a thrilling look at it as it swept by. In the non-raptor category, we saw about 50 Violet-Green Swallows and a few Cedar Waxwings, Meadow Larks, and Varied Thrushes.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 262&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 5.5*&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 47.64&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 11&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 86&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 26&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 45&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 66&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 11&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101012" rel="alternate" title="Tuesday, October 12, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101012" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Anastasia Ennis</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101011</id><published>2010-10-11T17:25:11.741-0700</published><updated>2010-10-11T17:25:11.741-0700</updated><title>Monday, October 11, 2010</title><content type="html">Today was pleasant and warm up on the hill. Temperatures hovered around the mid-70s throughout with a slight breeze from the northwest. A midday spurt of raptors, mainly Red-tailed Hawks, Cooper's Hawks and Sharp-shinned Hawks, was bracketed by periods of idleness in the early and late going. Broad-winged Hawks continued to stream by and there was a noticeable uptick in the number of adult accipiters beginning to join the many juveniles on their southward migration. On the songbird front, the first Varied Thrush seen this season was spotted early in the morning just as the team ascended the hill.  &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 248&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 5.5*&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 45.1&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 10&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 45&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 55&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 58&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 57&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 15&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 2&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101011" rel="alternate" title="Monday, October 11, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101011" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jonathan Stein</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101010</id><published>2010-10-10T17:12:35.732-0700</published><updated>2010-10-10T17:12:35.732-0700</updated><title>Sunday, October 10, 2010</title><content type="html">There was fog below and mostly blue skies above for the Sunday II team today. Raptor-wise, not much was on the move in the morning but by early afternoon, when the fog eventually dissipated, a steady flow of birds began to stream by. Included among the assortment of Turkey Vultures, Red-tailed Hawks and Cooper&#146;s Hawks that made up the majority of the count were two Ferruginous Hawks sighted in the sky to the left of Battery Spencer, a handful of close-in Broad-winged Hawks and a lone juvenile Golden Eagle seen silhouetted against Mount Tamalpais. The team rounded out the day by watching the aerial acrobatics of the Blue Angels before descending the hill.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 190&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 5.5&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 34.6&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 12&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 51&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 38&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 40&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 24&lt;br/&gt;
Ferruginous Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Golden Eagle: 1&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 10&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101010" rel="alternate" title="Sunday, October 10, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101010" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jonathan Stein</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101009</id><published>2010-10-09T16:31:35.459-0700</published><updated>2010-10-09T16:31:35.459-0700</updated><title>Saturday, October 09, 2010</title><content type="html">The skies were clear for Saturday hawkwatch and the annual Blue Angels festivities. Although the weather was cooperative with bright sun and light winds, the flow of hawks was light. The number of blue steel birds seemed to outnumber the hawks in the last hour, when the team had to scour the hills to add a falcon--an American Kestrel--to the count. Earlier in the day the team did get to observe an adult male Northern Harrier and aerial courtship displays from the local pair of Red-tailed Hawks that live in Kirby Cove. Also in the skies, the hawkwatchers' perspective made it seem that the fighter jets were stooping on passing Accipiters, but all of the real birds merely continued their flights south, no doubt puzzled by all the racket overhead.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 327&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 6&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 54.5&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 9&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 103&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 43&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 53&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 10&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 92&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 17&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101009" rel="alternate" title="Saturday, October 09, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101009" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Lindsay Addison</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101008</id><published>2010-10-08T16:41:55.340-0700</published><updated>2010-10-08T16:41:55.340-0700</updated><title>Friday, October 08, 2010</title><content type="html">The day started off calm with some high cirrus clouds that thinned as the day got warmer and the wind picked up. We saw a pair of White-tailed Kites at the start of our day and had a juvenile Golden Eagle soar over the hill. Later in the day we had an up-close view of a Swainson's Hawk, some Broad-winged Hawks, and a couple of Peregrine Falcons. Several Merlins led in for the Blue Angels who were practicing again for the air shows this weekend. There were not a lot of birds today, but we had some great views and a nice variety of species.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 243&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 5.75*&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 42.26&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 13&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 102&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 13&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 36&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Swainson's Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 59&lt;br/&gt;
Golden Eagle: 1&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101008" rel="alternate" title="Friday, October 08, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101008" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Anastasia Ennis</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101007</id><published>2010-10-07T16:36:56.937-0700</published><updated>2010-10-07T16:36:56.937-0700</updated><title>Thursday, October 07, 2010</title><content type="html">Today started off with some high clouds shading us, but we still had nice views of birds during our busiest hour from 10 to 11. Flickers and Meadow larks were also flying about, and we got a long look at a Yellow-shafted flicker that perched on a rock. Highlights today included a distant dark-morph juvenile Broad-winged hawk as well as a juvenile Ferruginous hawk and an adult Cooper's hawk. The clouds cleared in the afternoon in time for the Blue Angels and others to practice their maneuvers for the Fleet Week air show this weekend.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 319&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 5.75*&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 55.48&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 12&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 124&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 16&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 27&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 111&lt;br/&gt;
Ferruginous Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 13&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101007" rel="alternate" title="Thursday, October 07, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101007" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Anastasia Ennis</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101006</id><published>2010-10-06T17:08:31.880-0700</published><updated>2010-10-06T17:08:31.880-0700</updated><title>Wednesday, October 06, 2010</title><content type="html">When our data recorder announced that we had already counted over one hundred raptors by 11:00 a.m. today, I began to think that the Wednesday II Hawkwatch team was in for some serious raptor-related thrills.  This proved to be the case when five White-tailed Kites surprised everyone by flying directly over the observation site!  The team also spotted three immature Golden Eagles today, one of which was close enough to see without the aid of binoculars.  Finally, when a juvenile Broad-winged Hawk appeared above the north tower of the Golden Gate Bridge and then flew right by the Hawkwatchers, this was really the icing on the cake.  The kettles of fifteen or more Turkey Vultures that formed near Hawk Hill were also nothing short of spectacular! Our count of six hundred and sixty-nine raptors currently stands as the highest hawk count this season! Clear skies, westerly winds, and warm weather thermals created the perfect conditions for raptor watching.   &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 669&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 5.75*&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 116.4&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 13&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 227&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 3&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 10&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 63&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 93&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 24&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 149&lt;br/&gt;
Golden Eagle: 3&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 50&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 7&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101006" rel="alternate" title="Wednesday, October 06, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101006" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Genevieve Rozhon</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101005</id><published>2010-10-06T08:50:14.996-0700</published><updated>2010-10-06T12:42:14.996-0700</updated><title>Tuesday, October 05, 2010</title><content type="html">There were Golden Eagles galore today for the Tuesday II team. The afternoon featured visits from three young eagles, all of whom offered long, captivating looks that didn&#146;t require squinting or undue neck craning. The Golden Eagle pace has picked up considerably with five now sighted in the last two days. Today also set the season-high for both Merlins and Northern Harriers as eight Merlins and 12 Northern Harriers made an appearance on the count sheet. Songbird-wise, a handful of Northern Flickers &#151; most of which were Red-shafted but some of which were clearly intergrades between Yellow-shafted and Red-shafted &#151; busied themselves in the scrub near our alternate hawkwatching site early in the day. &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 376&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 5.5*&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 68.4&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 13&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 63&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 12&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 60&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 85&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 94&lt;br/&gt;
Golden Eagle: 3&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 14&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 16&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 3&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101005" rel="alternate" title="Tuesday, October 05, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101005" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jonathan Stein</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101004</id><published>2010-10-04T17:05:30.332-0700</published><updated>2010-10-04T17:05:30.332-0700</updated><title>Monday, October 04, 2010</title><content type="html">Today's Hawkwatch team observed a relative smorgasbord of raptors!  Although the total number of raptors counted was not the all-time high for this season, we did count fourteen hawk species!  This included everything from White-tailed Kites and Golden Eagles (the first of the season) to Broad-winged Hawks and Ferruginous Hawks.  We also witnessed some hilarious aerial scuffles.  At one point, a juvenile Cooper's hawk ran into an adult Peregrine in the air, and the Peregrine did a few "log rolls."  Then the Peregrine proceeded to scream its head off.  A juvenile Ferruginous hawk that was minding its own business happened upon this scene, and was promptly harassed and bumped by the Peregrine.  This peregrine was then joined by another, and they circled the area, screaming back and forth at each other.  I guess the moral of this story is "don't mess with big falcons!"&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 421&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 5.67*&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 74.3&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 14&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 126&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 2&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 57&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 82&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 88&lt;br/&gt;
Ferruginous Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Golden Eagle: 2&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 13&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 10&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 19&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 3&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101004" rel="alternate" title="Monday, October 04, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101004" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Genevieve Rozhon</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101003</id><published>2010-10-03T16:49:05.433-0700</published><updated>2010-10-03T16:49:05.433-0700</updated><title>Sunday, October 03, 2010</title><content type="html">This morning, the Sunday Hawkwatch team was met with heavy fog hanging around the level of Hawk Hill.  Although the outlook for the day appeared bleak, the team decided to observe raptors from the level of the Annex, with the hope that the fog would eventually clear. At the Annex, we were happy to observe several accipiters and White-tailed Kites hunting the South Slacker ridge. When the fog began to lift around 10:30 a.m., we decided to head up the hill and start counting raptors.  Considering our later start time, we still counted a significant number of raptors today.  The majority of raptors we saw included Turkey Vultures, adult Red-tailed Hawks, juvenile Cooper's Hawks, and juvenile Sharp-shinned Hawks.  We also saw a fair number of American Kestrels and one Merlin.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 212&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 4.17&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 50.88&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 8&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 71&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 27&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 25&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 54&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 9&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 16&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 3&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101003" rel="alternate" title="Sunday, October 03, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101003" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Genevieve Rozhon</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101002</id><published>2010-10-02T13:24:16.343-0700</published><updated>2010-10-02T13:24:16.343-0700</updated><title>Saturday, October 02, 2010</title><content type="html">Once again, Saturday I's team was doomed to fog. We took a trip to the rifle range where we saw an adult Red-tailed hawk. Then we drove to the overlook at Bird Rock and saw another Red-tail perched near Battery Alexander. Some Turkey Vultures and a Kestrel were also seen in the Headlands today but, unfortunately, the top of Hawk Hill was not. Maybe next time it will be clear?&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 0&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 0&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 0&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101002" rel="alternate" title="Saturday, October 02, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101002" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Anastasia Ennis</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20101001</id><published>2010-10-01T17:00:31.323-0700</published><updated>2010-10-01T17:00:31.323-0700</updated><title>Friday, October 01, 2010</title><content type="html">The Friday I team made its first appearance at the alternate hawkwatch site after being shut out by fog or spending the day at the spring migration site for the first three weeks of the 2010 season. The morning was overcast but visibility was good, and by the afternoon the wind had picked up and the skies had cleared. A total of 260 hawks winged past the hawkwatchers, for an average of 52 hawks per hour. Sharp-shinned Hawks were the best-represented species, with 67 total individuals counted, including one adult that showed off its blue back. Cooper's Hawks were sparser, coming in at 29. Merlins and Kestrels put in appearances, along with Peregrine Falcons, one of which put on a spectacular show by stooping on an unfortunate Sharp-shinned Hawk. Other sightings included an early afternoon Osprey directly overhead and two Northern Harriers, one an adult mail.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 260&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 5*&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 52&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 10&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 67&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 67&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 29&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 50&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 12&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 14&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20101001" rel="alternate" title="Friday, October 01, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20101001" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Lindsay Addison</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20100930</id><published>2010-09-30T16:56:36.861-0700</published><updated>2010-09-30T16:56:36.861-0700</updated><title>Thursday, September 30, 2010</title><content type="html">The skies remained indifferent to the Thursday I team's optimism and enthusiasm, and foggy conditions prevailed today at the alternate hawkwatch site. When the group met in the morning, they birded briefly around the visitor center in hopes of seeing a Black-and-white Warbler then headed up to attempt a hawkwatch. However, strong winds dense fog, and no visibility greeted them, so they retreated to a sheltered spot and waited for the rest of the morning. In the afternoon, the fog opened up around Kirby Cove, so the group got in some birding at the Annex, where the local Red-tails and some Accipiters were to be seen.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 0&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 0*&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 0&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20100930" rel="alternate" title="Thursday, September 30, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20100930" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Lindsay</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20100929</id><published>2010-09-29T16:42:31.247-0700</published><updated>2010-09-29T16:42:31.247-0700</updated><title>Wednesday, September 29, 2010</title><content type="html">The Broad-winged Hawks kept making their way through the Headlands today marking the sixth straight day where at least one has been sighted by hawkwatchers. Temperatures hovered around the high 60s for most of the day and a brisk northwest breeze brought birds in for close inspection. Highlights included the aforementioned broadwings, an adult male Northern Harrier cruising past Kirby Cove and a juvenile Ferruginous Hawk soaring over Battery Spencer.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 264&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 5.5*&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 48&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 11&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 55&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 41&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 63&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 58&lt;br/&gt;
Ferruginous Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 17&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 5&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20100929" rel="alternate" title="Wednesday, September 29, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20100929" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jonathan Stein</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20100928</id><published>2010-09-28T16:31:24.344-0700</published><updated>2010-09-28T16:31:24.344-0700</updated><title>Tuesday, September 28, 2010</title><content type="html">It was a sweltering day on the hill, with little to no breeze and temperatures in the 80s climbing throughout the day. We saw most of our birds in the morning and early afternoon, getting great looks at juvenile Ferruginous hawks and both juvenile and adult Broad-winged hawks, who spent some time above HawkWatch. We also saw 5 Black swifts in the morning hour. The rest of the day we had steady Accipiter sightings, a large kettle of Turkey vultures hanging around, several Red-shouldered hawks, and many dragonflies.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 328&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 5*&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 65.6&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 11&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 74&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 75&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 81&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 63&lt;br/&gt;
Ferruginous Hawk: 4&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 12&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20100928" rel="alternate" title="Tuesday, September 28, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20100928" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Anastasia Ennis</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20100927</id><published>2010-09-27T16:52:35.215-0700</published><updated>2010-09-27T16:52:35.215-0700</updated><title>Monday, September 27, 2010</title><content type="html">The Monday I team sweated through a hot one today. But luckily for us, there were plenty of raptors out there to keep us company during a 13 species, four falcon day at our alternate hawkwatch site. The first Prairie Falcon of the season was sighted today and was joined by two Peregrine Falcons, two Merlins and eight American Kestrels for a wonderfully falcon-filled five-and-a-half hours of watching. The day also featured splendid looks at two juvenile Ferruginous Hawks and eight juvenile Broad-winged Hawks, many of which could be seen easily from the hill without the aid of optics.  &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 397&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 5.5*&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 72.2&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 13&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 70&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 104&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 129&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 47&lt;br/&gt;
Ferruginous Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Prairie Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 14&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 2&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20100927" rel="alternate" title="Monday, September 27, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20100927" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jonathan Stein</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20100926</id><published>2010-09-26T18:04:04.698-0700</published><updated>2010-09-26T18:04:04.698-0700</updated><title>Sunday, September 26, 2010</title><content type="html">Today was a lively and exceedingly enjoyable day up on the hill: sunny with just a slight breeze and hawks streaming by in waves. A variety of species, 13 in all, were spotted during six hours of counting. Great scope looks at three juvenile Broad-winged Hawks and an adult Swainson's Hawk making its way across the Bay toward San Francisco proved to be the highlights. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Falcons abounded as well with five Merlins, five American Kestrels and three Peregrine Falcons all announcing their presence. The Merlin abundance was a special treat, especially since several came shooting right by the hill allowing for spectacular looks as the birds headed south. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;There were even some interesting migrant songbirds out and about: Townsend's and Yellow Warblers, Horned Larks, Pine Siskins, Violet-green and Northern Rough-winged Swallows and hundreds of Vaux's Swifts to name a few. All in all, a great day for watching feathered fliers in the Headlands. &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 409&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 6&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 68.2&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 13&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 75&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 2&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 162&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 70&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Swainson's Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 58&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 19&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 2&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20100926" rel="alternate" title="Sunday, September 26, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20100926" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jonathan Stein</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20100925</id><published>2010-09-25T16:28:52.589-0700</published><updated>2010-09-25T16:28:52.589-0700</updated><title>Saturday, September 25, 2010</title><content type="html">The hawkwatch team sweated it out on the hill today under a clear sky. Temperatures reached into the mid-nineties, and winds were light from the north. The team was greeted by three Northern Harriers and some morning Kestrels. Many good looks of Cooper's and Sharp-shinned Hawks were to be had as they rode the thermals south, and six Merlins transited through as well.  However, the highlights of the day were excellent, long looks at some spectacular birds. A juvenile Broad-winged Hawk showed off in the Golden Gate for over five minutes (others of its compatriots soared high above in kettles of vultures and Accipiters), and a juvenile Ferruginous Hawk shot out of the north and circled in front of the hill, affording a great view for all. The grand rara avis finale came when an adult dark-morph Ferruginous Hawk came gliding in from beneath the FM tower and proceeded to circle up, slowly gaining altitude and finally melting away into the East Bay.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 525&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 6&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 87.5&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 10&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 128&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 118&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 98&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 125&lt;br/&gt;
Ferruginous Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 13&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 17&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 5&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20100925" rel="alternate" title="Saturday, September 25, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20100925" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Lindsay Addison</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20100924</id><published>2010-09-24T16:49:40.408-0700</published><updated>2010-09-24T16:49:40.408-0700</updated><title>Friday, September 24, 2010</title><content type="html">The air was hot with a warm breeze for today's HawkWatch. While we didn't count as many birds today as in previous days, likely due to the weak winds, we saw an amazing diversity of species. We had some great up-close views of Merlins and an adult Broad-winged hawk in addition to the many Accipiters migrating by. At one point in the day we had a kettle of two juvenile Ferruginous hawks, a juvenile Northern Harrier, and two Turkey Vultures directly above where we were standing. A beautiful day with beautiful birds!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 339&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 5.5*&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 61.5&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 13&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 73&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 59&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 78&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 71&lt;br/&gt;
Ferruginous Hawk: 3&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 24&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 10&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20100924" rel="alternate" title="Friday, September 24, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20100924" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Anastasia Ennis</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20100923</id><published>2010-09-23T16:46:39.541-0700</published><updated>2010-09-23T16:46:39.541-0700</updated><title>Thursday, September 23, 2010</title><content type="html">Thursday II enjoyed a temperate and not terribly windy day at the alternate hawkwatch site. A generally northwest wind helped push a nice, if somewhat intermittent, flight through the headlands, and the hawkwatchers saw a total of 429 raptors. Among those birds were several stand-out species including Ferruginous Hawk, Swainson's Hawk, Merlin, and White-tailed Kite. The hill was also visited by numerous juvenile Cooper's and Sharp-shined Hawks, many of which afforded watchers great looks before they set out to points south. A handful of Peregrine Falcons and Red-shouldered Hawks helped to round out an eleven-species day.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 429&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 5.8*&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 73.54&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 11&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 147&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 79&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 67&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Swainson's Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 104&lt;br/&gt;
Ferruginous Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 9&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20100923" rel="alternate" title="Thursday, September 23, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20100923" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Lindsay Addison</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20100922</id><published>2010-09-22T16:56:39.903-0700</published><updated>2010-09-22T16:56:39.903-0700</updated><title>Wednesday, September 22, 2010</title><content type="html">The accipiters came pouring through again today during another windy one at our alternate hawkwatching site. Sharp-shinned Hawks and Cooper's Hawks dominated the count numbers for the third straight day with Turkey Vultures and Red-tailed Hawks each posting respectable totals. Three Merlins were also seen on the day, all of whom were flying fast and low, making their way quickly across the Bay. &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 460&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 6*&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 76.7&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 7&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 95&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 98&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 97&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 106&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 44&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 8&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20100922" rel="alternate" title="Wednesday, September 22, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20100922" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jonathan Stein</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20100921</id><published>2010-09-21T15:48:02.713-0700</published><updated>2010-09-21T15:48:02.713-0700</updated><title>Tuesday, September 21, 2010</title><content type="html">"Next time we should bring a kite." The hawkwatchers spent a windy and fairly busy day at the alternative hawkwatch site, with clusters of Accipiters coursing through the headlands accompanied by a fair number of kestrels and a Merlin. Other species seen included an Osprey, a few Peregrine Falcons, and Red-shouldered Hawks. The sky was blue and the sun was out, so many good looks were available, although as the wind strengthened holding binoculars steady on distant birds. Highlights included views of Sharp-shinned Hawks and Cooper's Hawks dog-fighting before heading south across the Golden Gate.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 358&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 5.5*&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 65.09&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 9&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 77&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 84&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 49&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 61&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 20&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 52&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 3&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20100921" rel="alternate" title="Tuesday, September 21, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20100921" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Lindsay Addison</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20100920</id><published>2010-09-20T17:25:35.915-0700</published><updated>2010-09-20T17:25:35.915-0700</updated><title>Monday, September 20, 2010</title><content type="html">After several days of heavy fog and drizzle, the Hawkwatch team was rewarded with clear skies and a fantastic count of four hundred and ninety raptors today!  The accipiters are officially moving en masse! When the team first arrived at our alternate hawk counting site, the fog was sitting low over the ocean.  However, around 10 a.m., the fog rose and reduced visibility on the hill to less than 0.1 mi.  Although we were discouraged, the fog cleared again by 11 a.m., to everyone's relief.  That's when the excitement began.  Sharp-shinned Hawks started filling the skies around 11 a.m. and increased in number until 3 p.m. Cooper's Hawks really started popping up between 1 p.m. and 3 p.m.  Today's Hawkwatch team was also happily surprised by the appearance of two juvenile Broad-winged Hawks over the bay!  One of these birds flew right by the count site.  These are the first Broad-winged Hawks to be counted by Hawkwatch this season.  We also observed one White-tailed Kite hovering by the north tower of the Golden Gate Bridge.  Juvenile Red-tailed Hawks and juvenile Sharp-shinned Hawks comprised the majority of the total count today.   &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 498&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 5.75*&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 86.6&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 11&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 44&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 178&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 68&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 148&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 16&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 24&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20100920" rel="alternate" title="Monday, September 20, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20100920" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Genevieve Rozhon</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20100919</id><published>2010-09-19T13:03:56.963-0700</published><updated>2010-09-19T13:03:56.963-0700</updated><title>Sunday, September 19, 2010</title><content type="html">During the first fifteen minutes of observation time on Hawk hill today, the Hawkwatch team counted four accipiters and three American Kestrels. This left the team feeling pretty optimistic about the rest of the day.  However, when the fog rolled in around 10 a.m., visibility on Hawk hill was substantially reduced.  A short time after that, it began to drizzle.  No birds were counted from 11 a.m. to 12 p.m. This being the case, the Hawkwatch team decided to throw in the towel for the day.  &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 18&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 1.75&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 10.3&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20100919" rel="alternate" title="Sunday, September 19, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20100919" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Genevieve Rozhon</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20100918</id><published>2010-09-18T12:04:58.912-0700</published><updated>2010-09-18T12:04:58.912-0700</updated><title>Saturday, September 18, 2010</title><content type="html">Today was foggy with a hint of a drizzle, but we bravely set off on a walk around Rodeo Lagoon. There were no raptors to be found, but we did see a Wandering Tattler. We took a field trip to the Las Gallinas ponds and saw a dark morph Red-tailed Hawk perched on a power pole, several Northern Harriers, and a couple American Kestrels. There are raptors out there, but they are difficult to spot in the thick Headlands fog. Maybe next time, Saturday I.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 0&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 0&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 0&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20100918" rel="alternate" title="Saturday, September 18, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20100918" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Anastasia</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20100917</id><published>2010-09-17T14:14:01.961-0700</published><updated>2010-09-17T14:14:01.961-0700</updated><title>Friday, September 17, 2010</title><content type="html">Friday I was greeted with damp, dense, (relatively) warm fog at Fort Cronkhite, so with no signs of clearing, the team took a walk up Bobcat Trail to see what else could be seen. The visibility remained the same throughout the morning, with the only change in conditions being a shift from mere fog to some light pinprick drizzle.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;However, there was quite a bit of wildlife to enjoy, including 23 species of birds, four of which were raptors. The nature hike yielded various mammals, reptiles, insects and mollusks, plus 23 bird species, including four raptors. The birds were: Turkey Vulture, Red-tailed Hawk (juvenile), Cooper&#146;s Hawk (juvenile), Northern Harrier, Wrentit, White-crowned Sparrow, Lincoln&#146;s Sparrow, Song Sparrow, House Wren, Black Phoebe, Say&#146;s Phoebe, Pacific Slope Flycatcher, Bushtit, Chestnut-backed Chickadee, American Goldfinch, Lesser Goldfinch, Blue-gray Gnatcatcher, Spotted Towhee, Common Raven, Anna&#146;s Hummingbird, Mourning Dove, Yellow Warbler, Common Yellowthroat.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 0&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 0*&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 0&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20100917" rel="alternate" title="Friday, September 17, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20100917" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Lindsay Addison</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20100916</id><published>2010-09-16T13:22:27.541-0700</published><updated>2010-09-16T13:22:27.541-0700</updated><title>Thursday, September 16, 2010</title><content type="html">The Thursday I hawkwatch team encountered intractable fog today. After slide study and a short walk during which an Anna's Hummingbird gave the whole group great looks, the team went to the annex in hopes of finding the fog was clearing. However, more rolled in, and after lunch the group adjourned to 1064 for another round of slide study before calling the day at 1:00.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 0&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 0*&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 0&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20100916" rel="alternate" title="Thursday, September 16, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20100916" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Lindsay</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20100915</id><published>2010-09-15T14:00:03.337-0700</published><updated>2010-09-15T14:00:03.337-0700</updated><title>Wednesday, September 15, 2010</title><content type="html">Heavy morning fog in the Headlands crushed any hope of the Wednesday 1 team ascending the hill to our alternate hawkwatching site today. Instead, the team circled Rodeo Lagoon and spotted several Common Yellowthroats, Yellow Warblers and Great and Snowy Egrets among other species. Toward the end of the walk, a Merlin flew in and perched high in a conifer no more than 50 feet from us. The bird stayed there for 10 minutes allowing nice long scope looks before being displaced by a Red-tailed Hawk. The watch was called at 1 p.m.  &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 0&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 0*&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 0&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20100915" rel="alternate" title="Wednesday, September 15, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20100915" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jonathan Stein</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20100914</id><published>2010-09-14T16:20:18.554-0700</published><updated>2010-09-14T16:20:18.554-0700</updated><title>Tuesday, September 14, 2010</title><content type="html">Today started off slowly, with fog steadily rolling in. At noon the wind picked up and blew the fog by our faces more quickly. Despite the weather we saw a good number of adult Red-tailed hawks, some accipiters, and two juvenile Sharp-shinned hawks. Finally, in the last half hour the fog cleared and we saw a juvenile Ferruginous hawk, the first of the season!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 116&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 5.75*&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 20.17&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 8&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 33&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 56&lt;br/&gt;
Ferruginous Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20100914" rel="alternate" title="Tuesday, September 14, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20100914" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Anastasia</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20100913</id><published>2010-09-13T16:37:15.121-0700</published><updated>2010-09-13T16:37:15.121-0700</updated><title>Monday, September 13, 2010</title><content type="html">A scaled down Monday I team braved the wind and cold at our alternate hawkwatching site and were rewarded with a few gratifying moments during an otherwise bleak day today. A juvenile Northern Harrier provided nice looks before circling upward into the hazy layer of fog. And a male American Kestrel hover-hunted here and there for a time near the watch site. But the day's highlight turned out to be the very first bird counted: an adult Peregrine Falcon seen soaring lazily overhead before making its way across the Bay. The watch adjourned at 3 p.m.     &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 57&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 4.5*&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 12.7&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 16&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 33&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 3&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20100913" rel="alternate" title="Monday, September 13, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20100913" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jonathan Stein</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20100912</id><published>2010-09-12T16:43:39.187-0700</published><updated>2010-09-12T16:43:39.187-0700</updated><title>Sunday, September 12, 2010</title><content type="html">It was blustery today with fog throughout up on Hawk Hill. Red-tailed Hawks and Turkey Vultures were seen milling around for most of the day. The two Peregrine Falcons were seen out over Kirby Cove around mid-day. And the two Cooper's Hawks, both juveniles, were seen during the last hour as the day wound to a close. &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 47&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 5.25&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 8.95&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 14&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 29&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 2&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20100912" rel="alternate" title="Sunday, September 12, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20100912" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jonathan Stein</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20100911</id><published>2010-09-11T16:34:40.424-0700</published><updated>2010-09-11T16:34:40.424-0700</updated><title>Saturday, September 11, 2010</title><content type="html">Sunshine above and fog below greeting the hawkwatchers of Saturday II. The fair weather continued throughout the day with the wind strengthening in the afternoon and sweeping most of the morning fog out of the bay in time for the afternoon fog to make its appearance. Although the watch remained above it all, the day was relatively slow. A total of 194 hawks were sighted, at 34.2 hawks per hour. However, 9 species were tallied with good looks at Ospreys, Red-shoulders, a Northern Harrier, and a Cooper's and a Sharpie doing aerial battle above the Golden Gate.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 194&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 5.7&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 34.2&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 9&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 78&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 12&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 79&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 3&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20100911" rel="alternate" title="Saturday, September 11, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20100911" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Lindsay Addison</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20100910</id><published>2010-09-10T16:51:37.167-0700</published><updated>2010-09-10T16:51:37.167-0700</updated><title>Friday, September 10, 2010</title><content type="html">It was a beautiful clear day on the hill, with highs in the 80s and a pleasant breeze starting up in the afternoon, bringing birds with it. We saw several kettles of Red-tailed hawks waiting to cross the bay to the south across the low fog bank at the Golden Gate. A Merlin zoomed by us and a couple of harriers flapped through as well. We also saw three dark morph juvenile Red-tailed hawks.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 338&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 5.67*&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 59.65&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 8&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 123&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 184&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 4&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20100910" rel="alternate" title="Friday, September 10, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20100910" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Anastasia</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20100909</id><published>2010-09-09T16:23:18.863-0700</published><updated>2010-09-09T16:23:18.863-0700</updated><title>Thursday, September 09, 2010</title><content type="html">After drawing a very foggy and windy first day, the Thursday II team was treated to a bright sunny day that began with light winds from the southeast and concluded with stronger winds from the northwest and fog rolling in beneath the alternate hawkwatch site. Good looks were to be had at male and female Kestrels, many juvenile Red-tails including some dark morphs, and an adult Cooper's Hawk. Meanwhile, the Peregrine Falcon stood sentry on the north tower. The highlight of the day came when a Bald Eagle chose to pay the Headlands a visit. At the end of the day, the team had tallied a total of 214 hawks representing 8 species at a rate of 38.9 per hour.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 214&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 5.5*&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 38.9&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 8&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 74&lt;br/&gt;
Bald Eagle: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 125&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20100909" rel="alternate" title="Thursday, September 09, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20100909" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Lindsay Addison</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20100908</id><published>2010-09-08T13:35:04.750-0700</published><updated>2010-09-08T13:35:04.750-0700</updated><title>Wednesday, September 08, 2010</title><content type="html">Although the Hawkwatch team was optimistic about observing raptors today, alas, the fog won out, and we had to call the count off.  However, we decided to stroll around the lagoon at Fort Cronkhite, and saw a Western Sandpiper, a Least Sandpiper, a Green Heron, and several Yellow Warblers. After a brief stop at the Headlands Visitor's Center (to fuel up on hot chocolate), we made our way up to the annex on Conzelman road (to see if the fog had receded there at all).  Visibility was still poor there, but we did happen to see three adult Red-tailed Hawks talon-grappling over Rodeo Lagoon.  Hopefully tomorrow's Hawkwatch team will have better luck!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 0&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 0*&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 0&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20100908" rel="alternate" title="Wednesday, September 08, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20100908" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Genevieve Rozhon</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20100907</id><published>2010-09-07T13:17:00.157-0700</published><updated>2010-09-07T13:17:00.157-0700</updated><title>Tuesday, September 07, 2010</title><content type="html">The fog was low and thick today, prohibiting the Tuesday II team from successfully spotting migrating raptors at our alternate hawkwatching site. The team decided to hike down toward Kirby Cove and was rewarded with some nice looks at Pygmy Nuthatches, Blue-gray Gnatcatchers and California Towhees. Raptor-wise, a few Red-tailed Hawks and Turkey Vultures were spotted as was the adult male Peregrine Falcon manning his post on the North Tower. &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 0&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 0*&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 0&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20100907" rel="alternate" title="Tuesday, September 07, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20100907" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jonathan Stein</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20100906</id><published>2010-09-06T17:04:14.005-0700</published><updated>2010-09-06T17:04:14.005-0700</updated><title>Monday, September 06, 2010</title><content type="html">This was another great day to see Osprey and American Kestrels in the Headlands!  Today we counted nine more Osprey migrating south and sixteen American Kestrels!  The day started off hazy and warm with very minimal wind. Early on, the Hawkwatch team got to witness a kestrel and an accipiter having a "disagreement."  The leucistic Bewick's Wren also made another appearance at the count site.  The temperature peaked around noon with a high of eighty-seven degrees Fahrenheit.  Later in the afternoon, winds from the WSW picked up speed and helped cool off the Hawkwatch team.  Juvenile Red-tailed Hawk were seen more than any other type of raptor today.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 208&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 6*&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 34.7&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 7&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 65&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 9&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 93&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 16&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20100906" rel="alternate" title="Monday, September 06, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20100906" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Genevieve Rozhon</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20100905</id><published>2010-09-05T17:08:59.887-0700</published><updated>2010-09-05T17:08:59.887-0700</updated><title>Sunday, September 05, 2010</title><content type="html">Today started off with heavy fog in the Headlands.  This limited the visibility from Hawk Hill.  However, the fog receded by eleven o'clock, and by mid-afternoon, the Hawkwatch team was able to spot birds several miles away with their spotting scopes. For all of you Osprey and American Kestrel fans out there, today was the day to see those birds up close.  The Hawkwatch team was privileged to see nine Osprey and twelve American Kestrels during our count!  One of the American Kestrels flew by with several hummingbirds in hot pursuit!  Juvenile Cooper's Hawks and one Sharp-shinned Hawks also flew in fairly close to the Hawkwatch team, which allowed new Hawkwatchers to practice their accipiter identification skills.  So far, this was one highest hawk counts for the GGRO 2010 season.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 265&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 5.67&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 46.7&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 8&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 68&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 9&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 162&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 12&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 3&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20100905" rel="alternate" title="Sunday, September 05, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20100905" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Genevieve Rozhon</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20100904</id><published>2010-09-04T13:36:42.871-0700</published><updated>2010-09-04T13:36:42.871-0700</updated><title>Saturday, September 04, 2010</title><content type="html">The fog sat heavy in the Marin Headlands this Saturday. After a bird walk around the lagoon where we saw some phalaropes and a Caspian tern. We stopped at the Annex to check in with the docent talk, but they hadn't seen much besides fog, so we took a field trip to the Mill Valley marsh. It was still foggy when we returned to the Headlands. &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 0&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 0&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 0&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20100904" rel="alternate" title="Saturday, September 04, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20100904" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Anastasia</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20100903</id><published>2010-09-03T16:50:38.360-0700</published><updated>2010-09-03T16:50:38.360-0700</updated><title>Friday, September 03, 2010</title><content type="html">Today the Friday I team spent the first couple hours checking out the Red-necked Phalaropes in the lagoon before heading to the alternate hawkwatch site. There we experienced fog below covering much of the Golden Gate Bridge and streaming into the bay, but clear skies above. We were treated to a display from the bridge Peregrine almost as soon as we arrived, and the rest of the day was rather slow, although we enjoyed watching George and his family circle through. Late in the day, a couple of bold juvenile Red-tails were seen crossing the foggy strait, heading southward. A total of 38 hawks were counted, for 9.1 hawks per hour.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 38&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 4*&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 9.1&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 22&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 13&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20100903" rel="alternate" title="Friday, September 03, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20100903" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Lindsay Addison</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20100902</id><published>2010-09-02T16:54:36.508-0700</published><updated>2010-09-02T16:54:36.508-0700</updated><title>Thursday, September 02, 2010</title><content type="html">Today was another hot day for the Hawkwatch team.  However, westerly and south-westerly winds during the observation period helped cool down the Headlands somewhat. It turned out to be a great day to watch juvenile Red-tailed hawk perform acrobatics, practice hunting techniques, and tease the local adult Red-tails. The Hawkwatch team was also treated to some great close-up views of juvenile Red-shouldered hawks adult and Peregrine Falcons.  At one point, two Peregrine were spotted perching next to each other on the Golden Gate Bridge! Several Osprey and American Kestrels were also seen in the Headlands today.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 138&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 5*&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 23.8&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 38&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 81&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 2&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20100902" rel="alternate" title="Thursday, September 02, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20100902" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Genevieve Rozhon</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20100901</id><published>2010-09-01T16:22:46.543-0700</published><updated>2010-09-01T16:22:46.543-0700</updated><title>Wednesday, September 01, 2010</title><content type="html">All that sunscreen and extra ice water came in handy today. It was hot throughout with temperatures reaching 92 degrees during the 2 o'clock hour. Lots of juvenile Red-tailed Hawks braved the heat and continued their southward march. Osprey, Sharp-shinned Hawk, Northern Harrier, Turkey Vulture, Cooper's Hawk and American Kestrel were also spotted today. Around midday, two large falcons were sighted circling above the Golden Gate's North Tower but both birds were moving fast and away from the hawkwatch team toward Crissy Field preventing identification. The watch adjourned at 3:05 p.m.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 122&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 5*&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 22.2&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 8&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 31&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 71&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 2&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20100901" rel="alternate" title="Wednesday, September 01, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20100901" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jonathan Stein</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20100831</id><published>2010-08-31T16:40:31.449-0700</published><updated>2010-08-31T16:40:31.449-0700</updated><title>Tuesday, August 31, 2010</title><content type="html">The fog came through in waves this morning but was mostly below us at our elevation. It cleared up in the afternoon but there was a persistent layer of fog that hovered under the Golden Gate Bridge and over the Bay all day, causing a kettle of about 7 Red-tailed hawks to hang around for quite a while, while they waited to see land before crossing south. Towards the end of the day we got a great look at some Peregrine falcons while the resident pair chased off an interloper right over our heads.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 87&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 5.5*&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 15.8&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 8&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 33&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 40&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 3&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20100831" rel="alternate" title="Tuesday, August 31, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20100831" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Anastasia</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20100830</id><published>2010-08-30T16:33:32.654-0700</published><updated>2010-08-30T16:33:32.654-0700</updated><title>Monday, August 30, 2010</title><content type="html">The first White-tailed Kite of the season was spotted today spiraling upward over Hawk Hill before melting into the clouds. The kite proved to be one of nine species seen, matching our most species-rich day this season. Northern Harrier, Cooper's Hawk, Peregrine Falcon, American Kestrel, Red-shouldered Hawk and Sharp-shinned Hawk were seen in addition to lots of Red-tailed Hawks and Turkey Vultures.   For most of the watch, blue skies and a light breeze predominated. Toward the end, the wind picked up and fog began to creep in and envelope the crew. With visibility deteriorating, the watch was called at 3 p.m.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 103&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 5.5*&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 18.7&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 9&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 42&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 43&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20100830" rel="alternate" title="Monday, August 30, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20100830" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jonathan Stein</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20100829</id><published>2010-08-29T15:52:16.030-0700</published><updated>2010-08-29T15:52:16.030-0700</updated><title>Sunday, August 29, 2010</title><content type="html">The day started out promising with great looks at an American Kestrel barreling forth out of the clouds. But quickly thereafter, the fog rolled in again and continued to roll in again and again for the rest of the watch, limiting visibility considerably. A smattering of raptors, mostly Red-tailed Hawks and Turkey Vultures, were sighted through the fog. The highlight of the day came when a dark morph juvenile Red-tailed Hawk circled Hawk Hill, providing excellent views. The watch was called at 2 p.m. due to excessive fog.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 43&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 3&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 14.3&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 13&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 26&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 3&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20100829" rel="alternate" title="Sunday, August 29, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20100829" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jonathan Stein</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20100828</id><published>2010-08-28T16:36:48.608-0700</published><updated>2010-08-28T16:36:48.608-0700</updated><title>Saturday, August 28, 2010</title><content type="html">The remnants of an Alaskan storm brought us a strange mixture of billowing clouds, gusty winds and blue skies. Juvenile redtails, practicing their stilling skills, dominated the count. An adult and a juvenile peregrine were above us simultaneously, and the adult stooped on a redtail. A good start to Sat II's season.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 166&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 5.42&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 30.6&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 7&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 49&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 109&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 2&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20100828" rel="alternate" title="Saturday, August 28, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20100828" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Lindsay</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20100827</id><published>2010-08-27T13:48:48.517-0700</published><updated>2010-08-27T13:48:48.517-0700</updated><title>Friday, August 27, 2010</title><content type="html">Fogged out for the second day in a row! The fog was higher today and started clearing in the late afternoon, but we had already decided to come down and wouldn't have been able to collect more than two hours of data. Thursdays and Fridays seem to be out of luck the first two weeks of HawkWatch!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 0&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 0*&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 0&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20100827" rel="alternate" title="Friday, August 27, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20100827" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Anastasia</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20100826</id><published>2010-08-26T14:55:35.382-0700</published><updated>2010-08-26T14:55:35.382-0700</updated><title>Thursday, August 26, 2010</title><content type="html">Thursday II's first day was very foggy! After an extended morning meeting we headed over to the Annex but could barely see the base of the Golden Gate Bridge. We did see two resident Red-tails in a tree, guarding Kirby Cove, as well as a low-flying Cooper's hawk. We took a tour of the alternate HawkWatch site, but all we could see was fog and the tears in our eyes from the brisk wind.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 0&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 0*&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 0&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20100826" rel="alternate" title="Thursday, August 26, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20100826" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Anastasia</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20100825</id><published>2010-08-25T16:37:22.596-0700</published><updated>2010-08-25T16:37:22.596-0700</updated><title>Wednesday, August 25, 2010</title><content type="html">Although today's Hawkwatch team received a break from the heat wave, they were buffeted all day long with westerly winds up to 29mph.  However, seeing two Osprey, which appeared to be heading south, zoom over our heads, made up for the extremely windy weather!  We also observed several American Kestrels, a few Northern Harriers, and one Cooper's hawk with a gigantic bulging crop (looked like it just had a big snack!). The majority of raptors we saw today were juvenile Red-tailed Hawks and Turkey Vultures. Good luck to tomorrow's Hawkwatch team!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 140&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 4.5*&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 31.1&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 56&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 75&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20100825" rel="alternate" title="Wednesday, August 25, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20100825" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Genevieve Rozhon</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20100824</id><published>2010-08-24T16:45:52.264-0700</published><updated>2010-08-24T16:45:52.264-0700</updated><title>Tuesday, August 24, 2010</title><content type="html">The heat continued today, with temperatures reaching 99 degrees in light winds that tailed off as the afternoon progressed. Sightings were up a little too. Two hundred and forty-two total hawks were observed, and Turkey Vultures and juvenile Red-tailed Hawks again were the most common raptors. Adding to the mix when hawk sightings are slow in coming, an apparently leucistic Bewick's Wren has been hanging around the alternate hawkwatch site for the past day or so.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 243&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 5*&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 48.6&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 9&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 136&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 9&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 84&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20100824" rel="alternate" title="Tuesday, August 24, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20100824" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Lindsay</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20100823</id><published>2010-08-23T17:10:24.931-0700</published><updated>2010-08-23T17:10:24.931-0700</updated><title>Monday, August 23, 2010</title><content type="html">The Headlands really heated up today, with the ambient temperature ranging above eighty degrees Fahrenheit and minimal wind until after 2:00 p.m.  However, the Hawkwatchers sweat it out at our alternate hawk watch site today, and were rewarded with several sightings of American Kestrels and juvenile Red-shouldered Hawks.  Overall juvenile Red-tailed Hawks and Turkey Vultures were the most common raptors seen today.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 147&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 5*&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 29.4&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 68&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 65&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 3&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20100823" rel="alternate" title="Monday, August 23, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20100823" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Genevieve Rozhon</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20100822</id><published>2010-08-22T17:09:15.247-0700</published><updated>2010-08-22T17:09:15.247-0700</updated><title>Sunday, August 22, 2010</title><content type="html">Although today started off with heavy fog over Hawk Hill, the Hawkwatch team was optimistic that the fog would soon clear. So, we hiked up to Hawk Hill and started counting raptors at 10:45 a.m.  It turned out to be a great day to hawk watch!  The fog gave way to the warm sun by noon, and after that, we could see all the way to Mount Tamalpais.  Gentle winds from the NNW direction predominated during the day.  The most common species seen today were Red-tailed Hawks and Turkey Vultures.  The Red-tailed hawks were mainly playful, awkward juveniles, who hung around the Headlands for several hours. We also saw several female American Kestrels and juvenile Red-shouldered hawks.  The total number of hawks counted today was 152 hawks.  Since we counted hawks for 4.75 hours, our rate of hawks per hour was 32.  Hopefully tomorrow&#128;&#153;s Hawkwatch will also enjoy great weather and have plenty of raptors to watch!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 152&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 4.75&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 32&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 42&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 99&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20100822" rel="alternate" title="Sunday, August 22, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20100822" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Genevieve Rozhon</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20100821</id><published>2010-08-21T16:52:00.568-0700</published><updated>2010-08-21T16:52:00.568-0700</updated><title>Saturday, August 21, 2010</title><content type="html">Daily HawkBlog: First Day on Hawk Hill!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;We got off to a late start as we waited out the weather and sorted out all the business for the Saturday I crew's first day of the season. We spent some time at the Annex waiting for the skies to clear slightly and finally made it up to Hawk Hill around noon. Visibility was fair with the fog continuing to lift, although the sun really didn't break through until about 2:30. Today was mostly a practice run and we only spent three hours on the hill, but we did see a lot of Turkey vultures and some Red-tailed hawks playing around in the sky. The only other raptor species we saw was an osprey, although we did spot a dark morph juvenile Red-tail! Our total count was 84 raptors in 3.25 hours with a rate of 25.8 hawks per hour.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 84&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 3.25&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 25.8&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 46&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 35&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 2&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20100821" rel="alternate" title="Saturday, August 21, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20100821" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Anastasia</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20100820</id><published>2010-08-20T15:55:43.505-0700</published><updated>2010-08-20T15:55:43.505-0700</updated><title>Friday, August 20, 2010</title><content type="html">Much like Thursday I, the Friday I team spent a day in the fog. Although there were no birds to be seen--with the exception of Fog Phoenixes--the group was able to get oriented to the site and go over protocols. With the fog remaining heavy, the team adjourned to the annex shortly before one to eat lunch and watch the local Red-tails.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 0&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 0*&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 0&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20100820" rel="alternate" title="Friday, August 20, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20100820" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Lindsay</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20100819</id><published>2010-08-19T17:01:09.200-0700</published><updated>2010-08-19T17:01:09.200-0700</updated><title>Thursday, August 19, 2010</title><content type="html">It was a low thick fog in the Headlands today.  The optimistic Hawkwatchers went up to the alternate count site and thought the skies would clear - but alas, they did not.  The team took a walk around the lagoon, hoping for a river otter sighting, and were instead entertained by a juvenile and adult Red-tailed Hawk doing barrel rolls and other acrobatics.  Hopefully the fog will clear for Friday's team!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 0&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 0*&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 0&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20100819" rel="alternate" title="Thursday, August 19, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20100819" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jill</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20100818</id><published>2010-08-18T16:52:29.360-0700</published><updated>2010-08-18T16:52:29.360-0700</updated><title>Wednesday, August 18, 2010</title><content type="html">A beautiful and clear day at our alternate hawkwatching site led to a highly productive day up on the hill. Red-tailed Hawks, mostly juveniles, were streaming by at a 14 bird per hour clip. Two Red-shouldered Hawks came in and allowed close inspection. An assortment of accipiters were spotted. And the season&#146;s first American Kestrel, a female zooming by fast and low, wrapped up the day nicely.      &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 119&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 5*&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 23.8&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 38&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 69&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20100818" rel="alternate" title="Wednesday, August 18, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20100818" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jonathan</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20100817</id><published>2010-08-17T18:18:31.617-0700</published><updated>2010-08-17T18:18:31.617-0700</updated><title>Tuesday, August 17, 2010</title><content type="html">First Day Collecting Data!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;After being fogged out on the first day of the season, we were wary of the fog that swept down the coast towards us in our first hour, but we were soon treated to bright blue skies and brisk winds that kept the fog away for the rest of the day! Because it was our first day at our alternate hawkwatching site, we spent some time arranging people and scopes to determine the best viewing quadrants and ended up with five viewpoints.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;We saw many Turkey Vultures and Red-tailed hawks and one of each common Accipiter species. There were two Peregrines and one Red-shoulder that flew by as well. Hoping for more hawks and clear skies tomorrow!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 87&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 4.5*&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 19.3&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 41&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 38&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 2&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20100817" rel="alternate" title="Tuesday, August 17, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20100817" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Anastasia</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20100816</id><published>2010-08-16T15:17:05.556-0700</published><updated>2010-08-16T15:17:05.556-0700</updated><title>Monday, August 16, 2010</title><content type="html">The opening day of the 2010 season and not a single migrating raptor to be seen. The fog was low and thick at our alternate hawkwatch site, limiting visibility considerably. Strong winds and a lack of birds forced the team to descend to the Annex, where observers were treated to the comings and goings of a few local Redtails but little else. The day ended at 1 p.m.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 0&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 3*&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 0&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20100816" rel="alternate" title="Monday, August 16, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20100816" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jonathan</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20100812</id><published>2010-08-12T21:16:52.073-0700</published><updated>2010-08-12T21:16:52.073-0700</updated><title>Thursday, August 12, 2010</title><content type="html">Only a few days to go. Hawkwatch's 2010 season starts on Monday.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
You may have seen one or two test messages on Facebook and Twitter floating by. Please ignore these! I'm just checking that the plumbing still works, so we can publish daily hawkwatch numbers starting from Monday.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
2010 is going to be a strange season for GGRO Hawkwatch. Due to &lt;a href="http://www.nps.gov/goga/parknews/2010-0324.htm"&gt;ongoing work on Conzelman Road&lt;/a&gt;, we don't have access to Hawk Hill on Mondays through Fridays, so we will be counting from a remote alternate site on those days. On weekends, the Hawkwatch team will be on Hawk Hill but access is still prohibited to the general public. The hawkwatching will be different enough from the two locations that we expect our alternate site's data will not be quantitively comparable with past years' data. However, we don't want to pass up the chance to do some regular hawkwatching this season to get a good qualitative feel for the 2010 flight.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Since the public will not be allowed to visit Hawk Hill until possibly November, we are setting up a new public hawkwatching and interpretive site just for weekends in September and October.  Known as the Annex, this is the large four-bench turnout on Conzelman Road just before you hit the Upper Conzelman Road locked fog gate.  We will station GGRO docents there from 10 am to 2 pm during all clear weekend days in September and October.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
We don't know how this will all turn out, but we do know three things: it's going to be an interesting season; there are going to be lots of beautiful raptors in the skies; and you can follow it all here, via the Facebook feed. Stay tuned.&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20100812" rel="alternate" title="Thursday, August 12, 2010" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20100812" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Julian Hyde</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20091206</id><published>2009-12-06T14:19:12.153-0800</published><updated>2009-12-06T14:19:12.153-0800</updated><title>Sunday, December 06, 2009</title><content type="html">A small team of five made it up to the hill today, to end the 2009 season.  A rather slow day, with only five species, but we got to see quite a spectacle when two Red-tails talon-grappled and went plummeting down quite a ways before letting go.  We left the hill just in time for it to rain on our cars as we drove back to the office.  Thanks for a great season, Sunday II!  &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Total Sightings: 89&lt;br/&gt;
Hours Counted: 3&lt;br/&gt;
HPH: 25.43&lt;br/&gt;
Total Species: 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Species Counts:&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 15&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 59&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Unidentified...&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.ggro.org/events/hawkwatchToday.aspx#20091206" rel="alternate" title="Sunday, December 06, 2009" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20091206" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Robyn</name></author></entry>

</feed>