<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><?xml-stylesheet href='http://www.blogger.com/styles/atom.css' type='text/css'?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/">
    <id>hydromatic-ggro</id>
    <updated>2019-12-01T11:52:22.531-0800</updated>
    <title type="text">GGRO daily hawkwatch update</title>
    <link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml" rel="next" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml" rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#feed" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <author>
      <name>GGRO</name>
      <uri>http://www.ggro.org</uri>
      <email>ggro@parksconservancy.org</email>
    </author>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20191201</id><published>2019-12-01T11:52:22.531-0800</published><updated>2019-12-01T11:52:22.531-0800</updated><title>Sunday, December 01, 2019</title><content type="html">"Dear Hawkwatchers, we accept the fact that we had to sacrifice a whole migration to be watched for whatever reason you deemed fit, but we think you're crazy for wanting us to fly close so you can tell us who we are. You see us as you want to see us, in the simplest terms, in the most convenient identifications. But what we found out, is that in each one of us is a Sharpie, and a Merlin, and a Red-tailed Hawk, a Roughie, and a Turkey Vulture. Does that answer your ID datasheet? Sincerely yours, The Raptor Club." Signing out for an awesome season! From all of us to you, we wish everyone happy holidays and many more raptor filled days!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20191201" rel="alternate" title="Sunday, December 01, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20191201" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Paula Eberle</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20191130</id><published>2019-11-30T14:35:16.114-0800</published><updated>2019-11-30T14:35:16.114-0800</updated><title>Saturday, November 30, 2019</title><content type="html">As the Saturday II team was preparing to leave for Hawk Hill, we felt small droplets of rain on our faces. Moments later, the droplets became a drizzle, so we dashed back inside the office to seek shelter. With the rain showing no signs of letting up, we decided to have our end of the season potluck inside! Despite the dismal weather, everyone had a great time reflecting on the season's highlights and sharing the delicious dishes brought by our amazing team members. We wish tomorrow's team better weather and thanks for a great hawkwatching season!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20191130" rel="alternate" title="Saturday, November 30, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20191130" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Paula Eberle &amp; Emma Regnier</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20191129</id><published>2019-11-29T16:38:02.023-0800</published><updated>2019-11-29T16:38:02.023-0800</updated><title>Friday, November 29, 2019</title><content type="html">The rain came down throughout the Bay Area today, but Hawk Hill remained dry, almost as if the clouds knew it was the Friday II team's last day. While temperatures were low, spirits were high and warm food filled our bellies from the annual potluck. With the migration season wrapping up, the flight was a slow one, yet we still had many views of Northern Harriers hunting around the hill. Two sightings of adult male Northern Harriers were had today, with these "grey ghosts" floating silently along the hillsides and even over the water. The highlight of the day came from two adult Peregrine Falcons. We first saw one, dive bombing an adult Red-tailed Hawk just off the South Platform. It then flew up into the sky and was joined by the second adult, before they both passed low over the team, one after the other. The day ended on a more solemn note, as some of our Hawkwatchers had their last day on the hill today, but we are excited to see what adventures they end up on next. Good luck for the last two teams of the season! We will see you next year.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 105&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5.25&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 20&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 7&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 28&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 14&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 51&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20191129" rel="alternate" title="Friday, November 29, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20191129" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Paula Eberle</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20191128</id><published>2019-11-28T12:42:25.770-0800</published><updated>2019-11-28T12:42:25.770-0800</updated><title>Thursday, November 28, 2019</title><content type="html">It was a frigid Thanksgiving hawkwatch, with wind chills bottoming out in the low 30s and a stiff breeze all morning. The birds were feeling the cold temperatures too, as few raptors were on the move. Perhaps it was apt that about a third of the birds we saw today were Turkey Vultures, including a flyby from our resident with tag number 368. We also saw a number of Northern Harriers, including two adult females. Though our count numbers were low, we still enjoyed our morning on the hill and the Thursday II team is sad to see the season come to a close. We wish everyone a safe and happy Thanksgiving, filled with great food and even better company! &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 43&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 2.5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 17.2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 15&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 22&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20191128" rel="alternate" title="Thursday, November 28, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20191128" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jeremy Pallant and Maggie Brown</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20191127</id><published>2019-11-27T16:17:46.744-0800</published><updated>2019-11-27T16:17:46.744-0800</updated><title>Wednesday, November 27, 2019</title><content type="html">With dark rain clouds looming all around us, the Wednesday II team kept one eye on the hawks and one eye on the clouds as we started our final hawkwatch count for the season. An hour after we began, the rain finally caught up to us, so we packed up and drove back to the GGRO office. But sunshine poking through the clouds gave us new hope, and sure enough the rain had moved on just in time for lunch. We reassembled the team and returned to Hawk Hill to resume counting. When we arrived, two adult Peregrine Falcons and an adult Red-tailed Hawk greeted us with daring displays of aerial acrobatics! In the mid-afternoon, an adult male Northern Harrier was spotted below Rocky Ridge, foraging alongside an adult female. Raptor activity slowed down by the end of the count, but we were happy to be back on the hill in the sunshine nonetheless. The Wednesday II team is grateful for our resilient team members and looks forward to more raptors next fall!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 98&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 4.5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 21.78&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 7&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 38&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 40&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 6&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20191127" rel="alternate" title="Wednesday, November 27, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20191127" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Emma Regnier &amp; Veronica Pedraza &amp; Jeremy Pallant</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20191126</id><published>2019-11-26T13:38:48.913-0800</published><updated>2019-11-26T13:38:48.913-0800</updated><title>Tuesday, November 26, 2019</title><content type="html">Today was chilly, with temperatures hovering around 48&amp;#730;F and rain in the forecast for the afternoon. The Tuesday II team bundled up in extra layers and kicked off our last hawkwatching day with a potluck feast to warm our stomachs. A few Red-tailed Hawks and Turkey Vultures cruised along the hillside, including everyone's favorite tagged vulture, #368. Just before noon, a pair of adult Peregrine Falcons caught the attention of the East Quadrant hawkwatchers. We watched the pair weave through the cables of the Golden Gate Bridge in hot pursuit of a small black bird. In an incredible feat of agility, one Peregrine stooped over midspan and collided with its prey, snatching it out of thin air. After their successful hunt, the falcons flew back towards the base of the north tower and disappeared from view. We ended our count abruptly as it began to rain, but we were grateful to have seen some action before the weathered turned. We wish the best of luck to the rest of the hawkwatch teams as we near the end of the 2019 season!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 83&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 3.08&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 26.94&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 47&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 19&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 7&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20191126" rel="alternate" title="Tuesday, November 26, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20191126" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Emma Regnier &amp; Veronica Pedraza</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20191125</id><published>2019-11-25T16:57:09.212-0800</published><updated>2019-11-25T16:57:09.212-0800</updated><title>Monday, November 25, 2019</title><content type="html">The last Monday II of the season was a beautiful day on Hawk Hill, with clear skies and a light breeze. Our count started off strong, with a good flight of both Red-tailed Hawks and Turkey Vultures dotting the sky. Mid-morning, two Peregrine Falcons were spotted stooping on one another over Land's End, putting on a show for everyone on the hill. Then, right in front of West Quadrant, a male American Kestrel appeared and fluttered past the hawkwatchers. The first of many male kestrel sightings, seeing these buoyant little falcons up close was a definite highlight of the day. As the sun began to sink, a gorgeous adult Red-tail cruised over the East Quadrant, stilling into the wind just above the hill. As if in a final salute, it tucked in its wings and gracefully glided across the path only a few feet in front of us! We're grateful for a great season together and are already looking forward to next fall!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 271&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 45.17&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 8&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 106&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 12&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 118&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 16&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 7&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20191125" rel="alternate" title="Monday, November 25, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20191125" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Maggie Brown &amp; Emma Regnier</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20191124</id><published>2019-11-24T16:51:25.432-0800</published><updated>2019-11-24T16:51:25.432-0800</updated><title>Sunday, November 24, 2019</title><content type="html">The sun was shining as the Sunday I team made its way up to Hawk Hill. With a nice breeze from the East and clear skies, we were excited yet wistful as we began our last day on the hill for this season. Despite the great conditions, it was a slow day. With only a few hours of heavy raptor activity, the team got to chat about the upcoming holidays and plan birding trips for the off season. One of the Common Ravens that so frequent the hill joined us in our potluck as it sat on Fish Rock with a tasty rabbit for lunch. The Northern Harriers were still buzzing around the hillsides and valleys, while male American Kestrels continued to hunt in the areas around the hill. One particular male was seen perched on a rock for most of the day and would return whenever he left. The Sunday I team wishes everyone a great last day of Hawkwatch as the season comes to an end, and we are excited for our next season!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 211&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5.75&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 36.7&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 8&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 88&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 99&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 3&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20191124" rel="alternate" title="Sunday, November 24, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20191124" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>PaulaEberle &amp; Veronica Pedraza</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20191123</id><published>2019-11-23T16:38:15.277-0800</published><updated>2019-11-23T16:38:15.277-0800</updated><title>Saturday, November 23, 2019</title><content type="html">The Saturday I team had a beautiful day to finish off their 2019 season. It was a bright sunny day with warm temperatures and a mild breeze with a decent amount of raptor flow for late in the season. Early in the morning, the hawkwatchers in North Quadrant picked up on a White-tailed Kite moving across the ridge below the FM towers. Several hawkwatchers who had not yet seen a White-tailed Kite this year eagerly crowded onto the North platform to watch the bird as it made its way toward Sausalito. Our count today also included nine dark morph Red-tailed Hawks, whose underwing covert patterns ranged from a speckled brown to a uniform dark chocolate color. Another positive sign from today was the high number of sightings of American Kestrels, which have had surprisingly low numbers this year. We counted eleven American Kestrels, one of the highest single-day counts of the season. We also continued this season's strong run on Northern Harriers, with eighteen total sightings, including three adult females. It's been a great season of hawkwatching for the Saturday I team, and although we're sad to see the season go, we know that great things await in the coming years! &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 240&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 40&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 10&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 87&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 18&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 109&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 11&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 3&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20191123" rel="alternate" title="Saturday, November 23, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20191123" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jeremy Pallant and Paula Eberle</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20191122</id><published>2019-11-23T16:19:57.036-0800</published><updated>2019-11-23T16:19:57.036-0800</updated><title>Friday, November 22, 2019</title><content type="html">After a season full of days shortened or cancelled because of weather, the Friday I team finally got up to the hill for an excellent day of hawkwatching. The sun was out all day long, temperatures fell comfortably in the 60s, and there was a light breeze throughout the day. With these great conditions came numerous great sightings. Shortly after our count began, a keen hawkwatcher picked up on a White-tailed Kite moving South just inside the Golden Gate. Just seconds after the kite disappeared from view, an Osprey appeared in the middle of the Golden Gate shipping channel, illuminated by the harsh early morning sun. About an hour later, the hawkwatchers in West quadrant picked up on a juvenile Bald Eagle flying west over Rodeo Lagoon. The Bald Eagle spent several minutes soaring with a comparatively minute adult Red-tailed Hawk before exiting to the west over Hill 88. The early hours of the afternoon were characterized by high numbers of Red-tailed Hawks, including several dark morph birds. At about 2:30 PM, the North Quadrant hawkwatchers spotted a bird hover hunting over between Fish Rock and Kremin's Crag. Unlike the Red-tailed Hawks we had been seeing throughout the afternoon, this bird had distinct white markings at the ends of its upperwings and a thick white band at the base of its tail. As the large Buteo moved through the East Quadrant, it showed off its dark belly band and carpal patches, proving that it was a juvenile Rough-legged Hawk. The whole team crowded into the North and West quadrants to watch as the Rough-legged Hawk made several passes back and forth between Hawk Hill and the FM towers before disappearing to the North. As the day was wrapping up, a second Bald Eagle was spotted over the North Tower of the Golden Gate Bridge. This bird showed almost no white in its undersides and had white feathers in its head and tail, although it still maintained a patch of dark feathers across its eye, indicating a fourth-year bird. By day's end, we had accumulated over 300 sightings of 13 different species. It was a truly sweet way to end the season and Friday I can't wait to see what next year brings!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 309&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5.78&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 53.46&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 13&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 128&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Bald Eagle: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 19&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 123&lt;br/&gt;
Rough-legged Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 7&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20191122" rel="alternate" title="Friday, November 22, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20191122" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jeremy Pallant</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20191121</id><published>2019-11-21T16:57:02.515-0800</published><updated>2019-11-21T16:57:02.515-0800</updated><title>Thursday, November 21, 2019</title><content type="html">The Thursday I team had a gorgeous day to conclude our season of hawkwatching. The sun was shining all day long and there was a modest breeze throughout the day, which brought in several interesting birds. Almost immediately after our arrival to the hill this morning, an adult Peregrine Falcon came speeding by the hill, passing just a few feet in front of the North and East Quadrant hawkwatchers. Later in the morning, the hawkwatchers in West Quadrant spotted a large raptor circling up over Rodeo Lagoon. As the bird soared, it caught the sunlight, and its bright white head and tail were unmistakable. The hawkwatchers watched in awe as the adult Bald Eagle spent several minutes circling over Point Bonita before departing to the West. After lunch, the North quadrant hawkwatchers spotted a large white bird with bowed wings soaring over the Volcano - an Osprey! The bird passed over North Slacker, showing off its characteristic M-shaped wings. As the day was wrapping up, the hawkwatchers in the West Quadrant spotted a feisty male American Kestrel divebombing an adult Red-tailed Hawk that was perched on Rocky Ridge. The Red-tailed Hawk dealt with the bombardment for a few minutes, before giving up and taking off to the Northeast. It was a terrific final day of hawkwatching for the Thursday I team, and although we're sad to see the season come to an end, we're already looking forward to what next year has in store! &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 219&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5.5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 39.82&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 11&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 79&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Bald Eagle: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 10&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 108&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 4&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20191121" rel="alternate" title="Thursday, November 21, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20191121" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jeremy Pallant and Paula Eberle</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20191120</id><published>2019-11-20T16:34:04.676-0800</published><updated>2019-11-20T16:34:04.676-0800</updated><title>Wednesday, November 20, 2019</title><content type="html">The Wednesday I team started our final count of the 2019 season with good visibility and strong winds from the north. A couple of Red-tailed Hawks circled Hawk Hill and several Turkey Vultures wobbled in the wind during the first hour. Shortly after 10 am, shouts of excitement from the East Quadrant drew the team's attention to a pair of Snow Geese flying low over Conzelman Road. We watched as they banked in the North Quadrant and disappeared behind a ridge. In the mid-afternoon, raptor activity had slowed to a trickle as the wind died down. Suddenly, a juvenile Bald Eagle appeared in front of Slacker Ridge and the whole team rushed over to watch it rise over the valley. The eagle continued to gain altitude until it disappeared from our view over Mt. Tam. The Red-tail flight picked up again in the last hour of our count and a small kettle formed over the Golden Gate Bridge. This small burst of activity was the perfect sendoff for the Wednesday I team!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 222&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 37&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 7&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 88&lt;br/&gt;
Bald Eagle: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 11&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 114&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 2&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20191120" rel="alternate" title="Wednesday, November 20, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20191120" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Maggie Brown &amp; Emma Regnier</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20191119</id><published>2019-11-19T16:50:48.723-0800</published><updated>2019-11-19T16:50:48.723-0800</updated><title>Tuesday, November 19, 2019</title><content type="html">It was a gorgeous final day of the season for the Tuesday I team. The sun was shining, the wind was blowing, and birds were on the move. Throughout the day, we were perpetually surrounded by Red-tailed Hawks, which accounted for more than half of our sightings. We watched several adult Red-tailed Hawks interacting and performing undulating displays in the strong winds. The winds also brought in three White-tailed Kites, two of which cruised by Hawk Hill, showing off their dark carpal spots and charcoal-black shoulders. Shortly after noon, a juvenile Bald Eagle rose up in front of Mt. Tamalpais, much to the excitement of both the hawkwatchers and a visiting group of children from Nature Bridge. The eagle effortlessly swept over the hill, seemingly unaffected by the high winds as it made its way North over Angel Island. It was also a productive day for falcons. Throughout the day, we had sightings of eight American Kestrels, several of which came within feet of the hawkwatchers. The end of our day was punctuated by a late-afternoon adult Peregrine Falcon, which stooped several times in North quadrant before disappearing from sight. While the Tuesday I team is sad that the season has come to a close, we had a year full of great sightings and we can't wait to see what future seasons have in store. Best of luck to the rest of the teams who will be having their final hawkwatching sessions of the season in the coming days!  &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 218&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5.75&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 37.91&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 10&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 37&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Bald Eagle: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 9&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 143&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 4&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20191119" rel="alternate" title="Tuesday, November 19, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20191119" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jeremy Pallant and Emma Regnier</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20191118</id><published>2019-11-18T16:51:41.247-0800</published><updated>2019-11-18T16:51:41.247-0800</updated><title>Monday, November 18, 2019</title><content type="html">It was a beautiful final day of hawkwatch for the Monday I team. In the morning, a Merlin breezed by the hill and hawkwatchers in the North Quadrant watched with delight as it flew directly between them and our Dayleader! It swooped by to catch a bug and departed as quickly as it came. Later in the day, an Osprey was spotted near the North Tower of the Golden Gate Bridge. It circled up with a pair of Red-tailed Hawks and eventually made its way south. Another exciting moment came about an hour later when hawkwatchers in the East Quadrant called in an adult Ferruginous Hawk! Everyone flocked over to watch the large buteo fly up over Kirby Cove before crossing the Golden Gate. These moments contributed to an excellent last day on the hill. The Monday I team had a great season overall and wishes the other teams good luck in the final cycle of the 2019 season!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 251&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 41.83&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 10&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 69&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 12&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 21&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 125&lt;br/&gt;
Ferruginous Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 5&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20191118" rel="alternate" title="Monday, November 18, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20191118" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Maggie Brown &amp; Veronica Pedraza</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20191117</id><published>2019-11-17T16:28:13.900-0800</published><updated>2019-11-17T16:28:13.900-0800</updated><title>Sunday, November 17, 2019</title><content type="html">Hawk Hill blessed the Sunday II team with some favorable air movement and clear skies, giving us a great flight with many close viewings. Early in the morning, a male American Kestrel popped up into the sky and flew straight towards the hill. We were delighted to see him fly close through each of the four quadrants, showing off his rufous back and steel blue wings, diagnostic of a male Kestrel. As has been seen in the recent days, we had an onslaught of Northern Harriers throughout the whole count. The high point of today, however, was a sighting of not one, but two juvenile Rough-legged Hawks. The first was seen rising above the water just in front of South Quadrant. Its dark belly next to its stark white underwings and tail were easily seen as the bird circled up. A perfect photo-op moment appeared when the large Buteo lazily soared above the Golden Gate Bridge. Our second Rough-legged Hawk was the last sighting of the day and closed our count perfectly! Seen far out over Mount Tam, its white tail gave it away as an exciting bird. It wasn't until we saw those dark carpal patches that we confirmed it was a Rough-legged Hawk. As we packed up to end the day, the raptor stuck around and flew South towards Slacker Ridge. Hope the favorable conditions continue through tomorrow, which starts our last cycle of the season!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 491&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5.75&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 85.39&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 9&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 169&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 43&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 26&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 9&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 221&lt;br/&gt;
Rough-legged Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 9&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 6&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20191117" rel="alternate" title="Sunday, November 17, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20191117" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Paula Eberle</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20191116</id><published>2019-11-16T16:31:13.785-0800</published><updated>2019-11-16T16:31:13.785-0800</updated><title>Saturday, November 16, 2019</title><content type="html">Fog filled the valley this morning, so the Saturday II team went birding at Rodeo Lagoon, eager to look for the Tri-colored Heron that has become a bit of a local celebrity for birders. We found the heron wading in the shallow water close to the bank, where we watched it catch a few sizeable fish. Blue sky broke through the fog above us, prompting us up to Hawk Hill. As we began counting, an adult Sharp-shinned Hawk flew in close from the West Quadrant and circled through all quadrants before crossing the Golden Gate. The rest of the day was slow, with negligible wind and fog clinging over the valley and ocean. Norther Harriers cruised around the hillsides, and we watched one juvenile bird pounce on a small rodent and carry it off to eat! Just before our count ended, a dashing male American Kestrel appeared from the West Quadrant and zipped towards the north, where he proceeded to kite above the Coyote Brush several times before finally catching an insect and eating it on the wing. We hope the breeze picks up for tomorrow's count!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 106&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 4.17&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 25.42&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 7&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 39&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 25&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 29&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20191116" rel="alternate" title="Saturday, November 16, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20191116" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Emma Regnier and Paula Eberle</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20191115</id><published>2019-11-15T15:53:42.777-0800</published><updated>2019-11-15T15:53:42.777-0800</updated><title>Friday, November 15, 2019</title><content type="html">The Friday II team started the morning on a high note. Before heading up to Hawk Hill, we made a quick stop at Rodeo Lagoon to look for the Tri-colored Heron that has been hanging around in the recent weeks. We spotted it foraging in some reeds near a Great Egret and a Snowy Egret. Once up on the hill, we had a much slower morning. The breeze was low, the clouds were close, and the birds were not flying. Around noon, however, the skies cleared, and we got more hopeful. A Buteo breakout occurred, with large numbers of Red-tailed Hawks zooming towards us from Mount Tam and crossing effortlessly into San Francisco. After the initial boom of birds, out raptor stream mellowed to a nice even pace. Early afternoon brought us a Ferruginous Hawk, lazily flying over from Hill 88. It circled in West quadrant for a few moments before heading on its way. About an hour later, a male American Kestrel decided to kite in the air just in from of North Quadrant, giving us a spectacular view of this little raptor. Just as the day was beginning to wind down, fog from the west blew in and covered the hill in a blanket of clouds, causing us to stop our count one hour early. Despite the early departure, it was an exciting day up on the hill!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 249&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5.2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 47.88&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 9&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 80&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 19&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 12&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 9&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 113&lt;br/&gt;
Ferruginous Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 3&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20191115" rel="alternate" title="Friday, November 15, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20191115" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Paula Eberle</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20191114</id><published>2019-11-14T13:23:39.114-0800</published><updated>2019-11-14T13:23:39.114-0800</updated><title>Thursday, November 14, 2019</title><content type="html">The Thursday II team arrived this morning with high hopes for today's hawkwatch. Unlike in previous days, there wasn't a blanket of fog hanging over the Headlands. On our way up to the hill, we made a brief stop at the East end of Rodeo Lagoon to look at the recently sighted Tricolored Heron and found it nestled amongst the marsh grass. Upon our arrival to the hill, conditions were comfortable with relatively good visibility. Temperatures were in the mid-50s and there was a mild breeze. Raptor activity was minimal throughout the morning, with migrating birds few and far between. Although our count was slow, we did see three species of falcons, including an adult Peregrine Falcon stooping upon potential prey in the North Quadrant, several Male Kestrels kiting in the South and West Quadrants, and a Merlin that made a beeline for the Golden Gate Bridge after popping up below the South platform. As lunchtime rolled around, the skies darkened and rain clouds closed in quickly. By 12:30, moderate rainfall meant an early closure to our count. It's certainly been a week of strange weather, but it was nice to be up on the hill today, albeit for only a couple hours. Hopefully our last meeting will bring more forgiving weather conditions and lots of great birds!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 77&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 2.33&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 33.05&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 35&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 9&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 27&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20191114" rel="alternate" title="Thursday, November 14, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20191114" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jeremy Pallant and Maggie Brown</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20191113</id><published>2019-11-13T13:46:52.798-0800</published><updated>2019-11-13T13:46:52.798-0800</updated><title>Wednesday, November 13, 2019</title><content type="html">The Wednesday II team was greeted with a wall of thick fog upon arriving in the Marin Headlands this morning. Sightings of a vagrant Tri-colored Heron at Rodeo Lagoon prompted the team to turn their binoculars to the water's edge and scan for this Gulf Coast native while waiting for better weather. We were walking along the shore towards its last known location near the east end of the lagoon when a romp of otters appeared close to the bank! The otters took turns watching us closely and diving down to catch fish. Before we reached the end of the lagoon, another birder pulled his car over to let us know he had just seen the heron fly towards the beach. We followed suite, but saw only Snowy Egrets and waterfowl. Not wanting to give up so easily, we ventured back to the east end of the lagoon for one last look. From out of the reeds, the Tri-colored Heron appeared! It landed just in front of us, to our delight and amazement! We watched it snag a fish and everyone got great looks at its bluish plumage and rusty-brown neck. Energized by our successful heron hunt, we decided to drive up Hawk Hill to assess the visibility, but unsurprisingly, we were met with only denser fog. We're hopeful that our last hawkwatch day of the season will bring clearer skies! &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20191113" rel="alternate" title="Wednesday, November 13, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20191113" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Emma Regnier &amp; Veronica Pedraza &amp; Jeremy Pallant</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20191112</id><published>2019-11-12T16:39:03.994-0800</published><updated>2019-11-12T16:39:03.994-0800</updated><title>Tuesday, November 12, 2019</title><content type="html">&lt;br/&gt;It was an amazing start to the morning for the Tuesday II team when a Ferruginous Hawk appeared over Rodeo Lagoon shortly after starting our count. Its bright three points of light stood out in the distance and caught our attention. As it circled closer to Hawk Hill, we were able to get great looks at its rufous shoulders and pantaloons, field marks signifying that it was an adult bird. It soared overhead for a short while, seemingly in no rush to fly south. In the afternoon, West Quadrant spotted another surprise species: a hulking, dark bird near the Rifle Range. We caught a glimpse of its white belly and back, and its enormous dark brown wings. It was a sub-adult Bald Eagle! Amazed, the team continued to watch this large raptor circle beneath us before crossing the fog-covered bay towards the city. Just as the fog was encircling the South Quadrant, a gray ghost appeared from out of the mist. As quickly as the male harrier appeared, it vanished, before popping up in North Quadrant moments later. As the day wound down, we concluded our count with happy hearts after another great day on the hill!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 229&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 38.17&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 11&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 100&lt;br/&gt;
Bald Eagle: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 20&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 12&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 69&lt;br/&gt;
Ferruginous Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 7&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20191112" rel="alternate" title="Tuesday, November 12, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20191112" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Veronica Pedraza &amp; Emma Regnier</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20191111</id><published>2019-11-11T16:43:44.667-0800</published><updated>2019-11-11T16:43:44.667-0800</updated><title>Monday, November 11, 2019</title><content type="html">After the fog-filled mornings of the past few days, the Monday II team was thrilled to begin our count with sunshine and good visibility. There were several Accipiters circling the hill in the morning, including a very close adult Sharp-shinned Hawk that breezed through all four quadrants. Shortly after, hawkwatchers in the North Quadrant spotted a large, steady raptor circling over Mt. Tam. As it started flying in from the northwest, we noticed its large head and plank-like wings which helped us determine that it was an eagle. It cruised over Hawk Hill and everyone got to see its brown belly and white underwing coverts - key field marks of a juvenile Bald Eagle! We watched with admiration as it continued its journey south. Afternoon flight was relatively slow, but we finished our day with an awesome sighting of a White-tailed Kite over Slacker Ridge. We are looking forward to our final day on the hill in two weeks!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 238&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 39.67&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 10&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 55&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Bald Eagle: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 22&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 35&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 107&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 8&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20191111" rel="alternate" title="Monday, November 11, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20191111" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Maggie Brown &amp; Emma Regnier</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20191110</id><published>2019-11-10T15:54:45.718-0800</published><updated>2019-11-10T15:54:45.718-0800</updated><title>Sunday, November 10, 2019</title><content type="html">Stray fingers of fog lingered in the headlands this morning, but the sun broke through and the Sunday I team was able to make it up to Hawk Hill for our count. With little breeze, the day was slow but still full of excitement. Mid-day, an adult male Northern Harrier flew in lazy circles in the valley off West quadrant, accompanied by a pumpkin spice juvenile Northern Harrier that was following him around. Soon after, two boisterous male American Kestrels were sighted over the rifle range and seemed to be playing with each other. Far in the North, a juvenile Rough-legged Hawk surprised us all as it flew over the landscape. Even from a distance, the white tail shone as the bird banked in flight. Later in the day, a Merlin zoomed into view, hunting insects in the sky. We were delighted to see a successful catch and watched as the bird ate on the wing. Suddenly, the fog rushed in and enveloped the hill, causing an early end to our day, but not before the ghostly silhouette through the fog of a close Northern Harrier sent us on our way. Hope the weather clears up for tomorrow!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 217&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 4.75&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 45.68&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 11&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 50&lt;br/&gt;
Bald Eagle: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 17&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 19&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 94&lt;br/&gt;
Rough-legged Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 11&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 8&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20191110" rel="alternate" title="Sunday, November 10, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20191110" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Paula Eberle &amp; Veronica Pedraza</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20191109</id><published>2019-11-09T16:42:46.371-0800</published><updated>2019-11-09T16:42:46.371-0800</updated><title>Saturday, November 09, 2019</title><content type="html">It was another foggy morning in the Marin Headlands and hawkwatching was once again delayed by poor visibility. The Saturday I team spent the morning walking around Rodeo Lagoon, where there were several exciting raptor and non-raptor sightings. Midway through our walk, an adult Peregrine Falcon made a close run over the lagoon, before stopping on a sandbar to bathe at the water's edge. On the Eastern end of the lagoon, the hawkwatchers were greeted by an Osprey and a juvenile Northern Harrier, a good omen of the improved hawkwatching conditions to come. Our walk around the lagoon also brought several exciting non-raptor sightings, including a vocalizing Sora hiding in the marsh grass, a Surf Scoter exploring the deepest part of the lagoon, and a pair of Wilson's Snipes foraging in the mud beneath the Rodeo Lagoon Bridge. At about noon, signs of clearing skies signaled that it was time to head up to the hill. Sure enough, we were greeted by mostly clear skies in the North, East, and West quadrants, and we were able to begin our count at half-past noon. Though our count only lasted three hours, we still had some great sightings, especially in our last hour. Between 2:30 and 3:30, we spotted a juvenile Sharp-shinned Hawk harassing a male American Kestrel who was trying to relax on Kremin's Crag. Meanwhile, an adult female Northern Harrier lazily perused the hills surrounding the Coastal Trail. Just minutes before our count ended, we were treated to a great view of two adult Peregrine Falcons soaring above the North tower of the Golden Gate Bridge. Though our time on Hawk Hill was only half of what it usually is, we still enjoyed every moment of it! We look forward to seeing what's in store for our last meeting of the season in a couple weeks! &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 133&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 44.33&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 9&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 22&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 15&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 72&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 2&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20191109" rel="alternate" title="Saturday, November 09, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20191109" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jeremy Pallant and Paula Eberle</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20191108</id><published>2019-11-08T16:21:08.499-0800</published><updated>2019-11-08T16:21:08.499-0800</updated><title>Friday, November 08, 2019</title><content type="html">The Friday I team got off to a late start because of early morning fog that didn't let up until about 11:00 AM. When we finally made it up to the hill, we were joined by the final Migratory Story group of the season. Undeterred by the residual fog, the group from John Muir Elementary School had their heart set on seeing raptors. Though there was little raptor activity throughout most of the program, a kettle of eight Red-tailed Hawks formed in front of the South tower of the Golden Gate Bridge just as the school group was prepping to leave. Several eager young hawkwatchers immediately identified these birds as Buteos because of their size and shape. The remainder of the day brought varying amounts of visibility, as fog moved in and out of the valley throughout the afternoon. However, poor visibility didn't mean a lack of excellent sightings. Shortly after noon, the hawkwatchers in the South and West quadrants were treated to the sight of a distant Osprey, who flew briefly over Rodeo Lagoon before disappearing back into the fog over the ocean. Moments later, a male American Kestrel came whizzing by the South quadrant, showing off it's gorgeous rufous tail in the harsh afternoon sunlight. As the day was winding down, we were lucky enough to spot a Merlin that preyed upon several dragonflies before zooming out of sight behind South Slacker. The day ended abruptly when fog engulfed the top of Hawk Hill just after 3:00 PM, but after several weather cancellations earlier in the season, the Friday I team enjoyed every moment of hawkwatching that we got in today! &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 174&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 4.08&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 42.65&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 10&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 22&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 11&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 31&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 94&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 3&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20191108" rel="alternate" title="Friday, November 08, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20191108" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jeremy Pallant</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20191107</id><published>2019-11-07T13:47:11.027-0800</published><updated>2019-11-07T13:47:11.027-0800</updated><title>Thursday, November 07, 2019</title><content type="html">The Thursday I team had high hopes for our penultimate hawkwatching session of the season, but unfortunately the weather was not on our side. Heavy fog settled into the valley in the morning, obscuring visibility and nixing the possibility of getting up to Hawk Hill early. With hopes that it would clear later in the day, the Thursday I team opted to bird around Rodeo Lagoon. The lagoon did not disappoint - ducks, waders, and marsh-dwelling passerines abounded. Among the species we saw were Eared Grebes, Western Grebes, Ring-necked Ducks, American Wigeons, American Coots, Marsh Wrens, and Common Yellowthroats. We also spent quite a while watching a Great Egret, a young Double-Crested Cormorant, and a Great Blue Heron foraging for minnows at the water's edge. After an early lunch, the team opted to go to the top of the hill, hoping that conditions had improved enough to hawkwatch. While there were hints of blue sky around the peripheries of the headlands, Hawk Hill remained socked in and we had to call it quits. Although it wasn't the way we expected to be spending our second to last day out, we still enjoyed our observations of other Headlands avifauna and we have high hopes that our season will end on a high note in a couple weeks! &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20191107" rel="alternate" title="Thursday, November 07, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20191107" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jeremy Pallant and Paula Eberle</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20191106</id><published>2019-11-06T14:25:12.851-0800</published><updated>2019-11-06T14:25:12.851-0800</updated><title>Wednesday, November 06, 2019</title><content type="html">Fog filled the valley this morning, so the Wednesday I team took to Rodeo Lagoon to look for waterfowl while awaiting better visibility on Hawk Hill. We saw several species of grebes swimming on the lagoon, including Western Grebes and Eared Grebes. A Surf Scoter swam solo on the far side of the lagoon, next to an American Coot wading through the reeds. Blue skies above beckoned us to caravan up to the hill. We started our count at 11 am, with good visibility around us and a small kettle of Red-tailed Hawks overhead. Just barely above a creeping layer of fog, a sub-adult Bald Eagle appeared over North Slacker! Its white belly stood out against the rest of its dark brown plumage as it soared with a Red-tailed Hawk. The fog continued to roll in and out, giving us only brief moments of clarity to scan for birds. The team remained vigilant despite the ever-encroaching fog. Eventually, the decision was made shortly after 1pm to end our count, as the fog showed no signs of retreating. The Wednesday I team is looking forward to our final day on the hill in two weeks!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 105&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 52.5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 10&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 19&lt;br/&gt;
Bald Eagle: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 9&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 58&lt;br/&gt;
Ferruginous Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 2&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20191106" rel="alternate" title="Wednesday, November 06, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20191106" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Maggie Brown &amp; Emma Regnier</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20191105</id><published>2019-11-05T16:48:34.972-0800</published><updated>2019-11-05T16:48:34.972-0800</updated><title>Tuesday, November 05, 2019</title><content type="html">This morning was characterized by a pronounced inversion layer which kept Fort Cronkhite blanketed in fog. However, the Tuesday I team was pleased to find that the top of Hawk Hill was out of the fog and clear and sunny with a light breeze. Our team was grateful to have a couple extra pairs of eyes hawkwatching with us today - we had a former GGRO intern and a former hawkwatcher join us for our count today! Shortly after arriving on the hill, a juvenile Peregrine Falcon came hurtling by the hill, showing off its heavily streaked undersides and dark upperwings. In the late morning, we were lucky enough to be joined by a Migratory Story group from Paul Revere Elementary School, who excitedly watched the release of a juvenile female Sharp-shinned Hawk as part of our raptor docent program. By lunchtime, most of the fog had cleared and there was good visibility in all four quadrants. However, despite great conditions, hawk activity remained relatively slow throughout the afternoon. The definite highlight of the afternoon was an adult female and adult male Northern Harrier flying together on Rocky Ridge. The female showed off faded upperwing coverts and creamy undersides and the male gave the hawkwatchers a great look at its ghostly gray upperwings and neat white undersides. It's hard to believe that our next time out on the hill will be our last for the season, but we intend to make the most of it nonetheless! &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 222&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5.83&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 38.08&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 9&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 50&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 17&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 45&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 12&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 84&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 4&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20191105" rel="alternate" title="Tuesday, November 05, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20191105" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jeremy Pallant and  Emma Regnier</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20191104</id><published>2019-11-04T16:46:39.822-0800</published><updated>2019-11-04T16:46:39.822-0800</updated><title>Monday, November 04, 2019</title><content type="html">The day started with a blanket of fog covering Fort Cronkhite, but as the team made its way up to Hawk Hill, we were delighted to see blue skies overhead. Within the second hour of our count, we were surprised by a juvenile Broad-winged Hawk circling in front of the Golden Gate Bridge! These little buteos are few and far between this time of the year since their migration through the Headlands generally peaks around late September/early October. Around 11 am, we were joined by a group of students from Mission Education Center for a Migratory Story program. The students learned how to use binoculars to search for birds and were treated to a special raptor release of a juvenile Red-shouldered Hawk. In the afternoon, we had a distant sighting of a juvenile Bald Eagle that soared above Angel Island and drifted across the Golden Gate. Just before the end of the day, the team had another exciting sighting when a juvenile Ferruginous Hawk popped up low in the East Quadrant. The bright white underside and face of this large buteo flashed with every turn as it drifted above Kirby Cove and gave the team a chance to admire it. While the number of overall sightings was low, the Monday I team was pleased to have high species diversity today, and we look forward to our last day out on the hill in two weeks!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 169&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 28.17&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 13&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 59&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Bald Eagle: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 12&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 21&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 62&lt;br/&gt;
Ferruginous Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 4&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20191104" rel="alternate" title="Monday, November 04, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20191104" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Veronica Pedraza &amp; Maggie Brown</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20191103</id><published>2019-11-03T16:34:43.331-0800</published><updated>2019-11-03T16:34:43.331-0800</updated><title>Sunday, November 03, 2019</title><content type="html">The haze is clearing, and the birds are flying up on Hawk Hill. The Sunday II team made their way up the hill today and were immediately greeted by a male American Kestrel flying by. As they set up, some of the hawkwatchers chatted about seeing an eagle on the drive over, so spirits were high, and people were ready. As if the birds heard us talking, a juvenile Bald Eagle emerged from behind Hill 88 and flew lazily over towards the hill, displaying white patterning in its underwing coverts. Mid-day, the team saw their second eagle of the day in the form of a juvenile Golden Eagle. Its tail had clean white on the base of each feather, indicating its status as a first-year bird. Two more Golden Eagles floated by before the day was up, both seen rather far away. The day was also full of Peregrine Falcons, both juveniles and adults. Hoping this high species count stays well into next week for the other teams to enjoy!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 436&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5.75&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 75.83&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 13&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 137&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Bald Eagle: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 17&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 39&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 17&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 195&lt;br/&gt;
Ferruginous Hawk: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Golden Eagle: 3&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 9&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20191103" rel="alternate" title="Sunday, November 03, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20191103" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Paula Eberle</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20191102</id><published>2019-11-02T16:51:18.169-0700</published><updated>2019-11-02T16:51:18.169-0700</updated><title>Saturday, November 02, 2019</title><content type="html">It was a quiet morning on Hawk Hill. The Saturday II team was in high spirits, and mid-morning brought the first of many Red-tailed Hawk and Turkey Vulture sightings. The morning also brought the first of a handful of adult female Northern Harriers, including one individual carrying prey in its talons. A group of students from Cal State Berkeley joined us on the hill today as a fieldtrip for their Neuro-zoology class. They learned about both behavior and adaptation of raptors, before getting a close look at a passing juvenile Peregrine Falcon. Mid-day brought some excitement, as a male American Kestrel was seen diving on a wayward juvenile Red-tailed Hawk just in front of the Golden Gate Bridge. As the day moved on, several adult Sharp-shinned Hawks blew past the hill and over the bay. Their steel-blue dorsal plumage shone in the sun as they continued on with migration. All in all, it was a pleasant day in the headlands.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 319&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5.83&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 54.72&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 10&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 107&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 14&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 26&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 141&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 12&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20191102" rel="alternate" title="Saturday, November 02, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20191102" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Paula Eberle &amp; Emma Regnier</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20191101</id><published>2019-11-01T16:49:25.166-0700</published><updated>2019-11-01T16:49:25.166-0700</updated><title>Friday, November 01, 2019</title><content type="html">The Friday II team was excited when they walked on Hawk Hill today, accompanied by a breeze from the East and warm, clear skies. Two fast moving male American Kestrels zoomed by the hill within the first half hour of our count and were just as quickly identified and recorded. The rest of the morning was a little slow, with the wind staying primarily from the East, and most of the birds that were seen were far away. Between the hours of 10 and 11 am, one of those far birds turned into a Rough-legged Hawk, the third sighting of our season! As the day moved on, the winds began to come from the Northwest, and large kettles of Red-tailed Hawks filled the sky, keeping our hawkwatchers busy. The last hour of our count, however, was truly spectacular. Just after the rotation at 2:30 pm, a dark-morph adult Red-tailed Hawk flew in from the West and gave us all a great view of its chocolate belly and underwing coverts. Less than five minutes later, a large white raptor emerged from behind the South platform. The team was excited to see that it was a juvenile Rough-legged Hawk, flying close to the hill as it made its way North! The dark carpal patches were easily seen with the naked eye as this large Buteo flew past us. Soon after, an adult male Northern Harrier was seen skimming the bushes beneath North Quadrant and stayed near the hill for the rest of the hour. The grand finale of the day came from a close encounter with an adult Ferruginous Hawk! The rusty colored "leggings" of this adult were clearly seen as it floated above the hill, then left to the North in a similar manner to the Rough-legged Hawk seen just a half-an-hour earlier. Today was a truly great day, and we hope the weekend flight stays strong!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 560&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 93.33&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 12&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 147&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 22&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 33&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 29&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 11&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 292&lt;br/&gt;
Ferruginous Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Rough-legged Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 10&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20191101" rel="alternate" title="Friday, November 01, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20191101" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Paula Eberle</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20191031</id><published>2019-10-31T16:37:05.721-0700</published><updated>2019-10-31T16:37:05.721-0700</updated><title>Thursday, October 31, 2019</title><content type="html">It's Halloween and the Thursday II hawkwatchers were eager to see what surprises the day had in store. In the early morning, the wind was howling and birds were speeding by the hill. The high winds brought several raptors close to the hill, including multiple adult Accipiters. The males showed off their slate-blue topsides in the beaming sunlight, and several adults of both sexes gave the hawkwatchers great views of their rufous-barred undersides. However, the undisputed highlight of the morning was spotted by our hawkwatchers in South Quadrant during the 11-12 hour. Among a kettle of Turkey Vultures and Red-tailed Hawks, a large backlit bird rose up from beneath the VA Hospital. The hawkwatchers were able to see that the bird was considerably larger than the other birds with which it was kettling, but intense glare made it difficult to identify. As the bird moved toward the Golden Gate Bridge, the large raptor showed off a gorgeous white tail and head and its identity was unmistakable - an adult Bald Eagle! The cooperative eagle spent several minutes on the Southeastern side of the hill before passing 15-20 yards in front of the East Quadrant on its way north. Shortly after the Bald Eagle's departure, another large raptor arose from the Southwest, showing off clean white undersides and inky wingtips. Without hesitation, several hawkwatchers identified it as a juvenile Ferruginous Hawk. In the afternoon, winds calmed down noticeably and raptors emerged in large numbers. Between noon and 3:00 PM, we averaged well over 100 raptors per hour, including high numbers of Northern Harriers and Red-shouldered Hawks. By day's end, we had accumulated over 500 birds of 12 different species! All in all, it was a beautiful autumn day of hawkwatching. Happy Halloween to all! &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 517&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 86.17&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 12&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 146&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Bald Eagle: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 23&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 53&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 29&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 242&lt;br/&gt;
Ferruginous Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20191031" rel="alternate" title="Thursday, October 31, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20191031" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jeremy Pallant and Maggie Brown</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20191030</id><published>2019-10-30T16:39:44.867-0700</published><updated>2019-10-30T16:39:44.867-0700</updated><title>Wednesday, October 30, 2019</title><content type="html">Walking up to Hawk Hill, we held on tightly to our hats as gusts of wind blew all around us. A pair of adult Peregrine Falcons coasted in overhead, dancing in the wind like aerial acrobats. Soon after, Red-tailed Hawks, Turkey Vultures, and Northern Harriers popped up from the surrounding hillsides and gained altitude quickly in the strong breeze. One dark Red-tailed Hawk caught the attention of everyone on the hill. Its body was almost jet-black, with streaks of white in its chest and on its head, and it showed wavy barring along its flight feathers. Despite having the dark trailing edge of an adult Red-tail, its tail had only a brush of red near the tip and was otherwise silvery in color. This unusual visitor was none other than a Harlan's Hawk, a sub-species of Red-tailed Hawk and a real treat for the hawkwatchers. In the spirit of Halloween Eve, an adult male Northern Harrier, or Gray Ghost, appeared in the late afternoon and circled the hill closely before disappearing as quickly as he had appeared. We can't wait to see what kind of interesting birds November brings for the Wednesday II team!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 327&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 54.5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 10&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 96&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 16&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 15&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 10&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 168&lt;br/&gt;
Ferruginous Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 7&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 11&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20191030" rel="alternate" title="Wednesday, October 30, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20191030" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Veronica Pedraza &amp; Emma Regnier &amp; Jeremy Pallant</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20191026</id><published>2019-10-26T16:31:17.954-0700</published><updated>2019-10-26T16:31:17.954-0700</updated><title>Saturday, October 26, 2019</title><content type="html">Saturday I had a slower day today up on Hawk Hill. Haze, combined with little to no wind, stuck around the hill until about 1:30, when we finally got a nice little breeze coming in from the Southwest. With low air movement, the raptors weren't moving much, but they still gave us great views. Three juvenile Northern Harriers joined us mid-day and scuffled in the sky in front of the North quadrant platform. Their pumpkin bellies and white rump patches flashed as they twisted and turned around each other. A bit later, a Western Meadowlark landed in a tree, much to the surprise of a nearby adult Red-tailed Hawk. The hawk proceeded to chase the Meadowlark around, before flying on its way through the bay. What we lacked in raptors, we made up for in Band-tailed Pigeons, with large groups flying over the hill throughout the count. A couple of fast-moving Merlins gave us our only falcon sightings of the day as they zoomed by South Platform and hurried into the city. Overall, the team had a fun time on the hill!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 208&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5.83&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 35.68&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 7&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 51&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 12&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 19&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 104&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 10&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20191026" rel="alternate" title="Saturday, October 26, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20191026" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Paula Eberle &amp; Jeremy Pallant</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20191025</id><published>2019-10-25T13:36:46.826-0700</published><updated>2019-10-25T13:36:46.826-0700</updated><title>Friday, October 25, 2019</title><content type="html">With PG&amp;E's planned power outages and current wildfires, Golden Gate National Parks Conservancy is canceling all group and volunteer field programs in Marin today and actively monitoring air quality index for possible future continuance of field programs.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;While the Friday I team wishes that we could have been up on the hill counting raptors today, we completely understand that recent heat waves and high winds make conditions unsafe for hawkwatching.  This feels especially pertinent given the smoky conditions experienced by the counters on Hawk Hill yesterday afternoon. Here's to hoping that November brings less extreme weather and a great late-season raptor flight! To all affected by the heat, by power outages, and by wildfires, please stay safe and take care! &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20191025" rel="alternate" title="Friday, October 25, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20191025" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jeremy Pallant</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20191024</id><published>2019-10-24T14:49:19.291-0700</published><updated>2019-10-24T14:49:19.291-0700</updated><title>Thursday, October 24, 2019</title><content type="html">The winds were blowing up on Hawk Hill today, with gusts in the early morning approaching 30 miles per hour from the East. With the high winds came fast-moving raptors, which kept the hawkwatchers on their toes. Just after we started counting, three adult Peregrine Falcons came whipping by the hill, demonstrating their remarkable speed. In the late morning, we were joined by a Migratory Story group from Willow Creek Academy, who had a great morning of hawkwatching. During their program on the hill, they were lucky enough to see a Turkey Vulture with a patagial tag, which provided a perfect opportunity to learn about our banding and tagging programs. Before heading off at lunch time, the group got to witness the release of a female Cooper's Hawk, which stuck around the hill for a few minutes, showing off it's "flap-flap-glide" flight style. The highlight of the afternoon was a leucistic adult Red-tailed Hawk, appropriately nicknamed the "piano bird" as it displayed bright white primaries and upperwing coverts. As it took off toward Angel Island, it was joined by a dark morph juvenile Red-tailed Hawk, showing off the remarkable contrast between the two birds' pigmentation. Unfortunately, the day ended a bit early because of smoke that billowed over the hill from a fire in Richmond. Though our day ended early, we were still in high spirits! &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 223&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 4.1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 54.39&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 9&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 55&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 19&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 14&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 121&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20191024" rel="alternate" title="Thursday, October 24, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20191024" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jeremy Pallant and Paula Eberle</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20191023</id><published>2019-10-23T16:55:52.523-0700</published><updated>2019-10-23T16:55:52.523-0700</updated><title>Wednesday, October 23, 2019</title><content type="html">Like the past few days, our count started slowly with warm temperatures and only a light breeze. As the wind picked up, so did the raptor flight, just in time for two visiting groups of elementary school students to observe wild raptors. The Marin Horizon kindergarteners enjoyed learning all about raptor adaptations and migration with a special interactive Hawk Talk. One of our expert hawkwatchers led the other school group around Hawk Hill as they practiced recording their own sightings together. In the early afternoon, the Wednesday I team was treated to several low-flying male American Kestrels just overhead. Their bright white "strings of pearls" were clearly visible from below, and vibrant blue upperwing coverts shone in the afternoon sun. Everyone was grateful to be back on Hawk Hill for a beautiful and busy day watching hawks!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 425&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 70.83&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 10&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 99&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 21&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 40&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 54&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 12&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 169&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 9&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 13&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20191023" rel="alternate" title="Wednesday, October 23, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20191023" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Maggie Brown &amp; Emma Regnier</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20191022</id><published>2019-10-22T16:28:48.553-0700</published><updated>2019-10-22T16:28:48.553-0700</updated><title>Tuesday, October 22, 2019</title><content type="html">The day on Hawk Hill was warm and mostly windless, but that didn't stop the Tuesday I team from having a relatively productive day. Today was a falcon frenzy, characterized by numerous falcon sightings, especially American Kestrels. By 1:00 PM, we had nine American Kestrel sightings, including eight males. Several of these small falcons were seen eating dragonflies on the wing, and one of the males made a close pass by the hill, giving today's Migratory Story group from Willow Creek Academy a wonderful look at its rufous tail and slate-blue shoulders. Additionally, there were sightings of five Merlins today, one of which was also seen picking dragonflies out of the air. Though falcon sightings tapered off in the late afternoon as windspeeds picked up, we had a couple of great sightings to finish out our day, most notably an adult female Northern Harrier, and a chocolate-brown dark morph adult Red-tailed Hawk. The Tuesday I team wasn't scared off by the heat and we look forward to seeing what November has to offer! &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 341&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 56.83&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 9&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 123&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 14&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 39&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 53&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 12&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 80&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 9&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 2&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20191022" rel="alternate" title="Tuesday, October 22, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20191022" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jeremy Pallant and Emma Regnier</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20191021</id><published>2019-10-21T17:10:48.330-0700</published><updated>2019-10-21T17:10:48.330-0700</updated><title>Monday, October 21, 2019</title><content type="html">It was a relatively slow day on Hawk Hill for the Monday I team. There was not much wind in the morning, so the raptor flow seemed to be minimal. As the day continued, we observed many of our usual suspects in addition to a striking White-tailed Kite and a close-flying male American Kestrel. Even with a lack of activity during some moments throughout the day, our hawkwatchers stayed focused on the skies and their vigilance payed off when a surprise visitor emerged in the West Quadrant... A large bird with long, broad wings and round face popped up in the west and immediately grabbed the attention of everyone on the hill. We quickly identified it as a Short-eared Owl and watched in awe as it flew into the vegetation below the hill. This was an especially exciting moment for the team since we do not see many of these nocturnal raptors during our count! Overall, the team had another productive and delightful day of hawkwatching.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 318&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 53&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 8&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 89&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 11&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 52&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 62&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 89&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 12&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20191021" rel="alternate" title="Monday, October 21, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20191021" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Maggie Brown &amp; Veronica Pedraza</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20191020</id><published>2019-10-20T16:27:13.741-0700</published><updated>2019-10-20T16:27:13.741-0700</updated><title>Sunday, October 20, 2019</title><content type="html">The fog is gone! Sunday II enjoyed a clear day today with a slight breeze coming in from the North. Though the morning was slow, a small pick up in the breeze brought more raptors as the day went on. During our weekly Sunday Hawk talk, a juvenile Ferruginous Hawk flew over the talk right as the group was learning about Buteos. This allowed the visitors to not only see a gorgeous bird, but to see the big wings and tail of a Buteo! About an hour later, the North Quadrant followed a subadult Bald Eagle as it made its way towards Hawk Hill, then moved on through the bay. Towards the end of the day, a Merlin appeared in the South Quadrant. In true Merlin fashion, this fearless raptor was seen repeatedly diving on a juvenile Cooper's Hawk that was flying by. A close White-tailed Kite closed out the day perfectly, with its white wings unmistakable as it flew within a kettle of Turkey Vultures. We are hoping for more great birds as the season moves on!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 444&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 74&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 13&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 139&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Bald Eagle: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 19&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 53&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 47&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 141&lt;br/&gt;
Ferruginous Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 18&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 23&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20191020" rel="alternate" title="Sunday, October 20, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20191020" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Paula Eberle</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20191019</id><published>2019-10-19T13:57:33.017-0700</published><updated>2019-10-19T13:57:33.017-0700</updated><title>Saturday, October 19, 2019</title><content type="html">For the second day in a row, the weather didn't favor the counters on Hawk Hill. The day started off with decent visibility in most of the quadrants, although ominous clouds settled overhead as the morning went on. By late morning, winds from the west brought cold temperatures and fog to the hill. The unquestionable highlight of the day was an adult male Northern Harrier, which spent the morning patrolling the hills below North Quadrant. Just before the fog fully enveloped the hill, a male American Kestrel alit on a pole below the Hawk Hill parking lot, giving the hawkwatchers a lengthy view of its rufous and blue plumage. Between 12:30 and 1:00 PM, the hill was totally engulfed in fog, and the Saturday II team reluctantly called off our count early. Here's to hoping for more forgiving weather next time around! &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 95&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 31.67&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 7&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 43&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 9&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 9&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 23&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 3&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20191019" rel="alternate" title="Saturday, October 19, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20191019" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jeremy Pallant and Paula Eberle</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20191018</id><published>2019-10-18T13:46:15.971-0700</published><updated>2019-10-18T13:46:15.971-0700</updated><title>Friday, October 18, 2019</title><content type="html">With decent visibility and a good amount of breeze from the North, the Friday II team was excited to begin our day up on Hawk Hill. A Merlin started our morning full of excitement, however the flow of raptors was slow today. A male Sharp-shinned Hawk lets its presence be known during a raptor release today for a school group participating in our Migratory Story program. The kids were very excited to see a raptor up close and to use their new identification skills that they have been learning. The fog and the clear sky battled each other all morning, but the fog ultimately won, causing the team to call it a day and leave the hill around 1. Hopefully this fog doesn't stick around much longer!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 102&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 2.75&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 37.09&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 35&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 16&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 10&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 27&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 5&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20191018" rel="alternate" title="Friday, October 18, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20191018" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Paula Eberle</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20191017</id><published>2019-10-17T17:59:44.216-0700</published><updated>2019-10-17T17:59:44.216-0700</updated><title>Thursday, October 17, 2019</title><content type="html">The Thursday II team got off to a great start with a decent amount of raptor activity in the morning. Within the first hour of our count, an adult Peregrine Falcon popped up close to the hawkwatchers in North Quadrant and gave everyone a great view before zooming west. The remainder of the morning was full of Northern Harriers and Cooper's Hawks with a few Red-shouldered Hawks mixed in. Excitement picked up in the afternoon when a juvenile Ferruginous Hawk cruised over Hawk Hill on its way south. At the same time, one of our keen-eyed hawkwatchers picked up on a Golden Eagle heading the same way. Both large raptors crossed the Golden Gate and continued on their migration. We wrapped up the day with a salvo of Peregrine Falcons - 3 adults and a juvenile! They entertained us with their vocalizations as they impressively stooped on an unsuspecting Red-tailed Hawk and one another. It was another wonderful day of hawkwatching and the team looks forward to our next day out together on Halloween!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 348&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5.92&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 58.78&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 11&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 114&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 14&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 15&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 46&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 130&lt;br/&gt;
Ferruginous Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Golden Eagle: 1&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 8&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 12&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20191017" rel="alternate" title="Thursday, October 17, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20191017" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Maggie Brown &amp; Jeremy Pallant</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20191016</id><published>2019-10-17T18:03:12.194-0700</published><updated>2019-10-22T18:03:12.194-0700</updated><title>Wednesday, October 16, 2019</title><content type="html">The morning was overcast, with barely a breeze to be felt from atop Hawk Hill. Aside from the resident ravens, we saw very few birds flying until closer to 11 am, when the flight picked up and Sharp-shinned Hawks began to pop out from behind the hills and clouds. Mixed in with the flurries of juvenile Accipiters were handfuls of silvery-blue adult birds, which stood out against the landscape. To our delight, several White-tailed Kites flew in close to Hawk Hill, showing off their brilliant white plumage and charcoal-black shoulder patches, before continuing their journey southward. Interspersed between the kite sightings, the hawkwatch team was kept busy by multiple dark morph Red-tailed Hawks flying overhead through the '5th Quadrant.' By 2:30 pm, fog encircled the hill and we lost most of our visibility in the South Quadrant. We ended the day with a buzzer-beating juvenile Northern Harrier and we can't wait to be back in two weeks!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 271&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 45.17&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 10&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 78&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 22&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 30&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 35&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 79&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 12&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20191016" rel="alternate" title="Wednesday, October 16, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20191016" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Emma Regnier and Veronica Pedraza and Jeremy Pallant</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20191015</id><published>2019-10-15T16:52:00.476-0700</published><updated>2019-10-15T16:52:00.476-0700</updated><title>Tuesday, October 15, 2019</title><content type="html">The valley was blanketed in fog when we arrived, so the Tuesday II team decided to bird on the beach and the lagoon while waiting for the skies to clear. We spotted two adult Cooper's Hawks perched around Fort Cronkhite, which sparked a group discussion about the differences in plumage between adult and juvenile Accipiters. Around noon, blue sky appeared over Hill 88, so the team raced for Hawk Hill to start counting raptors. An hour into our count, two Buteos soared in from the north and caught our attention. We watched them circle each other and realized that one bird was dwarfed by the other and lacked patagial markings - a Broad-winged Hawk! Its traveling companion turned out to be an adult Red-tailed Hawk, which gave the team an excellent opportunity to compare the two species. Towards the end of the afternoon, Hawk Blind called us over the radio asking if we wanted to participate in another Raptor ID Study. When the released bird popped into view, we found ourselves stumped by the dark and fast-moving raptor, scrambling to keep eyes on it though the brush. All field marks pointed to a Merlin, yet, based upon today's flight, it was most likely a Sharp-shinned Hawk... we recorded it as a Merlin and waited with bated breath for the reveal from the banding team. It was indeed a Merlin!! The team was delighted to end the day on such a positive note, and we look forward to our next day out on Hawk Hill!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 203&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 3.08&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 65.91&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 8&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 44&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 25&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 40&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 38&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 29&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 11&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 18&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20191015" rel="alternate" title="Tuesday, October 15, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20191015" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Emma Regnier &amp; Veronica Pedraza</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20191014</id><published>2019-10-14T17:37:02.381-0700</published><updated>2019-10-14T17:37:02.381-0700</updated><title>Monday, October 14, 2019</title><content type="html">It was an exciting day on Hawk Hill today! While the morning started hazy and slow, the wind soon picked up and encouraged some late-morning flurries of raptors. The Monday II team was joined by members of the Mendocino Coast Audubon Society around noon and enjoyed sharing the afternoon flight with them. There were many juvenile Northern Harriers that popped up around the hill throughout the day and everyone got great views of their pumpkin undersides as they weaved and wobbled across the hillsides. However, the most exciting moments of the day began in the late afternoon when the hawkwatchers in the East Quadrant noticed an odd-looking Buteo in Slacker Saddle. They alerted the rest of the team with excitement and it was determined to be a juvenile Rough-legged Hawk! We watched as it circled over Angel Island, exhibiting the bright white base of its tail and dark carpal patches before zipping towards San Francisco. Just minutes later another special Buteo popped up in the west over Rodeo Lagoon and came in close over Hawk Hill. It was a dark-morph juvenile Broad-winged Hawk! The team watched with delight as the dark little Buteo soared right over our heads. Just when we thought the day couldn't get any better, another Rough-legged Hawk was identified by a hawkwatcher in the North Quadrant and the team got an even longer look at the unique features of this arctic migrant. Each day on Hawk Hill brings something new!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 394&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5.5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 71.64&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 12&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 96&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 26&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 39&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 73&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 121&lt;br/&gt;
Rough-legged Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 11&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 15&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20191014" rel="alternate" title="Monday, October 14, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20191014" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Maggie Brown &amp; Emma Regnier</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20191013</id><published>2019-10-13T16:33:35.149-0700</published><updated>2019-10-13T16:33:35.149-0700</updated><title>Sunday, October 13, 2019</title><content type="html">While day 1 of Fleet Week brought the heat, day 2 was considerably cooler. A White-tailed Kite flying over the ocean welcomed us to Hawk Hill early in our count. The white wings and charcoal grey shoulders of the kite are always a wonderful sight to see. As the day went on, the fog crept back in and slowly tried to envelop the hill. A female American Kestrel proved to us that you can still count in the fog, however, as she perched on a rock right next to North quadrant, giving a clear view of her orange plumage. The fog took over most of the hill in the late afternoon, but East quadrant stayed clear, allowing visitors and hawkwatchers alike to view the airshow while scanning for raptors. The planes said goodbye to us as we packed our gear, and we are excited for our next time out!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 406&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5.5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 73.82&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 11&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 159&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 54&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 51&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 98&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 17&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 22&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20191013" rel="alternate" title="Sunday, October 13, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20191013" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Paula Eberle &amp; Veronica Pedraza</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20191012</id><published>2019-10-12T16:39:37.355-0700</published><updated>2019-10-12T16:39:37.355-0700</updated><title>Saturday, October 12, 2019</title><content type="html">The heat was on for Fleet Week, literally and figuratively. Temperatures on the hill climbed well into the 80s and lots of eager plane watchers came up to the hill to join the hawkwatchers. Neither the raptors nor the air show disappointed. In the late morning, an Osprey made a close pass by the West Quadrant, where it remained for several minutes before lazily soaring north over Mt. Tamalpais. The warm day also brought lots of Red-tailed Hawks, including five dark morph juveniles. One of the dark morphs passed directly over the hill, showing off its heavily spotted underwings to the hawkwatchers below. The day also brought a large diversity of migrating passerines, including high numbers of Violet-green Swallows and White-throated Swifts, as well as a smattering of Ruby-crowned Kinglets, which were among the first sighted this season. The day culminated with a great showing from the Blue Angels, which delighted all of the spectators on the hill. The Saturday I team can't wait to be hawkwatching again in a couple weeks! &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 415&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5.75&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 72.17&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 10&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 177&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 28&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 49&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 11&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 118&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 15&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20191012" rel="alternate" title="Saturday, October 12, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20191012" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jeremy Pallant and Paula Eberle</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20191011</id><published>2019-10-11T16:46:13.821-0700</published><updated>2019-10-11T16:46:13.821-0700</updated><title>Friday, October 11, 2019</title><content type="html">It was another sunny and clear day up at Hawk Hill! The morning started off with high winds coming from the North Quadrant but gave way as the day continued. This brought us plenty of close birds including many Accipiters and quite a few Peregrine Falcons.  It was also a great day for Northern Harriers with 13 individuals crossing our path throughout the count. Today also marked the first day of the Fleet Week Celebration! The team was delighted by a perfect viewing of the Blue Angels in the late afternoon. The Friday I team was excited to be up on the hill after several fog days earlier in the season. We're hopeful for many more days just like this one!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 453&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 75.5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 10&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 155&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 13&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 68&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 83&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 97&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 9&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 17&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 19&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20191011" rel="alternate" title="Friday, October 11, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20191011" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Taylor Barnes and Jeremy Pallant</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20191010</id><published>2019-10-11T16:06:39.788-0700</published><updated>2019-10-11T16:06:39.788-0700</updated><title>Thursday, October 10, 2019</title><content type="html">Due to the PG&amp;E de-powering, we were unable to conduct migration counts or banding today. &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20191010" rel="alternate" title="Thursday, October 10, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20191010" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Allen Fish</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20191009</id><published>2019-10-11T16:05:16.036-0700</published><updated>2019-10-11T16:05:16.036-0700</updated><title>Wednesday, October 09, 2019</title><content type="html">Due to the PG&amp;E de-powering, we were unable to conduct migration counts or banding today. &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20191009" rel="alternate" title="Wednesday, October 09, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20191009" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Allen Fish</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20191008</id><published>2019-10-08T16:01:45.863-0700</published><updated>2019-10-08T16:01:45.863-0700</updated><title>Tuesday, October 08, 2019</title><content type="html">Though the forecast today brought fog and high winds, the Tuesday I team wasn't deterred. In the early morning, there was a pronounced inversion layer with low-hanging fog obscuring visibility in the Southern and Eastern Quadrants. However, by late morning most of the fog had cleared and there was good visibility in all of the quadrants. We were joined this morning by a Migratory Story group from Malcolm X school, who spent their time on the hill identifying passing raptors and watching the release of a juvenile Cooper's Hawk. We were also lucky enough to be joined by a group of birders from Marin County Parks, who spent a couple hours hawkwatching with us. Though the fog crept back into the valley in the afternoon, we were still greeted by several excellent sightings. Just after lunchtime, a juvenile Golden Eagle emerged from the fog, effortlessly soaring North despite strong headwinds. After the eagle departed, we also spotted a White-tailed Kite and an adult male Northern Harrier, or "gray ghost," which seemed to materialize out of the fog. The afternoon also brought a wave of male American Kestrels, including three that appeared in rapid succession as the day was winding up. Though the fog eventually engulfed the hill at about 15:00, we were still more than satisfied with the days sightings!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 339&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5.5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 61.64&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 12&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 88&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 13&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 77&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 83&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 43&lt;br/&gt;
Golden Eagle: 2&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 9&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 12&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 16&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20191008" rel="alternate" title="Tuesday, October 08, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20191008" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jeremy Pallant and Emma Regnier</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20191007</id><published>2019-10-07T16:51:37.135-0700</published><updated>2019-10-07T16:51:37.135-0700</updated><title>Monday, October 07, 2019</title><content type="html">The Monday I team had another great day of hawkwatching with clear skies and warm temperatures. Raptors certainly weren't the only organisms flying above and around Hawk Hill today. The team counted hundreds of Vaux's Swifts, Violet-green Swallows, and a variety of dragonfly species. As expected, there were plenty of Accipiters popping up around the hill, which kept the hawkwatchers on their toes. It was also a great day for Broad-winged Hawk and Northern Harrier sightings, with both numbers being in the double digits. In the afternoon, we were thrilled to watch a kettle of Broad-winged Hawks form and circle above the mid-span of the Golden Gate Bridge. Throughout the day, a few raptors made closer appearances on the hill, and the team got great looks at a White-tailed Kite, an Osprey, and even a little Merlin! With migration picking up, we can't wait to see what the coming weeks have in store.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 405&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 67.5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 12&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 109&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 22&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 54&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 70&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 16&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 97&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 14&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 14&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20191007" rel="alternate" title="Monday, October 07, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20191007" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Maggie Brown &amp; Veronica Pedraza</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20191006</id><published>2019-10-06T16:47:44.694-0700</published><updated>2019-10-06T16:47:44.694-0700</updated><title>Sunday, October 06, 2019</title><content type="html">Sunny and clear skies welcomed the Sunday II team to Hawk Hill today. High winds from the North-East blew most of the day, but that didn't stop the birds, with a season high of 692 sightings. In the morning, an adult Cooper's Hawk flew close to West quadrant, giving the whole hill a great view of its rufous barred chest. Mid-day, visitors to the hill got to see another Cooper's Hawk up close, at our docent-led raptor release. The day closed out nicely with a far-away first-year Golden Eagle, and many falcons, including an adult Peregrine Falcon that flew in a close circle around the hill. The birds are flying and we're excited! Good luck to the rest of the hawkwatching teams this upcoming week.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 692&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 115.33&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 13&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 196&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 18&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 85&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 135&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Swainson's Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 207&lt;br/&gt;
Golden Eagle: 1&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 10&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 11&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20191006" rel="alternate" title="Sunday, October 06, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20191006" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Paula Eberle &amp; Taylor Barnes</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20191005</id><published>2019-10-05T16:51:39.312-0700</published><updated>2019-10-05T16:51:39.312-0700</updated><title>Saturday, October 05, 2019</title><content type="html">It was a beautiful day on Hawk Hill with great visibility and warm temperatures all day. Though wind patterns were inconsistent throughout the day, we still saw over 400 birds of 12 different species. The best sightings from the morning included a juvenile Bald Eagle, which soared over Mt. Tamalpais before making a very close pass over the hill, giving the hawkwatchers a great look at its skeleton-like underwings. We also had a juvenile Osprey come in very close to the hill, showing off beautiful brown and white scalloping in its upperwings.  In the late morning, we were joined by Golden Gate Audubon, who stuck around for today's Hawk Talk and some early afternoon hawkwatching. As they were preparing to head out, the banders caught a male Cooper's Hawk, which we released for them as part of our raptor docent program. The highlight of the afternoon was a pair of adult Red-shouldered Hawks, showing off beautiful crimson upperwing and underwing coverts, and bright white crescents in their wings. Though we didn't have tons of birds today, we still had some great sightings and we can't wait to see what's in store in a couple weeks!  &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 431&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5.83&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 73.93&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 12&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 141&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 2&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Bald Eagle: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 40&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 111&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 11&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 74&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 8&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 12&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 23&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20191005" rel="alternate" title="Saturday, October 05, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20191005" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jeremy Pallant and Paula Eberle</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20191004</id><published>2019-10-04T16:37:13.279-0700</published><updated>2019-10-04T16:37:13.279-0700</updated><title>Friday, October 04, 2019</title><content type="html">It was a beautiful and busy day up at Hawk Hill! The morning started off clear and continued to warm up as the day went on. The team and visitors were delighted with a raptor release which featured a juvenile Red-shouldered Hawk. The hawk decided to stick around for a bit longer and gave us a great viewing from the East quadrant. Later in the day, a male American Kestrel decided to show off its hunting abilities by catching an insect mid-air and eating it on the wing. The day sped by, just like many of the falcons that graced our presence today, and we soon reached 609 raptor sightings, the highest of the season! It was a productive day up at the hill and we're excited for many more days just like it!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 609&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 101.5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 11&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 189&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 12&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 91&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 135&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 19&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 9&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 108&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 16&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 25&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20191004" rel="alternate" title="Friday, October 04, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20191004" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Taylor Barnes &amp; Paula Eberle</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20191003</id><published>2019-10-03T16:30:10.616-0700</published><updated>2019-10-03T17:50:10.616-0700</updated><title>Thursday, October 03, 2019</title><content type="html">The morning started off clear and windless, with comfortable temperatures in the high 50s and low 60s and terrific visibility. In the late morning, we were joined by a Migratory Story group from a local elementary school. The kids showed off their knowledge of identifying various groups of raptors and were lucky enough to see the release of a female Sharp-shinned Hawk before they took off at lunchtime. In the afternoon, winds picked up considerably, and so too did raptor activity. The whipping winds from the North and West brought in many small kettles of Accipiters and Red-tailed Hawks. We were also lucky enough to spot several of our less common raptors - an Osprey passing low beneath the West quadrant, male and female American Kestrels zipping over Fish Rock, and a handful of Broad-winged Hawks crossing over the Golden Gate Bridge on their way south. The busy afternoon gave us high hopes for increased raptor activity in the coming days!  &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 453&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 75.5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 11&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 90&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 64&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 134&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 111&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 24&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 27&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20191003" rel="alternate" title="Thursday, October 03, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20191003" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jeremy Pallant and Maggie Brown</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20191002</id><published>2019-10-02T16:35:41.397-0700</published><updated>2019-10-02T16:35:41.397-0700</updated><title>Wednesday, October 02, 2019</title><content type="html">Another clear day on Hawk Hill today with plenty of sunshine, yet barely any breeze and occasional bursts of raptor activity. Together with education staff from the Crissy Field Center, we held a Migratory Story program for students from the Edwin and Anita Lee School. Full of energy, the students learned to recognize the shapes of the different raptor groups and eagerly scanned the skies for birds to tally on their clipboards. Before departing, they had the awesome opportunity to observe a raptor release of a juvenile Sharp-shinned Hawk and together we wished the bird well on the rest of its migration. From North Quadrant, a dark morph juvenile Red-tailed Hawk was spotted soaring above Rocky Ridge. To the excitement of the photographers on the hill, this bird was anything but camera shy, as it slowly rose overhead and gave everyone great looks at its heavily streaked underbelly. In addition to seeing a few other dazzling birds, including a low-flying young Peregrine Falcon, we were lucky to spot two Humpback whales breaching out in the mouth of the bay. Looking forward to our next day on the hill! &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 239&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 6.17&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 38.74&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 11&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 88&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 36&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 43&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 42&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 8&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20191002" rel="alternate" title="Wednesday, October 02, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20191002" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Emma Regnier &amp; Veronica Pedraza &amp; Jeremy Pallant</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20191001</id><published>2019-10-01T16:53:41.372-0700</published><updated>2019-10-01T16:53:40.372-0700</updated><title>Tuesday, October 01, 2019</title><content type="html">The skies were clear of fog and raptors as we started our count this morning. A noisy flock of Cedar Waxwings buzzed over the hill, entertaining the hawkwatchers with their boisterous chatter. The Accipiter flight picked up in the early afternoon, along with some other exciting species. Soaring between a group of Turkey Vultures loomed an enormous, plank-winged raptor. With the whole team working the mystery bird, it suddenly banked and flashed its clean white tail with a dark subterminal band - it was a juvenile Golden Eagle! Within the last half an hour of the count, a White-tailed Kite appeared over Rodeo Lagoon and soared with two young Sharp-shinned Hawks. Moments later, a flash of blue and orange caught our eye: a male American Kestrel swooped through the West Quadrant and became our first falcon sighting of the day. Even though we only saw sparse flurries of birds at a time, we were thrilled to get a diversity of species over the course of the day.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 257&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5.83&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 44.08&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 11&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 102&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 2&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 9&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 49&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 54&lt;br/&gt;
Golden Eagle: 1&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 18&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 31&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20191001" rel="alternate" title="Tuesday, October 01, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20191001" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Veronica Pedraza &amp; Emma Regnier</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190930</id><published>2019-09-30T17:20:35.395-0700</published><updated>2019-09-30T17:30:35.395-0700</updated><title>Monday, September 30, 2019</title><content type="html">We caravanned up to Hawk Hill with the banding teams bright and early to begin our raptor count shortly after 9am. Visibility was excellent in all quadrants, and there was a refreshing breeze blowing off the ocean. A young Broad-winged Hawk nearly slipped past us, until a keen-eyed hawkwatcher noticed it lacked a Red-tail's dark patagial marks. Around mid-morning, South Quadrant spotted a large whale feeding in the Golden Gate. The whale's shorter and more rounded dorsal fin clued us in to the species: Humpback! Seabirds swarmed the water's surface every time the whale emerged until eventually the whale had its fill and disappeared. Just as the afternoon flight of raptors seemed to be slowing down, two juvenile Golden Eagles soared into view from over Sausalito Ridge! We got some incredible looks at the white patches in their primaries and clean white tails with dark subterminal bands. Moments later, another eagle appeared over Angel Island and cruised along Slacker Ridge. However, this eagle sported a dirty white head and tail, large yellow beak, and lacked white in its primaries - a sub-adult Bald Eagle! We felt very lucky to have the chance to compare the plumages and features of these two impressive raptor species as we wrapped up another great day of hawkwatching.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 322&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 6.33&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 50.87&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 12&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 104&lt;br/&gt;
Bald Eagle: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 28&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 58&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 92&lt;br/&gt;
Golden Eagle: 2&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 11&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 17&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190930" rel="alternate" title="Monday, September 30, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190930" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Maggie Brown &amp; Emma Regnier</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190929</id><published>2019-09-29T16:53:35.871-0700</published><updated>2019-09-29T16:53:35.871-0700</updated><title>Sunday, September 29, 2019</title><content type="html">Clear skies and a breeze from the south welcomed the Sunday I team up to Hawk Hill for a busy morning of counting. The hill was visited by many birds and people, as multiple bird-watching groups joined us for part of the day. An Osprey came out of the North Quadrant and flew close over the hill, giving both the hawkwatchers and visitors a wonderful view of this large raptor. Within the next hour, 3 adult Peregrine Falcons gave a close show for visitors waiting for the Sunday hawk talk, at which a juvenile male Cooper's Hawk wowed the crowd during a raptor release. The day slowed down into the afternoon, but a far juvenile Golden Eagle closed the day out perfectly. We are excited to see what the next days hold!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 448&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 74.67&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 12&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 136&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 55&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 73&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 15&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 119&lt;br/&gt;
Golden Eagle: 1&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 30&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 35&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190929" rel="alternate" title="Sunday, September 29, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190929" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Veronica Pedraza &amp; Paula Eberle</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190928</id><published>2019-09-28T16:28:44.856-0700</published><updated>2019-09-28T16:28:44.856-0700</updated><title>Saturday, September 28, 2019</title><content type="html">There was a lot of hustle and bustle on Hawk Hill today - tons of people and birds were on the move. We were joined on the hill by several local birding groups, who gave us some extra pairs of eyes on a busy day of hawkwatching. The first highlight of the day was a partially leucistic adult Red-tailed Hawk, whose dorsal side resembled the keys on a piano. We were also lucky enough to see two juvenile Ferruginous Hawks today, one of which came overhead in the middle of today's hawk talk! The bird's clean white undersides and "three points of light" were on clear display for all to see. Today was also a busy day for falcons - a dozen Merlins and 8 Peregrine Falcons were sighted throughout the day. We also had a decent movement of Broad-Winged Hawks today, including a dark morph juvenile. All in all, it was a great day of hawkwatching, with more than 500 birds of 13 different species seen today. Both of those figures are seasonal highs thus far. May the good weather and abundant migration continue for many days to come!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 525&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 87.5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 13&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 178&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 44&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 91&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 20&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 121&lt;br/&gt;
Ferruginous Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 12&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 8&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 18&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 29&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190928" rel="alternate" title="Saturday, September 28, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190928" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jeremy Pallant and Paula Eberle</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190927</id><published>2019-09-27T14:15:45.325-0700</published><updated>2019-09-27T14:15:45.325-0700</updated><title>Friday, September 27, 2019</title><content type="html">Despite foggy skies in the early morning, the Friday I team still got up to the hill early with hopes of having a productive day of hawkwatching. For the first hour of counting, conditions looked promising - the low-hanging fog in the valley lifted and there was good visibility in the East, South, and West quadrants. Unfortunately, at about 10:30, winds from the West blew the fog back in and it didn't end up clearing for the remainder of the day. While we waited for the fog to clear, we were lucky enough to see a couple of American Kestrels that made quick passes over the hill before disappearing into the fog again. We also saw a few adult Red-tailed Hawks hugging the low brush beneath the southern platform, looking for prey below. Though our day of counting ended up being short, we still had a great time up on the hill and we're optimistic about having better conditions in two weeks!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 14&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0.83&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 16.87&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 7&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190927" rel="alternate" title="Friday, September 27, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190927" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jeremy Pallant</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190926</id><published>2019-09-26T17:31:10.994-0700</published><updated>2019-09-26T17:31:10.994-0700</updated><title>Thursday, September 26, 2019</title><content type="html">Hawk Hill was surrounded by fog when we arrived this morning, so we patiently waited for the sun to bring us enough visibility to begin our count. The birds must have shared our patience, because just as the fog lifted, our first raptor appeared from the mist: a Merlin! Shortly after, we spotted our first of many flocks of nomadic Band-tailed Pigeons - we ended up counting almost 300 Band-tails over the course of the day. Multiple juvenile Northern Harriers bobbed and weaved their way around the Headlands, adding a little pumpkin spice to this blustery autumn day. We watched as two young harriers snaked their way below Rocky Ridge, just barely skimming the top of the Coyote Brush as they concentrated on hunting. We invited several Nature Bridge school groups to watch for raptors with us and discussed the significance of long-term ecological studies. The students were eager to spot passing birds, and even got a close look at a male American Kestrel as it flew overhead. The team had a fun day and we can't wait to get back up on the hill next time!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 295&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5.5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 53.64&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 8&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 91&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 14&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 15&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 155&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 4&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190926" rel="alternate" title="Thursday, September 26, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190926" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Emma Regnier and Paula Eberle</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190925</id><published>2019-09-25T15:02:27.395-0700</published><updated>2019-09-25T15:02:27.395-0700</updated><title>Wednesday, September 25, 2019</title><content type="html">We started our raptor count with clear skies and a light breeze from the east. Within only a few minutes, we heard the distinctive, raspy calls from two pairs of adult Red-tailed hawks that were circling above Kirby Cove. Among the Red-tails was a juvenile Broad-winged Hawk that soared at eye-level along the hill before gliding overhead and giving everyone great looks at its pale underwings and streaky breast. It was a premonition of what was to come... We were delighted by the appearances of several more Broad-winged Hawks throughout the day, including a dark morph and an adult - sporting its signature black and white tail! To our surprise, we spotted multiple adult birds of several species, including a Swainson's Hawk, Red-shouldered Hawk, dark morph Red-tailed Hawk, Northern Harrier, Cooper's Hawk, and Sharp-shinned Hawk. It was a great learning opportunity for the team to compare the plumages of the adult birds with our usual flight of juveniles. By the early afternoon, we lost our cool breeze and had to end our count early due to the heat. Nonetheless, we are grateful for an exciting day of hawkwatching and wish tomorrow's team some cooler weather!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 307&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 76.75&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 10&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 63&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 19&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 61&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Swainson's Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 129&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 13&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190925" rel="alternate" title="Wednesday, September 25, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190925" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Maggie Brown &amp; Emma Regnier</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190924</id><published>2019-09-24T16:47:03.142-0700</published><updated>2019-09-24T16:47:03.142-0700</updated><title>Tuesday, September 24, 2019</title><content type="html">It was a hot day up on Hawk Hill today, as temperatures wavered in the upper 80's for most of the day. Wind was scarce in the morning, but picked up in the afternoon, which both cooled us off and brought in more birds for us to count. Visibility was excellent all day, as we could even see the ocean beyond the Farallon Islands. There was a fair amount of Accipiter movement to keep us on our toes. Both Sharp-shinned and Cooper's Hawks flew in close to the hill and gave us great looks. We also had a relatively good day for Merlins and Red-shouldered Hawks, of which we saw a handful of each species. We were hoping to see Broad-winged Hawks, but we didn't spot a single one today. In addition to the migrating raptors, there were flocks of migrating passerines flying overhead, including: Vaux's and Black Swifts, Lesser Goldfinches, Band-tailed Pigeons, Cedar Waxwings, Say's Phoebes, and Blue-gray Gnatcatchers. Hoping for an equally busy and productive day for our next time hawkwatching!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 392&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 65.33&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 10&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 129&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 46&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 91&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 83&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 18&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 19&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190924" rel="alternate" title="Tuesday, September 24, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190924" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jeremy Pallant &amp; Emma Regnier</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190923</id><published>2019-09-23T17:08:13.820-0700</published><updated>2019-09-23T17:08:13.820-0700</updated><title>Monday, September 23, 2019</title><content type="html">After a foggy start to our morning, the Monday I team was eager to count some raptors. Once on the hill, we immediately jumped into action since there were many hawks already flying in the clear skies surrounding Hawk Hill. The day was filled with plenty of Accipiters that would pass through in subsequent bursts. We were excited to observe several Broad-winged Hawks, and even got to see a dark morph individual! Another highlight of the day occurred in the early afternoon when hawkwatchers in the West Quadrant spotted a Merlin zoom right over the hill. It came in close and gave us a great view before quickly flying towards the Golden Gate Bridge. While the day was fast-paced, the team stayed on top of everything with good communication and determination. We are grateful for another productive day of hawkwatching!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 404&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 4.25&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 95.06&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 9&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 57&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 87&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 138&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 90&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 13&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 15&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190923" rel="alternate" title="Monday, September 23, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190923" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Maggie Brown &amp; Veronica Pedraza</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190922</id><published>2019-09-22T13:47:05.906-0700</published><updated>2019-09-22T13:47:05.906-0700</updated><title>Sunday, September 22, 2019</title><content type="html">Fog surrounded Hawk Hill today and did not release its grip in time for the Sunday II team to make a count. While initially hopeful after the sunny days of this past week, the team drove up to the Hill to wait out the fog. Small patches of sun greeted us, but Southern winds brought more fog that enveloped the Hill. As we drove back down to the office, a small group of raptors flew next to the road, allowing the team to see a Red-tailed Hawk and some Accipiters. Hopefully the sun returns and this next week is full of raptors!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190922" rel="alternate" title="Sunday, September 22, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190922" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Paula Eberle</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190921</id><published>2019-09-21T16:42:19.973-0700</published><updated>2019-09-21T16:42:19.973-0700</updated><title>Saturday, September 21, 2019</title><content type="html">It was a hot one on the hill today and the raptors were on the move. The Saturday II team had a busy day on the hill, with our total number of raptor sightings approaching 500. We were lucky enough to see ten species, including three species of falcon. Three Merlins were seen from the hill today, and there were also sightings of Peregrine Falcons and American Kestrels of both sexes. Other highlights from the day include two Osprey, two juvenile Red-shouldered Hawks and several juvenile Northern Harriers. All in all, it was a solid day of counting and the Saturday II team was kept on our toes all day long after being fogged out during the first two cycles. Best of luck to all of the hawk watchers as peak ramps up!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 493&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5.92&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 83.28&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 10&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 109&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 74&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 114&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 157&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 12&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 15&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190921" rel="alternate" title="Saturday, September 21, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190921" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jeremy Pallant and Paula Eberle</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190920</id><published>2019-09-20T16:37:27.610-0700</published><updated>2019-09-20T16:37:27.610-0700</updated><title>Friday, September 20, 2019</title><content type="html">Today held clear skies across the bay, giving the Friday II team a warm and wonderful day up on Hawk Hill. Starting off strong, the team saw a Merlin around 9:45 that flew right over the top of the hill and then dove after some prey! While it did not catch what it was aiming for, it was exciting to see the fierce little hunter in action. An adult Red-shouldered Hawk was seen flying low in the North Quadrant, with its vibrant red body and stark black-and-white patterning on its wings. The most exciting bird of the day, however, was an adult Swainson's Hawk. It flew right over the silhouettes, giving the whole team a clear view of the bird's dark flight feathers and dark bib. Hoping for another great day tomorrow!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 343&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5.83&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 58.83&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 11&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 117&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 34&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 57&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Swainson's Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 100&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 13&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190920" rel="alternate" title="Friday, September 20, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190920" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Paula Eberle &amp; Taylor Barnes</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190919</id><published>2019-09-19T16:49:12.046-0700</published><updated>2019-09-19T16:49:12.046-0700</updated><title>Thursday, September 19, 2019</title><content type="html">It was a gorgeous day on Hawk Hill - great visibility, temperatures in the 60s and 70s, and a slight breeze. Because of the excellent conditions, we had plenty of neat avian visitors, both raptor and non-raptor. Our very first sighting of the day was a White-tailed Kite, which hung out for a few minutes over Middle Kingdom before making a very close pass over the hill. It ended up being the first of four kites we saw today, all of which came in relatively close to the hill, much to the delight of the Thursday II hawkwatchers. Later in the morning, we got a terrific view of two adult Peregrine Falcons, which came over the hill chattering and stooping upon one another. Our morning also brought some excellent non-raptor migrants, including three Black Swifts. Our day was capped off by a small flurry of falcons, including a male American Kestrel, which made a quick pass over the hill on his way south and a late afternoon Merlin, which spent several minutes circling the North Tower of the Golden Gate Bridge. All in all, it was a great day of hawkwatching! We're looking forward to meeting again in two weeks, when the heart of peak should be upon us!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 305&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 50.83&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 11&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 119&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 36&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 32&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 86&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 7&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 13&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190919" rel="alternate" title="Thursday, September 19, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190919" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jeremy Pallant and Maggie Brown</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190918</id><published>2019-09-18T13:44:06.930-0700</published><updated>2019-09-18T13:44:06.930-0700</updated><title>Wednesday, September 18, 2019</title><content type="html">To the surprise of both the Hawkwatch and Banding teams, we found ourselves caught in a light rain shower right as we were preparing to leave. Donning raincoats and binoculars, we braved the rain and started birding around the lagoon while waiting for the weather to improve. We spotted a Great Egret fishing alongside a Snowy Egret as we crossed the footbridge onto the beach. A family of Western Bluebirds flitted around the sand, stopping to snatch up small insects. The interns returned to the office to host a visiting group of 5th graders from St. Andrew's School and gave them a presentation on the GGRO's mission and the science of raptor migration. Meanwhile, the rest of the Wednesday II team hiked around the lagoon looking for more birds. They saw one Turkey Vulture, two Red-tailed Hawks, and a Great Horned Owl sleeping in a nearby Eucalyptus tree! The fog refused to lift from Hawk Hill, so we ended our day early, but we have our fingers crossed for better weather in two weeks.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190918" rel="alternate" title="Wednesday, September 18, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190918" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Emma Regnier &amp; Veronica Pedraza</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190917</id><published>2019-09-17T16:59:04.568-0700</published><updated>2019-09-17T16:59:04.568-0700</updated><title>Tuesday, September 17, 2019</title><content type="html">We had clear skies today for the Tuesday II team thanks to a break from the recent fog. Although the morning started off calm and quiet, the breeze soon picked up from the west and carried all types of raptors with it. From Point Bonita, a bright and flashy raptor caught our attention - our team's first White-tailed Kite sighting this season. Several juvenile Red-shouldered Hawks were spotted soaring up above the North Quadrant in the company of Cooper's Hawks and Red-tailed Hawks. We were fortunate to participate in 6 raptor ID studies over the course of the day, which challenged our Accipiter ID skills and generated great discussions. Students from George Moscone Elementary School visited Hawk Hill today as part of their Migratory Story program. The students practiced hawkwatching, experienced a raptor release, and left the hill buzzing with enthusiasm. As the day wound down, the birds kept on coming right up until the end of the official count. Overall, we had a great day of hawkwatching on the hill!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 302&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5.92&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 51.01&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 11&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 99&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 28&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 40&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 12&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 93&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 14&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 18&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190917" rel="alternate" title="Tuesday, September 17, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190917" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Veronica Pedraza &amp; Emma Regnier</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190916</id><published>2019-09-16T16:55:28.978-0700</published><updated>2019-09-16T16:55:28.978-0700</updated><title>Monday, September 16, 2019</title><content type="html">With a decent amount of fog covering the Marin Headlands this morning, we prepared to start watching for hawks near the roundabout on Conzelman Road. Once we reached the base of Hawk Hill, we realized that the sky was clearing overhead, so we made our way to the top to begin our official raptor count. The day was windy with mostly clear skies and plenty of Accipiters to test our ID skills. Fog rolled in a little after noon and completely engulfed the hill by 1:30 pm, which caused us to suspend our count. Feeling defeated by the seemingly never-ending fog, we began preparing to pack up for the day. Just as we were debriefing on the day's hawkwatch, we noticed a small break in the fog that expanded over the course of a few minutes and allowed us to see Rodeo Lagoon in the west and Slacker Hill in the north. With hopeful hearts, we decided to start our count again for the remaining hours of the afternoon. Our perseverance was rewarded with a late-afternoon flurry of raptors, including two Peregrine Falcons! We were glad to finish strong, despite the brief fog intermission.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 241&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 60.25&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 112&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 14&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 16&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 86&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 10&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190916" rel="alternate" title="Monday, September 16, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190916" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Maggie Brown &amp; Emma Regnier</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190915</id><published>2019-09-15T17:02:11.289-0700</published><updated>2019-09-15T17:02:11.289-0700</updated><title>Sunday, September 15, 2019</title><content type="html">Today started off extremely foggy with limited visibility. The hawk watchers remained patient and the fog lifted at 1pm leaving nothing but clear and sunny skies. The Sunday I team was greeted with 215 passing raptors which included two dark morph Broad-winged Hawks! We also had another successful raptor release this weekend at Hawk Hill. An enthusiastic crowd was delighted by the release of a male Cooper's Hawk. It was a great way to end the weekend and we're hopeful this upcoming week will be clearer. &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 215&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 2.5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 86&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 9&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 61&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 41&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 22&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 71&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 11&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190915" rel="alternate" title="Sunday, September 15, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190915" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Taylor Barnes</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190914</id><published>2019-09-14T16:02:30.767-0700</published><updated>2019-09-14T16:02:30.767-0700</updated><title>Saturday, September 14, 2019</title><content type="html">With the sunshine over the past few days initially giving Saturday I high hopes, the weather ultimately changed, causing the team to have a short day out on Hawk Hill. Low fog in the morning hung over Fort Cronkhite, and the team went hiking around Rodeo Lagoon. A couple of Fox Sparrows delighted us with a close viewing as they jumped around in the bushes near the trail. The River Otters were out today as well, playing in the lagoon and splashing around. Around noon the team headed up to the hill as the clouds lifted, giving visibility to each of the quadrants. The fog stayed away long enough to give us the first docent-lead raptor release of the season with a female Cooper's Hawk! She flew off into the fog as it enveloped Hawk Hill once again, cutting the day short. Hopefully the sun shines bright for tomorrow's team!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 120&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 1.67&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 71.86&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 51&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 12&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 47&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 5&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190914" rel="alternate" title="Saturday, September 14, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190914" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Paula Eberle</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190913</id><published>2019-09-13T13:15:23.458-0700</published><updated>2019-09-13T13:15:23.458-0700</updated><title>Friday, September 13, 2019</title><content type="html">It was a scorcher up on Hawk Hill today. By the time we arrived on the hill at about 9:30 AM, temperatures at the hill's summit had climbed past 85 degrees and there was little wind to speak of. By noon, we were experiencing temperatures in excess of 90 degrees, so the Friday I team made a unanimous decision to call off our count early to avoid dehydration and heat stroke. The birds were feeling the heat too - many of our sightings were kettles of birds rising on thermals high above the hill. However, despite our relatively brief count, we still saw more than 120 birds of 6 different species, including a distant Osprey in the middle of the morning and an-eleventh hour Merlin that circled over Mt. Tamalpais as we were getting ready to call it a day. Here's to hoping that temperatures chill out soon so that we can be comfortable during our peak season hawk watches! Until then, stay cool and drink lots of water! &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 122&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 2.67&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 45.69&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 58&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 46&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190913" rel="alternate" title="Friday, September 13, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190913" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jeremy Pallant and Taylor Barnes</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190912</id><published>2019-09-12T16:51:08.873-0700</published><updated>2019-09-12T16:51:08.873-0700</updated><title>Thursday, September 12, 2019</title><content type="html">Clear skies gave the hawkwatchers of Thursday I a 360-degree view around Hawk Hill as far out as the Farallons. The temperature steadily climbed as the day went on, and the raptors followed the warm updrafts high into the sky, making the "fifth" quadrant overhead busy all day. The steady flight of Accipiters continued from yesterday, as we spotted more Sharp-shinned Hawks. A light breeze from the South brought a young Broad-winged Hawk into view in front of the Golden Gate Bridge. A high-flying Northern Harrier snuck in among a small kettle of Red-tailed Hawks overhead. Not used to seeing Northern Harriers from so far below, the team relied on the bird's long tail, pointed wings, and deep wingbeats to identify it. Raptors were not the only exciting part of the day, as a Townsend's Solitaire breezed over Hawk Hill. Tomorrow's forecast calls for even warmer temperatures, so if you are planning on joining us on the hill, pack extra water and dress for success!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 360&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 60&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 9&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 137&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 22&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 36&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 140&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 12&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190912" rel="alternate" title="Thursday, September 12, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190912" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Paula Eberle &amp; Emma Regnier</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190911</id><published>2019-09-11T16:45:45.538-0700</published><updated>2019-09-11T16:45:45.538-0700</updated><title>Wednesday, September 11, 2019</title><content type="html">The morning was slow for raptor sightings, but the insects and other bird species were already on the move around Hawk Hill. We were thrilled to see two Monarch Butterflies within our first hour on the hill. We also spotted several Blue-gray Gnatcatchers, White-throated Swifts, Vaux's Swifts, a Great Egret, and a Red-breasted Nuthatch! Suddenly, a male American Kestrel appeared out of the fog in South Quadrant and soared overhead, showing off the bright white "string of pearls" on the trailing edge of his wings. Throughout the day, several distant mixed-species kettles tested our raptor ID knowledge and gave us the opportunity to use teamwork to successfully identify and pass the birds from quadrant to quadrant. A White-tailed Kite dropped in for a visit around lunchtime, and we watched it soar above the Golden Gate Bridge and disappear into the San Francisco skyline. With a westerly wind came an abundance of accipiters, which rekindled the age-old "Sharpie or Coop?" dilemma, but also provided an excellent learning experience for everyone on the hill. We had a busy and exciting day today and are looking forward to even more raptors as the migration picks up in the coming weeks!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 260&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 43.33&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 10&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 64&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 35&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 41&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 93&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 7&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190911" rel="alternate" title="Wednesday, September 11, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190911" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Maggie Brown &amp; Emma Regnier</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190910</id><published>2019-09-10T16:30:37.661-0700</published><updated>2019-09-10T16:30:37.661-0700</updated><title>Tuesday, September 10, 2019</title><content type="html">Today was sunny and warm, with clear views as far as the Geysers in the North and Mt. Diablo in the East. Shortly after unpacking at the hill, we were greeted by fleeting glimpses of a bobcat that disappeared into the chaparral around Fish Rock. As the morning went on, the birds took to the skies, and we saw Osprey, a few juvenile Sharp-shinned Hawks, Cooper's Hawks, and even a gliding adult Peregrine Falcon. A large group of energetic young students from Petaluma stopped at the Wingspans for a lesson on raptor biology and identification, and they had excellent questions about the current conservation status of raptor species, especially Peregrine Falcons. The students marveled at an extremely cooperative young Cooper's Hawk as it made several low passes just overhead. Towards the tail end of the count, we watched as two juvenile Red-tailed Hawks, one of which was a dark morph, dive-bombed each other, grappling talons over Kremin's Crag. Eventually the hawks settled their differences and flew across the Golden Gate together.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 201&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 33.5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 7&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 78&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 20&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 86&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 2&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190910" rel="alternate" title="Tuesday, September 10, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190910" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Emma Regnier and Jeremy Pallant</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190909</id><published>2019-09-09T16:36:35.511-0700</published><updated>2019-09-09T16:36:35.511-0700</updated><title>Monday, September 09, 2019</title><content type="html">The Monday I team enjoyed an awesome day of hawkwatching with clear skies, plenty of sunshine, and some exciting raptor activity! When we first arrived at Hawk Hill this morning, we started counting the usual Red-tailed Hawks and Turkey Vultures that circle the hill. As the wind picked up speed and the number of birds in the sky increased, we started seeing a greater variety of raptor species. In the afternoon, the team got a great view of a juvenile Broad-winged Hawk that flew directly over the hill. The most exciting moment of the day occurred when the team noticed a small raptor with pointed wings zooming around in the North Quadrant. We quickly gathered together and determined that it was a Merlin! About an hour later, we were lucky enough to get a glimpse of another Merlin flying high towards the Golden Gate Bridge. Since these were the first Merlin sightings of the season, we were super excited to have a second look at the flight style and characteristics of these quick, little falcons.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 184&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 30.67&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 11&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 61&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 9&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 93&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 5&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190909" rel="alternate" title="Monday, September 09, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190909" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Maggie Brown &amp; Veronica Pedraza</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190908</id><published>2019-09-08T16:47:59.780-0700</published><updated>2019-09-08T16:47:59.780-0700</updated><title>Sunday, September 08, 2019</title><content type="html">Today was a clear and sunny day up at Hawk Hill! We had a full day of counting raptors as the fog finally decided to stay away. The sunny skies brought visitors to our first Sunday hawk talk and we were delighted when an Osprey flew over for a close viewing. This was Sunday II team's first day on the hill after being fogged out two weeks ago. They were happily rewarded with this season's second Ferruginous Hawk sighting! With the fog finally clearing, we encourage future hawk watch teams to prepare for warmer weather, pack extra sunscreen, and get ready for an exciting peak!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 317&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 52.83&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 9&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 130&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 19&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 139&lt;br/&gt;
Ferruginous Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 10&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190908" rel="alternate" title="Sunday, September 08, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190908" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Taylor Barnes</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190907</id><published>2019-09-07T13:41:14.179-0700</published><updated>2019-09-07T13:41:14.179-0700</updated><title>Saturday, September 07, 2019</title><content type="html">For the second week in a row, the fog was not forgiving to the Saturday II team. In the morning, we spent about an hour birding on Rodeo Beach. Although there weren't many bird species of note, we were lucky enough to see two porpoises playing in the waves. In the late morning, the fog had risen and it looked like there was potential for the summit of Hawk Hill to clear, but we had no such luck. As we got to the top of the hill around lunch time, the fog rolled in again, obscuring visibility and preventing us from doing a count. However, despite the suboptimal hawkwatching conditions, we still had several dedicated visitors who stuck around to watch the season's first Hawk Talk. As the talk was finishing, they were rewarded with a great view of two juvenile Red-tailed Hawks and a juvenile Cooper's Hawk, who came to the hill undeterred by the fog. Here's to hoping for better weather when peak rolls around in a couple weeks! &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190907" rel="alternate" title="Saturday, September 07, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190907" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jeremy Pallant and Paula Eberle</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190906</id><published>2019-09-06T14:04:06.724-0700</published><updated>2019-09-06T14:04:06.724-0700</updated><title>Friday, September 06, 2019</title><content type="html">The hawk watchers did not make it up to the hill today to do an official count as the fog was too thick. That didn't stop the Friday II team from getting outside and taking a walk around Rodeo Lagoon. While out, the team spotted an Osprey flying over with its wings in the classic "M" shape. We're looking forward to clearer skies in our upcoming September hawk watching days. &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190906" rel="alternate" title="Friday, September 06, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190906" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Taylor Barnes</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190905</id><published>2019-09-05T15:30:47.583-0700</published><updated>2019-09-05T15:30:47.583-0700</updated><title>Thursday, September 05, 2019</title><content type="html">Despite some initial fog high above the hill, the Thursday II team started the day with good visibility in the lower areas of each quadrant. By the late morning, our visibility improved further, and we had clear skies above with a decent amount of raptor activity. We got a nice long look at an adult Red-shouldered Hawk that circled above Kirby Cove, and later observed an Osprey flying near the Golden Gate Bridge. By mid-afternoon the fog crept back in, but just as we were preparing to end our count, a flurry of four American Kestrels emerged from the fog and sped directly over Hawk Hill. It was an exciting way to end the day, and our team looks forward to what the rest of the season has in store!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 220&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 4.25&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 51.76&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 8&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 68&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 131&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 4&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190905" rel="alternate" title="Thursday, September 05, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190905" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Maggie Brown &amp; Jeremy Pallant</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190904</id><published>2019-09-04T13:58:26.779-0700</published><updated>2019-09-04T13:58:26.779-0700</updated><title>Wednesday, September 04, 2019</title><content type="html">Fog, fog, and more fog. Even though we're now into September, the August fog is still lingering. Unfortunately, the fog was too thick to make it up to the hill today, but the Wednesday II team still  made the best of the inopportune weather. We spent the morning birding around Rodeo Lagoon as we typically do on foggy days, and though visibility in the surrounding hills was poor, we still observed some neat birds. Our morning started off with a sighting of a juvenile Cooper's Hawk, which flew over Fort Cronkhite en route to Rodeo Beach, where it landed in the brush. Thanks to an excellent photo from a volunteer, we were able to see that the bird had a metal leg band, meaning it was probably banded recently at one of our blinds! We were also lucky enough to see a pair of Osprey surveying the water, although neither elected to dive into the lagoon in search of a late-morning snack. On our way back from the lagoon, we observed a small kettle of Red-tailed Hawks rising into the fog before disappearing from view. We also observed several interesting non-raptors, including recently fledged Common Yellowthroats, an Orange-Crowned Warbler, and a pair of vocalizing Virginia Rails which we were unable to find skulking in the marsh grass. Though we never made it up to the hill, we still had a great morning of birding and we're hoping for better luck next time around! Cheers from the Wednesday II team!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190904" rel="alternate" title="Wednesday, September 04, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190904" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Veronica Pedraza; Emma Regnier; and Jeremy Pallant</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190903</id><published>2019-09-03T14:31:09.132-0700</published><updated>2019-09-03T14:31:09.132-0700</updated><title>Tuesday, September 03, 2019</title><content type="html">Tuesday II's Fogwatch team spent the morning birding around Rodeo Lagoon waiting for the fog in the valley to lift. Armed with two scopes, we spotted a Killdeer and a Great Blue Heron foraging on the bank. Suddenly, a flash of brown wings drew our attention to a newcomer flying low over the lagoon. Luckily for us, this mystery bird perched on the fence line between the lagoon and the beach, and through the scope we saw its long, banded tail with a white terminal band and brown body - a juvenile Cooper's Hawk! We watched the young hawk until it took off into the brush and disappeared. Further along the lagoon, a flock of Red-necked Phalaropes was mingling with a trio of Pied-billed Grebes. Some notable mammalian sightings today included a Coyote crossing Bunker Road and two River Otters swimming among the reeds around the perimeter of the lagoon. Blues skies beckoned us up to Hawk Hill, but upon arriving, we discovered that the South and West Quadrants were still completely socked in with fog, so we did not start an official count. We've got our fingers crossed for better weather next time!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190903" rel="alternate" title="Tuesday, September 03, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190903" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Emma Regnier &amp; Veronica Pedraza</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190902</id><published>2019-09-02T14:15:33.702-0700</published><updated>2019-09-02T14:15:33.702-0700</updated><title>Monday, September 02, 2019</title><content type="html">The day started with clear skies and lots of enthusiasm from the Monday II team! We got up to the hill and were soon greeted by a juvenile Northern Harrier along with a few Turkey Vultures. Shortly after, we were also excited to see a dark morph juvenile Red-tailed Hawk glide past Hawk Hill and join a kettle of Red-tailed Hawks soaring above Kirby Cove. In the late morning, we got a nice look at the bright white crescents on the wings of a juvenile Red-shouldered Hawk. With it being Labor Day weekend, we enjoyed the company of many interested park visitors on the hill today. We were able to help them spot raptors around us and answer their thoughtful questions. Unfortunately, the fog began quickly rolling in to surround the hill around noon and we lost almost all visibility in each quadrant. Right before packing up for the day, we had an American Kestrel break through the fog and fly directly overhead. Although we ended our raptor count early due to the thick and persistent fog, everyone was still grateful for the opportunity to hawkwatch today.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 90&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 3.42&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 26.32&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 7&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 40&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 36&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 3&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190902" rel="alternate" title="Monday, September 02, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190902" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Maggie Brown &amp; Emma Regnier</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190901</id><published>2019-09-01T16:09:29.672-0700</published><updated>2019-09-01T16:09:29.672-0700</updated><title>Sunday, September 01, 2019</title><content type="html">The morning started off foggy but cleared enough for the team to start just before 11am. Hawk Hill was high enough to get us above the fog.  We got a few good hours of counting in before the fog rolled back over and surrounded us in the late afternoon. While visibility limited our bird sightings in the distance, some individuals decided to give us a closer look. These included a Cooper's Hawk, three American Kestrels, and many Red-tailed Hawks. An Osprey was also seen crossing the bridge towards the peninsula. &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 160&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 3.75&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 42.67&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 7&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 39&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 17&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 85&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 10&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190901" rel="alternate" title="Sunday, September 01, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190901" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Veronica Pedraza</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190831</id><published>2019-08-31T16:28:50.981-0700</published><updated>2019-08-31T16:28:50.981-0700</updated><title>Saturday, August 31, 2019</title><content type="html">While some fog in the morning started the Saturday 1 team with a walk around the lagoon, the sun won out and the team made it up to Hawk Hill for a full day of counting. The day turned out to be full of Red-tailed Hawks and Turkey Vultures, as well as the occasional Cooper's Hawk zooming by. By mid afternoon the team was lucky to see some more rare species, with three American Kestrels flying in for a close view right over the top of the quadrants. A Broad-winged Hawk also made a visit quickly after the Kestrels; a full two weeks before our first expected sighting! The day was closed out nicely with two Humpback Whales cruising through the bay, giving the team plenty of chances to spot them spouting. Here's to a successful start to the long weekend!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 231&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 4.75&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 48.63&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 7&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 79&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 13&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 112&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 12&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 21&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190831" rel="alternate" title="Saturday, August 31, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190831" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Paula Eberle</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190830</id><published>2019-08-30T14:07:39.591-0700</published><updated>2019-08-30T14:07:39.591-0700</updated><title>Friday, August 30, 2019</title><content type="html">It was another foggy day in the Marin Headlands. The Friday I team was hopeful for clear skies and waited patiently for the fog to move away but no such luck occurred. The team did make their way around Rodeo Lagoon where a juvenile Peregrine Falcon whizzed by at an incredible speed. The team also visited the Conzelman road roundabout where Turkey Vultures, Red-tailed Hawks, and a Cooper's Hawk all made an appearance. The hawk watchers got a glimpse of the banders at poak blind catch a juvenile Red-tailed Hawk which was an exciting sight. As Fog-ust comes to a close in just one day, we're hopeful that September will bring us clearer skies with many more bird sightings!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190830" rel="alternate" title="Friday, August 30, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190830" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Taylor Barnes</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190829</id><published>2019-08-29T16:29:20.765-0700</published><updated>2019-08-29T16:29:20.765-0700</updated><title>Thursday, August 29, 2019</title><content type="html">The sun was shining on Thursday I's team today! Partly cloudy skies and a breeze from the West made for good hawkwatching today on Hawk Hill. We started off the morning right with a flashy young Northern Harrier that worked its way around the hill, giving everyone a good look at its pumpkin-colored collar and flanks. A juvenile Cooper's Hawk also put on a show, circling in close above the hawkwatchers. Today was a great day for Red-tailed Hawks with 109 sightings, including #LH31L, who sports a lavender color band on its left leg. LH31L even joined us for lunch, as it was seen eating a snake in a dead snag on Hawk Hill! We're very grateful for this warm and sunny break from the fog, and we wish tomorrow's team the same luck!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 224&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5.5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 40.73&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 97&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 109&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 8&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190829" rel="alternate" title="Thursday, August 29, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190829" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Emma Regnier and Paula Eberle</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190828</id><published>2019-08-28T13:29:49.574-0700</published><updated>2019-08-28T13:29:49.574-0700</updated><title>Wednesday, August 28, 2019</title><content type="html">Today was another day of thick fog in the Marin Headlands which prevented the Wednesday I team from conducting an official raptor count on Hawk Hill. Instead, we spent some extra time inside working on our raptor ID skills so that we feel more prepared for peak migration to start in just a few weeks. We then went for a walk around Rodeo Lagoon, and saw Red-necked Phalaropes, Marbled Godwits, Great Egrets, a Great Blue Heron, a Pied-billed Grebe, and a Common Yellowthroat. We were also pleased to see several Turkey Vultures circling in and out of the foggy sky above us. Despite the low visibility, we still had a great day of birding and look forward to our next day on the hill!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190828" rel="alternate" title="Wednesday, August 28, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190828" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Maggie Brown</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190827</id><published>2019-08-27T13:05:34.395-0700</published><updated>2019-08-27T13:05:34.395-0700</updated><title>Tuesday, August 27, 2019</title><content type="html">This is Fog Blog Episode IV: A New Hope. Glimpses of blue sky above Rodeo Lagoon gave us hope for the hawkwatch today, but sadly, the fog atop Hawk Hill was here to stay. We turned our binoculars to the trees around the Headlands Center for the Arts and the lagoon, spotting several Red-necked Phalaropes, Pied-billed Grebes, and one Ruddy Duck. A couple of Yellow Warblers flitted by, reminding us that, despite the dismal weather conditions, there are still migrants on the move. Our first raptor of the day was a young Cooper's Hawk seen atop a telephone pole near the GGRO Office. We enjoyed a lovely team picnic outside of the Marin Headlands Visitor Center, where we spotted a few Red-tailed Hawks and Turkey Vultures soaring low through the valley. We can't wait to get back up on Hawk Hill next time!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190827" rel="alternate" title="Tuesday, August 27, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190827" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Emma Regnier</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190826</id><published>2019-08-26T16:16:04.154-0700</published><updated>2019-08-26T16:16:04.154-0700</updated><title>Monday, August 26, 2019</title><content type="html">Today was our first day back on the hill after three days of fog! The day started sunny and warm with clear skies above and some low fog in the distance. As the day continued, the wind picked up and the fog slowly started to creep up on us. However, we still managed to get in a full day of hawkwatching and got to see a Peregrine Falcon perched on the North Tower of the Golden Gate Bridge. During moments of slow raptor activity throughout the day, the Monday I team enjoyed watching other wildlife around Hawk Hill, including Blue-gray Gnatcatchers and Anise Swallowtail butterflies. It was a great way to start the second cycle of the season!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 103&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5.58&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 18.46&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 45&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 50&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190826" rel="alternate" title="Monday, August 26, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190826" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Veronica Pedraza</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190825</id><published>2019-08-25T13:31:09.119-0700</published><updated>2019-08-25T13:31:09.119-0700</updated><title>Sunday, August 25, 2019</title><content type="html">Welcome to fog blog day 3! Unfortunately, dense fog prevented the Sunday II team from hawk watching today. However, the team had a great morning of introductions and getting to know each other. Bird watching around Rodeo Lagoon did take place and many interesting species were seen including more Red-necked Phalaropes, Great Blue Herons, Turkey Vultures, and Red-tailed Hawks. The Sunday II team is hopeful for sunny and clear skies and remains positive for their future hawk watching days!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190825" rel="alternate" title="Sunday, August 25, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190825" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Taylor Barnes</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190824</id><published>2019-08-24T14:11:33.360-0700</published><updated>2019-08-24T14:11:33.360-0700</updated><title>Saturday, August 24, 2019</title><content type="html">Time for another Fog Blog! The Saturday II team got fogged out today but spent the day around the Headlands birding and getting to know each other. The Red-necked Phalaropes were still out in the eastern side of Rodeo Lagoon and were joined by some Pied-billed Grebes. While at the lagoon, the team got a wonderful surprise of hearing the calls of a Sora that was hiding deep in the reeds! Despite never making it out to Hawk Hill, the day was not devoid of raptors, with a close flyby from a beautiful rufous colored Red-Tailed Hawk and a sighting of a female American Kestrel. Here's hoping for some clear days to come!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190824" rel="alternate" title="Saturday, August 24, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190824" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Paula Eberle</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190823</id><published>2019-08-23T14:01:45.165-0700</published><updated>2019-08-23T14:01:45.165-0700</updated><title>Friday, August 23, 2019</title><content type="html">The fog was heavy today but that didn't stop the Friday II team from having a great morning of bird-watching. Although the hawk watchers did not make it up to the hill for the count, plenty of raptors were seen flying over Rodeo Lagoon. This included some Turkey vultures and Red-tailed hawks that flew just within eyesight below the fog. The team also spotted some Red-necked phalaropes, Baird's sandpipers, and even river otters! The fog could not keep down this team's positive attitude for a successful hawk watching season. &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190823" rel="alternate" title="Friday, August 23, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190823" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Taylor Barnes</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190822</id><published>2019-08-22T16:08:11.318-0700</published><updated>2019-08-22T16:08:11.318-0700</updated><title>Thursday, August 22, 2019</title><content type="html">It was a strange day on Hawk Hill, at least with respect to the weather. In the morning, fog was swirling all around the base of the hill, obscuring our sight lines in three of the four quadrants. However, visibility above the fog line was nearly perfect, with unobscured views of Mt. Diablo, Mt. Tamalpais, and the Sutro Tower. Because of the low-hanging fog, we didn't officially begin our count until just before noon, when the fog cleared enough to provide clear raptor viewing in the North and East quadrants. In the early afternoon, we got great views of a juvenile Northern Harrier, which circled Hawk Hill for several minutes before heading south across the Golden Gate. Several small kettles of Red-tailed Hawks were also seen high above the Golden Gate Bridge. In the middle of our afternoon hawkwatching, fog began to creep up the hill and our counting was again confined to small portions of the North and East quadrants. But with about an hour left before we called it quits for the afternoon, the skies cleared in all but the South quadrant, and we picked up several new species for the day, including an American Kestrel, a Sharp-Shinned Hawk, and a White-Tailed Kite. Considering the constraints placed upon us by the weather, our final tallies of 76 raptors and 8 species were very solid for a relatively short day of hawkwatching. &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 76&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 3.42&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 22.22&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 8&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 12&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 53&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190822" rel="alternate" title="Thursday, August 22, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190822" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jeremy Pallant</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190821</id><published>2019-08-21T16:33:12.019-0700</published><updated>2019-08-21T16:33:12.019-0700</updated><title>Wednesday, August 21, 2019</title><content type="html">It was another beautiful day on Hawk Hill! Although a bit warm, there was a light breeze and clear skies as far as the eye could see. The day of hawkwatching had ebbs and flows, with some stretches lacking birds and others showing lots of activity. In the late morning, we were fortunate enough to see a juvenile Osprey, a juvenile Red-shouldered Hawk sporting ivory crescents in its wings, and a few Northern Harriers, including a juvenile eating a vole on the wing. In the early afternoon, there was a lull characterized by low windspeeds and reduced bird movement. But in the last couple hours of the day, activity picked up significantly, with several excellent sightings just before day's end. These sightings included one more juvenile Red-shouldered Hawk, another Osprey, a female American Kestrel, a dark-morph Red-tailed Hawk, and a juvenile  Sharp-shinned Hawk being chased off the hill by a hummingbird. Our finally tally for the day was 8 total species, a very solid species diversity considering we're still in the middle of August. We can't wait to be out on the hill again in a couple weeks! Until then, all the best from the Wednesday II team! &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 128&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 25.6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 8&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 66&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 47&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 3&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190821" rel="alternate" title="Wednesday, August 21, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190821" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Veronica Pedraza</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190820</id><published>2019-08-20T15:17:24.967-0700</published><updated>2019-08-20T15:17:24.967-0700</updated><title>Tuesday, August 20, 2019</title><content type="html">The day started out promising, with strong winds from the North blowing in handfuls of young Red-tailed Hawks and one Northern Harrier over the ridgelines. Turkey Vulture #368 made another guest appearance and circled the Hawkwatchers several times before disappearing into the approaching fog. The fog began to creep up around the hill around 1 pm, but the East and South Quadrants remained clear, so we continued our raptor count. Despite our stubbornness, the fog completely closed in around us within the hour, and visibility dropped dramatically. Because none of the quadrants could reliably see nor count any raptors, the call to return to the GGRO office was made shortly thereafter, so we packed up our scopes and headed down the hill for the day. &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 51&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 2.83&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 18.02&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 28&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 19&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 2&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190820" rel="alternate" title="Tuesday, August 20, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190820" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Emma Regnier</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190819</id><published>2019-08-19T14:02:32.659-0700</published><updated>2019-08-19T14:02:32.659-0700</updated><title>Monday, August 19, 2019</title><content type="html">Fog-ust is here in full force, and unfortunately the thick fog and low visibility on Hawk Hill prevented our raptor count today. We spent some extra time in the office this morning working on our raptor ID skills and discussing tricky field marks with the hope that the fog would lift in the meantime. We trekked up to Hawk Hill for a short visit to practice identifying the nearby landmarks and get familiar with the rhythm of our team. Unable to see even the resident ravens through the fog, we descended the hill and hiked along the Coastal Trail to look for birds and other wildlife. Luckily, the fog didn't put a damper on the group's energy, and we can't wait to return and put our landmark and ID skills to the test!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190819" rel="alternate" title="Monday, August 19, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190819" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Emma Regnier</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190818</id><published>2019-08-18T17:44:17.404-0700</published><updated>2019-08-18T17:44:17.404-0700</updated><title>Sunday, August 18, 2019</title><content type="html">Today was a beautiful day up at the hill! The morning started off foggy but cleared up and left us with blue skies and clear sights. Our hawk watchers were filled with excitement and enthusiasm when an adult Peregrine Falcon zipped by 3 times! We saw a total of 95 birds today which is a great way to end the first week of the 2019 season. &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 95&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 4.25&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 22.35&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 44&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 41&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 2&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190818" rel="alternate" title="Sunday, August 18, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190818" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Taylor Barnes</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190817</id><published>2019-08-17T15:11:11.319-0700</published><updated>2019-08-17T15:11:11.319-0700</updated><title>Saturday, August 17, 2019</title><content type="html">Unfortunately, fog prevented the Saturday I team from counting raptors today. During the morning, we did a brief survey of the birds in Rodeo Lagoon. The highlights of our quick trip to the lagoon include  Snowy and Great Egrets, a Pied-Billed Grebe, a Great Blue Heron, a Willet, and a Caspian Tern. We did make the trek up to the top of Hawk Hill in the late morning, but by mid-afternoon the fog hadn't let up. There were a few Red-Tailed Hawks circling the hill that could be seen through the fog, but visibility was not good enough to conduct an official raptor survey. While we wish the weather could have been better today, we're also happy to hear how much success the teams earlier this week had! Hopefully in a couple weeks, we'll have a better chance to count some hawks! Until next time, cheers from the Saturday I team! &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190817" rel="alternate" title="Saturday, August 17, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190817" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jeremy Pallant</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190816</id><published>2019-08-16T17:42:46.244-0700</published><updated>2019-08-16T17:42:46.244-0700</updated><title>Friday, August 16, 2019</title><content type="html">It was a windy day up on the hill today! With winds gusting up to 25 miles per hour, we were definitely holding onto our hats while hawk watching today! However, despite the wind, visibility was great and there was still a fair amount of raptor movement. We saw a total of 126 birds today, representing 5 different species. While the vast majority of our birds were the usual suspects (i.e. Red-Tailed Hawks, Turkey Vultures, Northern Harriers, and Cooper's Hawks), we were lucky enough to have the season's first sighting of a Bald Eagle, a young juvenile that passed over the hill heading North. We've already seen 12 species so far this season, which is quite a few for the first week, so we're optimistic about what we'll see in the coming weeks! All the best from the Friday I team!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 126&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5.33&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 23.64&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 38&lt;br/&gt;
Bald Eagle: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 82&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190816" rel="alternate" title="Friday, August 16, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190816" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jeremy Pallant</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190815</id><published>2019-08-15T16:37:20.359-0700</published><updated>2019-08-15T16:37:20.359-0700</updated><title>Thursday, August 15, 2019</title><content type="html">Another beautiful day out on Hawk Hill! The strong winds from the West blew in some interesting birds throughout the afternoon. Between a flurry of young Red-Tailed Hawks and a few elusive Cooper's Hawks, we spotted an Osprey cruising across the North Quadrant. One of Hawk Hill's celebrity tagged Turkey Vultures, number 368, breezed by the Hawkwatchers up close and personal. The distressed calls from a juvenile Red-Tailed Hawk hinted us to our first sighting this season of an adult Golden Eagle, circling over the Golden Gate Bridge. The whole team was able to get eyes on this large raptor and marvel at how it dwarfed the nearby Red-Tailed Hawks. Within the same hour, another enormous bird soared into view and flashed its white tail and primaries, indicative of yet another Golden Eagle, this time a juvenile. By the end of the day our Hawkwatch team had doubled in size, and every in between cardinal direction was covered. Thanks to everyone who came out today!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 131&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 26.2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 48&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 73&lt;br/&gt;
Golden Eagle: 2&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 2&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190815" rel="alternate" title="Thursday, August 15, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190815" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Paula Eberle</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190814</id><published>2019-08-14T17:28:45.690-0700</published><updated>2019-08-14T17:28:45.690-0700</updated><title>Wednesday, August 14, 2019</title><content type="html">Today was a hot day on Hawk Hill! The birds must have thought so too since we had a pretty slow morning. Raptor activity picked up in the early afternoon as the ocean breeze swept in. Thanks to the clear skies all day long we were able to count raptors in all quadrants, especially the South and East. While we saw plenty of our usual guests around the hill, such as Turkey Vultures and Red-tailed Hawks, we also counted several Cooper's Hawks, a Sharp-shinned Hawk, and a juvenile Red-shouldered Hawk. We were all taken by surprise when a brilliant adult Ferruginous Hawk appeared in our East Quadrant and soared above the north end of the Golden Gate Bridge for over 30 minutes! It is unusual to see an adult Ferruginous Hawk this early in the season, so it was an exciting surprise for our third day of hawkwatching!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 88&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 17.6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 44&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 30&lt;br/&gt;
Ferruginous Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 5&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190814" rel="alternate" title="Wednesday, August 14, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190814" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Maggie Brown</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190813</id><published>2019-08-13T17:23:22.721-0700</published><updated>2019-08-13T17:23:22.721-0700</updated><title>Tuesday, August 13, 2019</title><content type="html">Another day of sunshine and mainly clear skies up on Hawk Hill! We started off the day right with two Osprey - the first of the season - spotted right as we began our count. A handful of Turkey Vultures and Red-tailed Hawks were spotted each hour, and one young Cooper's Hawk even treated us to a close flyover. We saw one juvenile Northern Harrier, one juvenile Red-shouldered Hawk, and two female American Kestrels (the first kestrels of the season!), but the real highlight of the afternoon was a White-tailed Kite! The migration is already off to a terrific start this year!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 105&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 21&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 8&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 64&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 2&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 26&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190813" rel="alternate" title="Tuesday, August 13, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190813" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Emma Regnier</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190812</id><published>2019-08-12T17:02:58.763-0700</published><updated>2019-08-12T17:02:58.763-0700</updated><title>Monday, August 12, 2019</title><content type="html">Happy first day of the 2019 raptor migration season! We had a (mostly) clear day on Hawk Hill with plenty of sunshine, which allowed us to stay out and count birds all day. We started off the season counting many Turkey Vultures and Red-tailed Hawks, some Cooper's Hawks, a few Red-shouldered Hawks, and even a Northern Harrier! With the great enthusiasm of our volunteers and staff, we know that we have an awesome season ahead of us.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 99&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 19.8&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 64&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 9&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 20&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190812" rel="alternate" title="Monday, August 12, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190812" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Maggie Brown</name></author></entry>

</feed>