<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><?xml-stylesheet href='http://www.blogger.com/styles/atom.css' type='text/css'?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/">
    <id>hydromatic-ggro</id>
    <updated>2020-11-20T17:16:53.562-0800</updated>
    <title type="text">GGRO daily hawkwatch update</title>
    <link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml" rel="next" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml" rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#feed" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <author>
      <name>GGRO</name>
      <uri>http://www.ggro.org</uri>
      <email>ggro@parksconservancy.org</email>
    </author>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20201120</id><published>2020-11-20T17:16:53.562-0800</published><updated>2020-11-20T17:16:53.562-0800</updated><title>Friday, November 20, 2020</title><content type="html">Friday's Nov 20, 2020 hawk count team enjoyed a remark-able final day of the season, with brisk (50s-60 deg.) east winds in the AM, and a handful of accipiter sightings in the first few hours. We got some great Peregrine looks as well, adults and juvs, and a steady stream of Redtails and Harriers throughout the day, including three juv harriers in a column over Slacker Hill. The eagle sightings were all distant -- along the Wolf Ridge skyline - but gave the day a snap of excitement.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;One of the highlights of the day was estimating flock sizes on Band-tailed Pigeons, which were especially active in the morning hours.  Several flocks were over 200 individuals and appeared to span a quarter-mile across the sky. The flocks below eye-level catching the AM sun against the backdrop of rock, coyote brush, and various colors of grasslands, are like so many uniform pieces of lapis tracking across the landscape. Hard not to be impressed. Our day total was a conservative 2000+ BTPI sightings.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;GGRO's Covid-Safe Hawkwatch 2020 finished up the autumn migration season today. Final species tallies will be forthcoming, but our count hours are close to 160 for the last three months.  This is about one-third of a "normal" count season for us, and we are all grateful that we could pull together such a meaningful dataset for this strange year. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Our great thanks to our 15 scheduled covid-safe hawk counters: Christine Carino, James McDermott, Linda Schneider, Robert Blumberg, Sam Hontalas, Dan Foldes, Erica Harris, Mary Kenney, Jane Rudebusch, George Eade, Bob Power, Cheryl Lentini, Deborah Crooks, Michaela Figari, and Nancy Elliot.  We are also grateful to the many non-schueduled banders and hawkwatchers who took time to come up to the Hill and watch outside the gates. You all were critical contributors to a spirit of migration constancy and excellent data collection.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Also thanks to our NPS and Parks Conservancy supervisors and colleagues who guided us through a shifting 2020 planning process, advocating for us all along the way: Bill Merkle, Alison Forrestel, Natasha Arnold, Ronni Johnson, Sharon Farrell, Sue Gardner, Denise McKinney, and - especially - Janet Klein. The eagle's share of the planning, strategizing, coordination, and success of the 2020 GGRO hawk count was by Step Wilson.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Many more people contributed skill and expertise also and will be listed in a 2020 end of the season report.  But for now deep thanks to you all. On behalf of the GGRO staff - Step Wilson, Teresa Ely, Kelsie McInnis - good winter birds to you, and thanks for following the great work of the GGRO. - Allen Fish&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;PS - If you'd like to be on the mailing list for our free quarterly email newsletter, the GGRO Quarterly - please send an email to ggro@parksconservancy.org -&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 172&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 34.4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 11&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 57&lt;br/&gt;
Bald Eagle: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 24&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 11&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 12&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 52&lt;br/&gt;
Golden Eagle: 1&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 3&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20201120" rel="alternate" title="Friday, November 20, 2020" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20201120" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Allen Fish</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20201119</id><published>2020-11-19T20:06:31.198-0800</published><updated>2020-11-19T20:06:31.198-0800</updated><title>Thursday, November 19, 2020</title><content type="html">While it was foggy just about everywhere else in the Bay Area, Hawk Hill was miraculously clear when the Thursday team arrived, making for another full if slow day. Conditions seemed optimal for some large raptor sightings, but it was not to be. Instead we were dealt a sparse flight of tails, harriers and tvs, with a sprinkling of falcons and accipiters for good measure. A COVID-safe donut delivery sweetened a bittersweet last Thursday of the season. -DC of Thursday Team C&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 108&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 21.6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 7&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 44&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 13&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 16&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 26&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 3&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20201119" rel="alternate" title="Thursday, November 19, 2020" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20201119" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>T. E. Ely</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20201118</id><published>2020-11-18T15:47:17.220-0800</published><updated>2020-11-18T15:47:17.220-0800</updated><title>Wednesday, November 18, 2020</title><content type="html">Though stormy skies had passed, a thick blanket of fog persisted as the Tues/Wed team assembled for their final time together on the hill this season. In the company of the king and queen raven pair and their loyal song sparrow subjects, we celebrated a successful season counting amid challenges of pandemic-level proportion. Come fire and smoke, seemingly unending summer heat, high wind and rain, power outages and porta-potty woes, our dedicated team of six faithfully counted migrating raptors, passerines, and insects. We delighted in our collective spirit for the task at hand, and were able to seamlessly apply our prior training and knowledge to identifying and passing birds to each other like pros. Some of us met each other for the first time in September, yet it felt like we had been a family for years and years. We owe this to the hard work of the GGRO in diligently building the good foundation of a hawkwatcher from day 1, so that when we came together this fall we could get right down to business and all knew exactly how to make this machine run smoothly. Now that the 2020 season has closed, we will look back and the challenges and triumphs. At the bald eagles and ferrugs, and sharpies and coops, and harriers and kites, and peregrines and merlins, and so many more amazing sightings we had. We will still reach for the elusive pizza bird (rough-legged hawk) that we missed as it detoured through Duluth instead. We will enjoy the sweet treats we shared today and hold the memories of our time together close. As we drive about our lives, we will hang our heads out the window to wonder "is that red-shouldered hawk on the telephone pole or just a really big coop" In our dreams, our premonitions of seeing California condors at Hawk Hill will be fulfilled and we will be dunking them into the Dunkadoo by the hundreds. And, we will count down the days until next fall when we can hawkwatch again. &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20201118" rel="alternate" title="Wednesday, November 18, 2020" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20201118" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jane Rudebusch</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20201117</id><published>2020-11-17T16:49:19.347-0800</published><updated>2020-11-17T16:49:19.347-0800</updated><title>Tuesday, November 17, 2020</title><content type="html">Four our last week there was no count today due to the needed rains in the Bay Area.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20201117" rel="alternate" title="Tuesday, November 17, 2020" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20201117" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Step Wilson</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20201116</id><published>2020-11-16T19:27:35.615-0800</published><updated>2020-11-16T19:27:35.615-0800</updated><title>Monday, November 16, 2020</title><content type="html">We never reached the 300 and 500 plus raptors that had been seen a few years earlier in the first weeks of November by one team member, but 2 adult Bald Eagles traveling together first thing were inspiring. But we scanned diligently and counted nearly 1000 Band-tailed Pigeons and another 105 raptors. Our day was complete and fulfilling.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 107&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 21.4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 52&lt;br/&gt;
Bald Eagle: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 17&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 31&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20201116" rel="alternate" title="Monday, November 16, 2020" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20201116" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Step Wilson</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20201113</id><published>2020-11-13T13:53:18.027-0800</published><updated>2020-11-13T13:53:18.027-0800</updated><title>Friday, November 13, 2020</title><content type="html">OK, we know that there was a storm coming in today, but we were greedy. Our fellow counters tallied 8 Bald Eagles Mon-Thurs this week, so surely there's going to be a Bald around today. No. Nope. Not even.  We had to settle for 6 Peregrine sightings, long sweeping and corkscrewing flights in the pre-storm winds, tail-chasing Redtails, Ravens and Harriers. Peregrines never learned the word shy.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The winds never calmed today, gusting from 15 to 20 mph, and steady around 7-8 mph from the South.  Temps also pretty constant - low 50s most of the day with wind chill to the mid 40s. Our intrepid team lasted until a late day and late season Osprey flew across the western sky heading south, and reminding us that the wall of rain was about to hit. We closed up at 1 pm.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Since much of the bird action on Hawk Hill in November is White-crowned Sparrows below and Turkey Vultures above, Richard Wilbur's poem fragment seems apt today:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;"Still, citizen sparrow, this vulture which you call unnatural, let him but lumber again to air over the rotten office, let him bear the carrion ballast up, and at the tall tips of the sky lie cruising."&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 54&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 18.0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 7&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 14&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 27&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 6&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20201113" rel="alternate" title="Friday, November 13, 2020" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20201113" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Allen Fish</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20201112</id><published>2020-11-12T21:09:46.678-0800</published><updated>2020-11-12T21:09:46.678-0800</updated><title>Thursday, November 12, 2020</title><content type="html">If you aren't editing your accipiters you ain't hawkwatchin'. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;After a few days of low sharp-shinned hawks numbers, we were excited to count a few every hour throughout the day. We had a few moments of "Is this a Sharp-shinned or a Cooper's hawk" and they usually ended up being sharpies, but we did see a couple coops. We were very certain about the three different bald eagles that came pretty close to the hill.  Lots of northern harriers were seen today too. We felt hints of a storm coming, but it was also warm during some hours and found ourselves putting on and taking off jackets as we rotated quadrants. We watched a male Kestrel catch a sparrow in a bush along the trail, and flew towards us basically showing off its prey. We also found that real time data checks are helpful. No pizza today. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Hill Song&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;E&lt;br/&gt;When the world has got you blue&lt;br/&gt;E.                                               E7&lt;br/&gt;When you're no longer sure what to do&lt;br/&gt;B7&lt;br/&gt;When you need a break from the hullabaloo &lt;br/&gt;E&lt;br/&gt;Look up, look up&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;A&lt;br/&gt;hurry get yourself up the hill&lt;br/&gt;E                        E7&lt;br/&gt;a place of feathers, talons and bills&lt;br/&gt;B7&lt;br/&gt;A place to watch and to be still&lt;br/&gt;E&lt;br/&gt;And look up&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;A&lt;br/&gt;When so many are home alone&lt;br/&gt;E                                       E7&lt;br/&gt;When there' s no cure to be found in the phone&lt;br/&gt;B7&lt;br/&gt;when you simply need a different tone&lt;br/&gt;E&lt;br/&gt;look up, look up&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;-DC&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 183&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 36.6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 10&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 64&lt;br/&gt;
Bald Eagle: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 13&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 20&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 67&lt;br/&gt;
Ferruginous Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 2&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20201112" rel="alternate" title="Thursday, November 12, 2020" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20201112" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>T. E. Ely</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20201111</id><published>2020-11-11T17:27:34.305-0800</published><updated>2020-11-11T17:27:34.305-0800</updated><title>Wednesday, November 11, 2020</title><content type="html">White throated swifts raining out of the sky like confetti, late-season sharpies zooming past, a front row seat to the peregrine show at 11:00. FIVE. BALD. EAGLES. Four seen during prime time--including an adult pair circling over Wolfback Ridge together--plus a fifth seen before the start of the count by early bird, eagle-eyed hawkwatcher, George. Dozens of porpoising harbor porpoise, a lone male kestrel, an adult male harrier and several juvs, a vortex of hundreds of swirling brown pelicans, and an afternoon flurry of red-tails of all flavors: adults and juvs, light, intermediate, and dark morphs. All framed in beautiful Autumn light with visibility for miles, it was not a bad way to close our penultimate week of the hawk count.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 147&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 29.4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 9&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 59&lt;br/&gt;
Bald Eagle: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 12&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 9&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 54&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 2&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20201111" rel="alternate" title="Wednesday, November 11, 2020" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20201111" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jane Rudebusch</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20201110</id><published>2020-11-10T17:34:39.342-0800</published><updated>2020-11-10T17:34:39.342-0800</updated><title>Tuesday, November 10, 2020</title><content type="html">Kites! Peregrines!  Adult Red-shoulder! Merlin #1! Merlin #2! Obfuscated red-shoulder! Harrier! Kestrels! Was that another Merlin?... Tuesday 2 team visitors! Carol! Pecan macaroons! More peregrines! Merlin #3! Whitewing a.k.a Kathy the harrier! Bagpipes again! So many dark morph red-tails! A marriage proposal! But no eagles today : (&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 191&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 38.2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 10&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 43&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 12&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 22&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 89&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 3&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20201110" rel="alternate" title="Tuesday, November 10, 2020" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20201110" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jane Rudebusch </name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20201109</id><published>2020-11-09T19:22:21.687-0800</published><updated>2020-11-09T19:22:21.687-0800</updated><title>Monday, November 09, 2020</title><content type="html">Beautifully clear cool day. Very distant sighting of Short-eared Owl past volcano and two hours later beyond step house. Wished it was closer and the distant Golden Eagle at Hill 88. Luckily the bald came close from the south even though it didn't stay long. Thanks Keith, George, and Carol at the wingspans.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 96&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 19.2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 9&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 33&lt;br/&gt;
Bald Eagle: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 40&lt;br/&gt;
Golden Eagle: 1&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20201109" rel="alternate" title="Monday, November 09, 2020" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20201109" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Step Wilson</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20201106</id><published>2020-11-06T17:11:22.007-0800</published><updated>2020-11-06T17:11:22.007-0800</updated><title>Friday, November 06, 2020</title><content type="html">Friday's count started at 10 am with a steady NW wind of 7 to 10 mph, gusting to 25, and never changed. Clouds built throughout the day, finally building up some cumulus streets in the afternoon that created spectacular cloud shadows and generally crystalline light.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;A quiet hawk day - we were lucky to get any accipiters at all.  The winds never relented and we are between low pressure systems.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Other highlights included:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(1) Watching two CHP motorcycle police ride down the Coastal Trail, and then a few dozen mins later, arrive at the top of Hawk Hill. They parked on the middle platform and greeted us covid-safely from the fenceline, and were delighted by the whole raptor migration thing.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(2) Observing three Ravens spend an hour in the high wind part of the day and the sky "stick-surf" where they: ride a stick through the air, moving it from feet to beak and back again; share one stick so that two Ravens ride side by side; drop the stick from high and try to catch it before it hits the ground; do somersaults with the stick rotating over the top of the bird.  This kept us going from 1 pm to 2 pm.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(3) Raptor-wise the most interesting part of the day was watching what shape changes are possible as a hawk is trying to not be blown off-course.  How streamlined can a Cooper's Hawk become to keep from getting blown to San Jose? One of ours seemed to be flying purely on alulas today.  (Alula = thumb feather.)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(4) Brown Pelicans everywhere today - in big flocks, 10 to 30 mostly inside the Golden Gate, some 1000s of feet in the air. Presumably moving around between storms, on the big big winds.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(4) A full rainbow landing its right footing on the North tower of the GG Bridge at 330 pm - a lovely bit of eye-candy for the long windy day.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 90&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 18&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 45&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 41&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20201106" rel="alternate" title="Friday, November 06, 2020" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20201106" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Allen Fish</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20201105</id><published>2020-11-05T17:32:11.801-0800</published><updated>2020-11-05T17:32:11.801-0800</updated><title>Thursday, November 05, 2020</title><content type="html">The Thursday team was greeted by an unseasonal, clear, warm day that began with a light breeze from the east and ended with winds from the west. A number of Northern Harriers moved through early in the day, and we were pleased to see the Merlins were acting like Merlin's again. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Despite the west wind picking up as the afternoon progressed, the raptors did not. Instead, we continued to count many Band-tailed Pigeons in the headlands, and a few Fox Sparrows, as well as the Ravens, which all kept our attention off the news.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;In lieu of aging birds, we aged ourselves, finding common ground in birds as well as the occasional song lyric -- ("movin on over," "penguins are so sensitive" and "making [its] way back to you [Bob]") and attempts at poetry:&lt;br/&gt;The tail comes on the north wind/red feathers flashing in the fall sun. (Blog by the amazing Thursday Team C)&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 163&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 32.6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 9&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 63&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 15&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 17&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 49&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 4&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20201105" rel="alternate" title="Thursday, November 05, 2020" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20201105" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>T. E. Ely</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20201104</id><published>2020-11-04T19:54:47.538-0800</published><updated>2020-11-04T19:54:47.538-0800</updated><title>Wednesday, November 04, 2020</title><content type="html">Feelings of trepidation from current events percolated over the hill today, but our spirits were lifted by clear views, great company, and some good bird sightings. Serenaded by a cacophony from bagpipes in the mid-morning and foghorns in the afternoon, we saw many sharpies, harriers, and kestrels. A juvenile peregrine and four merlins were a treat. One of these merlins was strikingly pale, belonging to the Prairie subspecies more commonly found in the interior western U.S. We also saw a juvenile ferruginous hawk lazily circling over the summit of Angel Island, before catching a direct line south over the city skyline. All fingers and toes are crossed that the incoming cold front arriving later this week brings in some exciting late-season tundra buteos, and other surprises from the north for all to enjoy.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 165&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 33&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 9&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 56&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 13&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 29&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 43&lt;br/&gt;
Ferruginous Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 6&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20201104" rel="alternate" title="Wednesday, November 04, 2020" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20201104" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jane Rudebusch</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20201103</id><published>2020-11-03T19:07:10.803-0800</published><updated>2020-11-03T19:07:10.803-0800</updated><title>Tuesday, November 03, 2020</title><content type="html">For the first time all season those extra layers toted in our packs came in handy, as afternoon winds shifted to the west and gusted up to 25 mph. A peregrine dueling a raven, close encounters with kestrels and merlins, and two appearances by a juvenile golden eagle were among many highlights. We also were treated by a leucistic red-tailed hawk in the a.m. showing off alternating white and brown primaries, secondaries, and tail feathers, like the keys on a piano. Today we celebrated the birthday of teammate Erica. A big happy birthday wish to you Erica from all of us on the hawk crew!!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 159&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 31.8&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 11&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 60&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 23&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 42&lt;br/&gt;
Golden Eagle: 2&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 9&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 8&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20201103" rel="alternate" title="Tuesday, November 03, 2020" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20201103" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jane Rudebusch</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20201102</id><published>2020-11-02T19:34:05.408-0800</published><updated>2020-11-02T19:34:05.408-0800</updated><title>Monday, November 02, 2020</title><content type="html">Warm day with early east wind led to low numbers of raptors during most of the day. Adult and juvenile Sharp-shinned Hawk continue to push through. Late day Bald Eagle heading north salvaged a slow afternoon.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 171&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 34.2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 11&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 56&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Bald Eagle: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 26&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 59&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 6&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20201102" rel="alternate" title="Monday, November 02, 2020" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20201102" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Step Wilson</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20201030</id><published>2020-10-30T16:26:17.342-0700</published><updated>2020-10-30T16:26:17.342-0700</updated><title>Friday, October 30, 2020</title><content type="html">Friday morning showed Hawk and Slacker hills to be islands of bird migration magnificence, sitting 300 feet above the ocean of fog on all sides.  The fog retreated during the day with a light SW wind which became a steady 10 mph breeze from the west after noon. Temps never got out of the mid 60s and jackets were required in the final hours of the day.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Raptorwise we had a consistent gentle stream of Redtails and Vultures, a few Sharpshins, fewer Cooper's Hawks, four "blink or you miss them" Merlins, and other assorted characters.  LOTS of BT Pigeons, some flocks of Purple Finches, and a handful of Variegated Meadowhawks - perhaps the last dragonflies of the season.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Remember that we often see a peak flight of interesting color morph Redtails and other buteos during November, so Hawk Hill migration-watching has another month to roll out its mysteries. Come watch! Your psyche deserves to see birds of prey migrate across the skies above the Golden Gate.  Does a human good.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 191&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 4.5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 42.4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 9&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 43&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 34&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 95&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 4&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20201030" rel="alternate" title="Friday, October 30, 2020" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20201030" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Allen Fish</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20201029</id><published>2020-10-29T16:30:53.714-0700</published><updated>2020-10-29T16:30:53.714-0700</updated><title>Thursday, October 29, 2020</title><content type="html">The day was warmer than expected and hazy with little to no wind. Even the Merlins were lethargic, soaring past without a wingbeat. The importance of landmarks was highlighted by the adult Ferruginous Hawk, moving past the Porta Potty at hawk camp as it flew from view. While it wasn't a big-number day, it was nonetheless a good one for Northern Harriers and Red-shouldered hawks.-Thursday Team C&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 247&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 49.4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 11&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 123&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 93&lt;br/&gt;
Ferruginous Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 4&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20201029" rel="alternate" title="Thursday, October 29, 2020" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20201029" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>T. E. Ely</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20201028</id><published>2020-10-28T18:50:47.565-0700</published><updated>2020-10-28T18:50:47.565-0700</updated><title>Wednesday, October 28, 2020</title><content type="html">Not much of a flight, but late afternoon high birds still coming in off the ocean. Very dark juvenile Peregrine Falcon at the end of the day that didn't cross.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 234&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 46.8&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 9&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 93&lt;br/&gt;
Bald Eagle: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 11&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 18&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 93&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 2&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20201028" rel="alternate" title="Wednesday, October 28, 2020" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20201028" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Step Wilson</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20201027</id><published>2020-10-27T19:21:59.315-0700</published><updated>2020-10-27T19:21:59.315-0700</updated><title>Tuesday, October 27, 2020</title><content type="html">Count canceled due to red flag warnings. &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20201027" rel="alternate" title="Tuesday, October 27, 2020" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20201027" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Step Wilson</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20201026</id><published>2020-10-27T10:27:53.184-0700</published><updated>2020-10-27T10:27:53.184-0700</updated><title>Monday, October 26, 2020</title><content type="html">Count canceled due to high winds and red flag warnings throughout the Bay Area.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20201026" rel="alternate" title="Monday, October 26, 2020" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20201026" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Kelsie McInnis</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20201023</id><published>2020-10-23T17:55:20.572-0700</published><updated>2020-10-23T17:55:20.572-0700</updated><title>Friday, October 23, 2020</title><content type="html">The Oct 23 count started with low fog surrounding Hawk Hill and a light westerly breeze. Temps stayed in the 60s-70s all day as the fog pulled back to off shore.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;A steady stream of Redtails and Turkey Vultures formed the backbone of the flight today, with a few Redshoulders and 2 late Broadwings among the buteos.  Some adults in with the accips, and two stunning Peregrine juvs -- one with deep bronzey dark background and muddy streaking throughout the underbody and underwings, and the other a pale-brown-backed bird with a very pale face and cap, presumed a tundrius.  Some great Merlin flybys today.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Maybe due to the cool weather or the actual turning of the seasons, not a dragonfly to be seen on Hawk Hill today, although several Vanessa butterflies were flapping around the hilltop. No swifts nor swallows, but some BT Pigeon flocks.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 260&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 52.0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 12&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 80&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 15&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 128&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 3&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20201023" rel="alternate" title="Friday, October 23, 2020" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20201023" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Allen Fish</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20201022</id><published>2020-10-22T15:01:49.060-0700</published><updated>2020-10-22T15:01:49.060-0700</updated><title>Thursday, October 22, 2020</title><content type="html">The ten o'clock hour was met by zero visibility in any direction. The team had a very constructive book and movie suggestion discussion while waiting for clearing. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Suggestions to offer: "My Octopus Teacher", "Kiss the Ground", the Attenborough "A Life on Our Planet" docs. Novels "The Overstory", "Where the Crawdads Sing","Celine", "A Boy and His Dog at the End of the World", anything by Louise Erdrich. Non fiction books: "Underland", "The Hidden Life of Trees", "Sand Talk". &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;By 1 pm despite some teasing moments, a steady west breeze kept the fog coming in steadily, preventing any count. We did have some nice time conversing with the resident ravens.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20201022" rel="alternate" title="Thursday, October 22, 2020" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20201022" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>T. E. Ely</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20201021</id><published>2020-10-21T18:57:49.611-0700</published><updated>2020-10-21T18:57:49.611-0700</updated><title>Wednesday, October 21, 2020</title><content type="html">Another warm day today, without much breeze to move the birds we had another low count of raptors and high count of pigeons. Looking forward to the next 4 weeks of counting. Thanks to all the non-activated volunteers for their continued engagement. Tom, Catherine, Mary, Jan and Tim&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 210&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 42&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 10&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 38&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 50&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 19&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 73&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 11&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20201021" rel="alternate" title="Wednesday, October 21, 2020" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20201021" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Step Wilson</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20201021</id><published>2020-10-21T17:05:51.506-0700</published><updated>2020-10-21T17:05:51.506-0700</updated><title>Wednesday, October 21, 2020</title><content type="html">Another warm day today, without much breeze to move the birds we had another low count of raptors and high count of pigeons. Looking forward to the next 4 weeks of counting. Thanks to all the non-activated volunteers for their continued engagement. Tom, Catherine, Mary, Jan and Tim&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 210&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 42&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 10&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 38&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 50&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 19&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 73&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 11&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20201021" rel="alternate" title="Wednesday, October 21, 2020" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20201021" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Step Wilson</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20201020</id><published>2020-10-20T18:00:29.096-0700</published><updated>2020-10-20T18:00:29.096-0700</updated><title>Tuesday, October 20, 2020</title><content type="html">Light East winds until 13:00 increasing and shifting to NW. RT's picked up but not much else. Distant view of Ferruginous Hawk. Nice push of adult Accipiters and big numbers of Band-tailed Pigeon. &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 245&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5.25&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 46.66&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 11&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 70&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 16&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 40&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 15&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 73&lt;br/&gt;
Ferruginous Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 12&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20201020" rel="alternate" title="Tuesday, October 20, 2020" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20201020" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Step Wilson </name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20201019</id><published>2020-10-19T15:50:24.943-0700</published><updated>2020-10-19T15:50:24.943-0700</updated><title>Monday, October 19, 2020</title><content type="html">We were greeted by massive fog bank on the Bay this morning, but clear blue skies at the top of the Hill. Within 30 minutes of starting, the fog overtook the Hill, causing us to suspend the count. By 11 am, the fog had sunken low again and we reconvened to continue tallying hawks. Glad we did! The flight was steady - many Redtails today. By late afternoon, the fog began to creep back up. We eventually lost most of west and north to the thick clouds of moisture but continued counting until our 3 pm stop time with decent visibility east and south. A Northern Harrier made a quick appearance 2 minutes before the count ended (our first/only NOHA of the day), bumping us up to 11 species - a fun sighting to end the count on!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 241&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 4.5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 53.6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 11&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 68&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 27&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 9&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 107&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 5&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20201019" rel="alternate" title="Monday, October 19, 2020" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20201019" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Kelsie McInnis </name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20201016</id><published>2020-10-16T14:53:34.921-0700</published><updated>2020-10-16T14:53:34.921-0700</updated><title>Friday, October 16, 2020</title><content type="html">Oct 16 started warm, but the BIG east wind picked up immediately this AM and provided cool fans for our count team today. Unfortunately the temp rose slightly throughout the day and by 130 pm reached 90-degrees, our threshold for stopping the count. So we did.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Starting to see more of a continuous train of juv Redtails as to be expected, and the adult accipiters are splitting the sky with the juveniles.  (Almost all juv accipiters in September at Golden Gate. Take a look in your Sibley guide to see the differences between these two plumages.) We saw the last - maybe - Broad-winged Hawk heading to Latin America somewhere for the winter.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Highlights were an AM juvenile Ferruginous Hawk, the big grasslands buteo once called the "Rusty-chapped Squirrel-Hawk" - except the juv's chaps (leg feathers) are white or gray.  This beauty got tail-chased to the North by an aggressive Raven.  And a bit later, while counting a column of Redtails, we noted that the top hawk was not in fact a hawk, but a pale-buffy, floppy-winged Short-eared Owl.  The owl flopped westward then disappeared as fast as it had shown up.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Other stuff? A steady stream of VG Swallows, also Band-tailed Pigeons, moving by.  A noticeable lack of visiting hawkwatchers, but later we realized they were staying cool in the tunnels below HAwk Hill.  Smart as an owl.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 202&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 3.75&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 53.9&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 10&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 68&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 15&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 20&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 86&lt;br/&gt;
Ferruginous Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 4&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20201016" rel="alternate" title="Friday, October 16, 2020" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20201016" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Allen Fish</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20201015</id><published>2020-10-15T16:01:26.714-0700</published><updated>2020-10-15T16:01:26.714-0700</updated><title>Thursday, October 15, 2020</title><content type="html">When we got up on the hill it was warm and windy. Adult sharp-shinned hawks finally made an appearance mid-morning and had an early Merlin fly of the bridge. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;A male kestrel gave us a show - eating a lizard in the air near east and north quadrants. There was a run of adult sharpies which continued throughout the day. There were also a lot of red shoulders today and we had a lot of good looks. There were a lot of juvenile turkey vultures flying through the Headlands. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;One humpback whale in the bay. Pipeline Swallow tails were abundant. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The Team remained focused like grim professionals. Adult red-tails and juvenile cooper's hawks define much of the afternoon. More adult sharp-shinned hawks, an osprey, and an harrier to round out the day. (This blog was written by the entire Thursday Team.)&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 417&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 83.4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 10&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 190&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 36&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 20&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 9&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 138&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 7&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20201015" rel="alternate" title="Thursday, October 15, 2020" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20201015" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>T. E. Ely</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20201014</id><published>2020-10-14T15:45:13.408-0700</published><updated>2020-10-14T15:45:13.408-0700</updated><title>Wednesday, October 14, 2020</title><content type="html">A Merlin greeted the Hawkwatchers with a slow pass across the top of the hill as we were setting up for the day. In the morning, there was a decent amount of activity from adult and juvenile sharpies and Cooper's hawks, red-tails, and northern harriers. We had several male kestrels and a few more merlins make an appearance. Highlights of mid-day were an adult ferruginous hawk that glided by the west quad and gave great looks of it's rusty red features. Soon after, a juvenile ferruginous hawk came by, a male harrier circled near Mt. Tam, and an adult bald eagle was spotted out in the north saddle. Unlike the BAEA from yesterday, this bird stayed far out in the north and did not give us close looks. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Shortly after noon, the heat was high and the wind was nonexistent, which no wind slowed the flight down to a near standstill. Only a squadron of turkey vultures passing around the headlands was there to entertain us. Mercifully, just before 2:00pm a strong breeze from the west picked up to revitalize both the hawks and the watchers. More sharp-shinned hawks came through, bringing the total above 60 for the day, and another merlin visited close by. We ended the day with a brief look at an adult peregrine falcon, and a very close view of an adult female harrier. Sadly, no broad-winged hawks were seen today, perhaps signaling a shift in the migration season.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 321&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 64.2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 11&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 100&lt;br/&gt;
Bald Eagle: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 16&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 60&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 30&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 10&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 84&lt;br/&gt;
Ferruginous Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 10&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20201014" rel="alternate" title="Wednesday, October 14, 2020" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20201014" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>T. E. Ely</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20201013</id><published>2020-10-13T16:28:51.913-0700</published><updated>2020-10-13T16:28:51.913-0700</updated><title>Tuesday, October 13, 2020</title><content type="html">Today started hot with a light eastern wind, as the day progressed the wind shifted from NNW and the cool breeze made the temps manageable. The hottest afternoon reading was 84-degrees.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Most of today's flight was Redtail and TV.  Some good numbers of Sharp-shinned and Cooper's hawks especially after 12 noon.  Broadwings seen in small numbers throughout the day - 11 in all. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The day's highlight? An adult Bald Eagle that drifted from Hill 88 vicinity, cruised toward Hawk Hill, then climbed another 500 ft over Hawk Hill and lined out for parts south.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;LOTS of non-rapts today - Band-tailed Pigeons and Violet-green Swallows by the 100s, but also hundreds of Variegated Meadowhawks, and some Common Green Darners and Black Saddlebags.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 332&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5.25&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 63.2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 12&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 114&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Bald Eagle: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 10&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 53&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 28&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 11&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 11&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 82&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 11&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20201013" rel="alternate" title="Tuesday, October 13, 2020" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20201013" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Allen Fish</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20201012</id><published>2020-10-12T17:06:37.811-0700</published><updated>2020-10-12T17:06:37.811-0700</updated><title>Monday, October 12, 2020</title><content type="html">Great day for the Monday team! Clear skies and good AQI all day made for our longest day on the Hill this season. The flight was steady with good diversity. We counted 12 species - the highest species count for this team so far. Highlights included a number of Osprey sightings and a juvenile Golden Eagle in the 1-2 pm hour! &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 344&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5.25&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 65.5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 12&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 122&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 43&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 27&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 12&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 14&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 97&lt;br/&gt;
Golden Eagle: 1&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 7&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20201012" rel="alternate" title="Monday, October 12, 2020" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20201012" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Kelsie McInnis</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20201009</id><published>2020-10-09T16:05:45.569-0700</published><updated>2020-10-09T16:05:45.569-0700</updated><title>Friday, October 09, 2020</title><content type="html">Hawk Hill was slow to clear after a night of fog + mist + misty-rain? - perhaps.  There were puddles on the hilltop.  We started the count at 1045 with crystal clear light and beautiful clouds and an explosion of termites.  Yes, I said termites - little black ones - I'll try to get an ID but the were winged and swarming out of holes in the ground on the hard-gravel top of Hawk Hill. 100s per minute emerging and flying into the sky. And where there are termites....&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;White-throated Swifts provided the most active entertainment, taking the word ZOOM much more seriously than we do. Dozens in the sky at once often strafing, stooping, sweeping, barnstorming, and zooming between hawk counters, not even pretending to respect the 10 foot distances we have set for ourselves.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Beyond the swifts, we noted both a Western Fence Lizard and a Bewick's Wren going to town on termites. Also a half dozen Western Bluebirds. No insectivores are going hungry on Hawk Hill tonight.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Raptor highlights were a steady showing of Broad-winged Hawks, some close, some far, including a dark morph juvenile cruising south. This has been a quiet year for Peregrines, however a pair o'Peregrines - one adult, one juv - did a spectacular fandango around, across, and through the sky over Hawk Hill for several minutes, thrilling us all, except perhaps the juvenile Redtail they stooped on repeatedly.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Another highlight of Hawk Hill ornithological oddness today was a weird gang attack of three Ravens on one Raven.  Or possibly it was just one Raven on one Raven with three others egging him on.  This took place around 1 pm, on the west platform, within 4 feet of a tourist: one Raven standing on another, pecking at its body with its beak.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The birds continued throughout the day until 2 pm when the fog swamped us from the West, and we called it a day.&lt;br/&gt;A special nod to the late John Lennon who turns 80 years young today, and wrote admiringly about birds of prey in his song, "For the Benefit of Mr. Kite."&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 138&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 3.25&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 42.5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 9&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 73&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 20&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 12&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 16&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 3&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20201009" rel="alternate" title="Friday, October 09, 2020" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20201009" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Allen Fish</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20201008</id><published>2020-10-08T16:04:48.972-0700</published><updated>2020-10-08T16:04:48.972-0700</updated><title>Thursday, October 08, 2020</title><content type="html">The day started off with cloudy overcast, and continued to be cloudy and foggy all day. But we had enough visibility to count all day.  Broad-wings are still moving through the Headlands. The highlight was a large number of turkey vultures migrating. Birds disappeared and reappeared in the cloud/fog all day. &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 257&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 51.4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 12&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 143&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 18&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 11&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 56&lt;br/&gt;
Golden Eagle: 2&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 9&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20201008" rel="alternate" title="Thursday, October 08, 2020" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20201008" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>T. E. Ely</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20201007</id><published>2020-10-07T15:58:01.427-0700</published><updated>2020-10-07T15:58:01.427-0700</updated><title>Wednesday, October 07, 2020</title><content type="html">Heavy fog in the morning with enough clearing around noon to start counting. Nice diversity and close looks today. Broad-wings, two merlins chasing each other, and a peregrine with a HUGE crop were the highlights. Cloud cover and some fog were continued through the afternoon, but not enough to stop us from counting. Winds from the north, and north west at times. &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 185&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 2.08&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 88.9&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 10&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 58&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 27&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 16&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 16&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 46&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 3&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20201007" rel="alternate" title="Wednesday, October 07, 2020" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20201007" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>T. E. Ely</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20201006</id><published>2020-10-06T15:53:29.785-0700</published><updated>2020-10-06T15:53:29.785-0700</updated><title>Tuesday, October 06, 2020</title><content type="html">Started a little late with the safety tailgate at 10 am, count start at 1030, as Hawk Hill emerged from the fog. We recommend checking the "Mt Tam Cam" along with the Crissy Field "East Beach Cam" for synthesizing a reasonable true picture of fog conditions on Hawk Hill.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Fog retreated to the Rodeo Lagoon area by noon but started to fill back in, swamping the Hill from the west by 2 pm.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Highlights of the day were several mixed kettles of raptors, mostly Broadwings, TVs, and Redtails, with a few accips thrown in. Most were in the warmest local bubble, the ridge west of Kirby Cove, which seemed to produce good thermals throughout the mid day.  At least one or two adult Cooper's Hawks came through, plus an adult dark dark morph Broadwing, likely the same one seen Oct 5th.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 254&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 3.5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 72.6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 10&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 86&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 10&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 31&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 17&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 39&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 57&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 4&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20201006" rel="alternate" title="Tuesday, October 06, 2020" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20201006" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Allen Fish</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20201005</id><published>2020-10-05T20:12:37.550-0700</published><updated>2020-10-05T20:12:37.550-0700</updated><title>Monday, October 05, 2020</title><content type="html">The morning started with a dense fog layer obstructing the Golden Gate Bridge and Hawk Hill. We delayed our start time and weren't feeling too optimistic about our chances of counting today. But by 10:30, the fog was starting to sink and blue skies were peaking out above Hawk Hill. The team met at noon and began counting at 12:30 pm. A short day, but a lot of good movement to be seen - a great day for Broad-winged Hawks. Highlight was a dark morph adult Broadwing that hung around and gave the team a few good looks!  &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 219&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 2.5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 87.6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 7&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 65&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 21&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 12&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 31&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 83&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 5&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20201005" rel="alternate" title="Monday, October 05, 2020" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20201005" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Kelsie McInnis</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20201002</id><published>2020-10-02T12:22:53.531-0700</published><updated>2020-10-02T12:22:53.531-0700</updated><title>Friday, October 02, 2020</title><content type="html">Friday Oct 2nd showed very high AQI, (see fire.airnow.gov) ranging throughout the orange and red zones for the Golden Gate region and north.  Given that extensive north winds are predicted for the day, we decided to cancel field counts today.  Good luck for next week -&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20201002" rel="alternate" title="Friday, October 02, 2020" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20201002" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Allen Fish</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20201001</id><published>2020-10-01T14:16:13.687-0700</published><updated>2020-10-01T14:16:13.687-0700</updated><title>Thursday, October 01, 2020</title><content type="html">No count today due to high temps and poor air. &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20201001" rel="alternate" title="Thursday, October 01, 2020" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20201001" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>T. E. Ely</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20200930</id><published>2020-09-30T16:13:22.031-0700</published><updated>2020-09-30T16:13:22.031-0700</updated><title>Wednesday, September 30, 2020</title><content type="html">Thick fog in the morning. Wind shifted, fog parted so team assembled for noon start. Big movement of birds right before noon and continued to have nice migration. Smoke and visibility ended the count after 2 hours.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 111&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 55.5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 11&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 15&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 27&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 11&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 41&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 2&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20200930" rel="alternate" title="Wednesday, September 30, 2020" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20200930" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Step Wilson</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20200929</id><published>2020-09-30T09:59:52.753-0700</published><updated>2020-09-30T09:59:52.753-0700</updated><title>Tuesday, September 29, 2020</title><content type="html">Heavy fog all day after yesterday's high heat. No count conducted. &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20200929" rel="alternate" title="Tuesday, September 29, 2020" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20200929" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Step Wilson </name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20200928</id><published>2020-09-28T16:15:35.984-0700</published><updated>2020-09-28T16:15:35.984-0700</updated><title>Monday, September 28, 2020</title><content type="html">Fires in the North Bay made for a hazy morning and limited visibility, but no fog and low AQI readings allowed the Monday team to start counting at 10 am. Highlights included a close Merlin and an adult female Northern Harrier. The morning was off to a strong start but the count was cut short by high heat at 11:30 am. &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 117&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 1.5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 78&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 26&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 13&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 63&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 4&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20200928" rel="alternate" title="Monday, September 28, 2020" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20200928" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Kelsie McInnis</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20200925</id><published>2020-09-25T16:59:40.820-0700</published><updated>2020-09-25T16:59:40.820-0700</updated><title>Friday, September 25, 2020</title><content type="html">A spectacularly clear AM with east winds in the morning turning to south and then west by the PM. An average flight of the four "regulars" -- Redtail, Sharpshin, Coop, and TVs,  Highlights included several gangs of Broad-winged Hawks moving high across the eastern sky using Slacker Ridge for lift. A juv Golden that first appeared against the south face of Mt Tam, but came in and out of view for 30 mins until it appeared near the GG Bridge, also following the Slacker Ridge line.  A young Osprey flew straight south, so close overhead, that we could smell the trout.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 249&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 4.75&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 52.4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 12&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 75&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 3&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 36&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 19&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 23&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 73&lt;br/&gt;
Golden Eagle: 1&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 3&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20200925" rel="alternate" title="Friday, September 25, 2020" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20200925" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Allen Fish</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20200924</id><published>2020-09-24T16:16:01.342-0700</published><updated>2020-09-24T16:16:01.342-0700</updated><title>Thursday, September 24, 2020</title><content type="html">Today started off with heavy fog, but it started to lift around noon. During the next hour, the raptors really started moving. Patchy fog in the early afternoon.  Red-shoulders and a white-tailed kite were the highlight of the day.    &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Poem of the day:&lt;br/&gt;Sly September fog. &lt;br/&gt;Flurries of hawk break through with the sun.&lt;br/&gt;Then Karl returns. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 164&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 2.75&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 59.64&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 9&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 32&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 29&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 20&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 58&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 12&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20200924" rel="alternate" title="Thursday, September 24, 2020" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20200924" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>T. E. Ely</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20200923</id><published>2020-09-23T17:48:21.418-0700</published><updated>2020-09-23T17:48:21.418-0700</updated><title>Wednesday, September 23, 2020</title><content type="html">Day started out slow with light east winds. Numbers never really picked up but the diversity was great. It started around noon with a Golden Eagle and Ferruginous Hawk spotted circling up together in the NW. It was great to sight a juvenile Swainson's Hawk to see all the buteos. And we ended the day with a Merlin. Wind shifted to the NW and we hope in will push in birds for tomorrow.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 264&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 52.8&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 15&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 79&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Bald Eagle: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 27&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 25&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Swainson's Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 94&lt;br/&gt;
Ferruginous Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Golden Eagle: 2&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 14&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20200923" rel="alternate" title="Wednesday, September 23, 2020" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20200923" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Step Wilson</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20200922</id><published>2020-09-22T19:21:19.950-0700</published><updated>2020-09-22T19:21:19.950-0700</updated><title>Tuesday, September 22, 2020</title><content type="html">Heavy fog was in the headlands this morning and covered Hawk Hill until after 13:00 even though it lifted in the rest of the headlands. &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20200922" rel="alternate" title="Tuesday, September 22, 2020" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20200922" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Step Wilson </name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20200921</id><published>2020-09-21T18:43:35.832-0700</published><updated>2020-09-21T18:43:35.832-0700</updated><title>Monday, September 21, 2020</title><content type="html">The team postponed our meeting time due to thick fog, and was feeling optimistic when patches of blue sky started breaking through the dense wall of fog at the Headlands and Golden Gate Bridge around 9 am. The team met at 10:30 am, greatly anticipating our first official count day together, but unfortunately, the fog never broke at Hawk Hill and there was no official count today. There was, however, lots of great raptor activity seen by volunteers and staff east of Hawk Hill at the Annex. 8 species were spotted, including 7 Merlins! Hoping for clear skies and many great raptors for the rest of the week!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20200921" rel="alternate" title="Monday, September 21, 2020" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20200921" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Kelsie </name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20200918</id><published>2020-09-18T15:57:16.840-0700</published><updated>2020-09-18T15:57:16.840-0700</updated><title>Friday, September 18, 2020</title><content type="html">Fog stayed in the Gate and all around the Headlands and Hawk Hill all day in spite of our noble hopes - a few accips scooting around the Hill, but no official count today. &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20200918" rel="alternate" title="Friday, September 18, 2020" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20200918" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Allen Fish</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20200917</id><published>2020-09-17T13:50:26.356-0700</published><updated>2020-09-17T13:50:26.356-0700</updated><title>Thursday, September 17, 2020</title><content type="html">Today was foggy, and it looked like the fog would lift by late morning.  We went up to count. There were some moments where we thought the fog would completely lift and move out, but that blue sky didn't last long. We closed up at 1pm. &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 7&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 1.25&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 5.6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20200917" rel="alternate" title="Thursday, September 17, 2020" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20200917" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>T. E. Ely</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20200916</id><published>2020-09-16T17:09:09.620-0700</published><updated>2020-09-16T17:09:09.620-0700</updated><title>Wednesday, September 16, 2020</title><content type="html">Today's first Hawkwatch count started with fog threatening to obstruct the count. Light winds in the morning which weren't good for any bird movement on the hill began to improve after an hour or more and so did the birds. Everyone was thrilled to again work on the difference between juvenile Sharp-shinned and Cooper's Hawks. Ospreys and American Kestrels moved through along with 4 Broad-winged Hawks. &lt;br/&gt;Hopefully tomorrow will have better winds as they picked up and continued later in the day. &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 225&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 45&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 11&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 78&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 29&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 21&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 70&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 3&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20200916" rel="alternate" title="Wednesday, September 16, 2020" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20200916" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Step Wilson</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20200915</id><published>2020-09-15T15:30:39.126-0700</published><updated>2020-09-15T15:30:39.126-0700</updated><title>Tuesday, September 15, 2020</title><content type="html">Hawkwatch did not officially count today as we are in our step up phase and counting only three days a week. Tomorrow's forecast looks better for air quality and visibility, so we did not count but worked with the data equipment. While spending an hour at the wingspans working with the data collection devices raptors seemed to be on the move with mainly juvenile Sharp-shinned and Red-tailed Hawks. Prairie Falcon and Golden Eagle were the stand out sightings of the hour/day. &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20200915" rel="alternate" title="Tuesday, September 15, 2020" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20200915" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Step Wilson</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20200914</id><published>2020-09-14T07:51:32.398-0700</published><updated>2020-09-14T07:51:32.398-0700</updated><title>Monday, September 14, 2020</title><content type="html">Hawkwatch canceled today due to poor AQI in and around the Marin Headlands. Early morning air quality registered as Very Unhealthy and AQI is predicted to remain in the Unhealthy range along the coast and throughout the Central Bay. Smoke conditions are forecast to improve over the next few days and we are hopeful to get our first official count day on the books later this week.  &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20200914" rel="alternate" title="Monday, September 14, 2020" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20200914" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Kelsie</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20200911</id><published>2020-09-11T10:53:10.334-0700</published><updated>2020-09-11T10:53:10.334-0700</updated><title>Friday, September 11, 2020</title><content type="html">Sept 11 GGRO hawk count was cancelled due to a high AQI measure throughout the Bay Area. Ratings this morning were between red and purple based on fire.airnow.gov and purpleair corresp to AQI's from 150 to 350.  The Ft Cronkhite outside sensor read 297 this AM  - very unusual for the coast. Take good care everyone -&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20200911" rel="alternate" title="Friday, September 11, 2020" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20200911" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Allen Fish</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20200910</id><published>2020-09-10T18:16:54.755-0700</published><updated>2020-09-10T18:16:54.755-0700</updated><title>Thursday, September 10, 2020</title><content type="html">AQI was in the Red in and around the Headlands around 7am, along with dense fog. No counting took place today. The smoke was bad all day.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20200910" rel="alternate" title="Thursday, September 10, 2020" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20200910" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>T. E. Ely</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20200909</id><published>2020-09-10T05:41:46.272-0700</published><updated>2020-09-10T05:41:46.272-0700</updated><title>Wednesday, September 09, 2020</title><content type="html">GGRO hawkwatch was to begin it's count today. The mix of fog and smoke in the headlands created conditions impossible to count. It was so dark at noon it looked like midnight. &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20200909" rel="alternate" title="Wednesday, September 09, 2020" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20200909" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Step Wilson </name></author></entry>

</feed>