<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><?xml-stylesheet href='http://www.blogger.com/styles/atom.css' type='text/css'?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/">
    <id>hydromatic-ggro</id>
    <updated>2022-09-30T16:41:33.636-0700</updated>
    <title type="text">GGRO daily hawkwatch update</title>
    <link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml" rel="next" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml" rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#feed" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <author>
      <name>GGRO</name>
      <uri>http://www.ggro.org</uri>
      <email>ggro@parksconservancy.org</email>
    </author>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20220930</id><published>2022-09-30T16:41:33.636-0700</published><updated>2022-09-30T16:41:33.636-0700</updated><title>Friday, September 30, 2022</title><content type="html">A light haze dusted the city and bridge as we approached the hill of clear skies and sun. Wind was nowhere to be found and it was a warm morning with the day ranging from 70-74 degrees F. With a slow start to the raptor flow, we enjoyed a good look at an adult male Northern Harrier- the infamous "grey ghost." Though the birds were slow at first, we were happy to see the first group of the season of Migratory Story students enjoying the lower viewpoints of Hawk Hill. We love welcoming our future raptor biologists! &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;An ever so slight 2 mph breeze started the migration flow. Kestrels danced through the sky up the cables of the Golden Gate Bridge and our midday excitement included watching Osprey glide across the valley and the lagoon. We hoped that the Broad-winged Hawk kettles from yesterday would continue, and indeed they did! Several kettles drifted in from Mount Tam as we patiently waited for them to get closer. We marveled at their flight pattern of small circling groups that reminded us of a mobile of birds on invisible strings. It was wonderful to see kettles of 5 or so birds being joined by Turkey Vultures, accipiters, and Red-tailed Hawks as the floated over Slacker Ridge toward the bay. A distant Golden Eagle was spotted in the northwest, and though we kept hoping it would come closer, it continued onward into the greenery toward Tam. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;During the last hour of the day, foghorns bellowed as thick fog blanketed the southeast and started to cover the lagoon in the west. A strong breeze of 10-12 mph from the west brought a flurry of Sharp-shinned Hawks near and far as the counters were tallying right up to the last minute busy with birds. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Carmen DeLeon, Conservation &amp; Community Science Program Coordinator &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Dayleaders: Holly Thomas &amp; Libby Rouan &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Count Team: Laura Thomas, Sonja Raub, Connor Cimmiyotti, Horacio Mena, Allen Fish, Carmen DeLeon &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 503&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 100.6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 12&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 99&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 157&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 57&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 30&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 102&lt;br/&gt;
Golden Eagle: 1&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Prairie Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 21&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 10&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 33&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20220930" rel="alternate" title="Friday, September 30, 2022" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20220930" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Carmen DeLeon</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20220929</id><published>2022-09-29T16:40:19.360-0700</published><updated>2022-09-29T16:40:19.360-0700</updated><title>Thursday, September 29, 2022</title><content type="html">Warmer temps and leisurely winds cleared up the skies, quickly dissipating the early morning fog. The gusts picked up during the last hour, reaching up to 9-mph, but with birds blasting over the Hill all day long, it was evident the wind was not needed.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The theme of the day was kettles of mostly Broadwings with a mix of Redtails, Coops, and Sharpies that rose over Slacker Ridge and slowly drifted towards the Golden Gate Bridge. The first Broadwing kettle of the morning emerged when the Hawkwatch team was getting ready to start the count! After that, we eagerly anticipated an exciting day -and the raptors delivered! The morning's highlights include a fleeting look at a White-tailed Kite and a few Merlins, one of which was snacking on a winged arthropod in flight. Noon had its own set of excitement; a juvenile Ferruginous Hawk rose from Gerbode Valley and made straight for the Bridge followed two minutes later by an adult Bald Eagle on the same trajectory. Lastly, the final hours of the count did not fall short of raptors either... even a sub-adult Swainson's Hawk and a couple of female Kestrels circled a few times before continuing their southern migration.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Overall, a spectacular day enjoyed by the Hawkwatch team and all the raptor afficionados that made it to the Hill today.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;- Laura Echávez, GGRO Senior Biotech&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Dayleader: Christine Cariño&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Count Team: Pat Bacchetti, Bob Blumberg, John Davis, Susan Greef, Carmen DeLeon, Laura Echávez&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 528&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 105&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 13&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 89&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Bald Eagle: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 170&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 65&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 14&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 80&lt;br/&gt;
Swainson's Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 82&lt;br/&gt;
Ferruginous Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 9&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 11&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20220929" rel="alternate" title="Thursday, September 29, 2022" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20220929" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Laura Echavez</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20220928</id><published>2022-09-28T17:29:37.809-0700</published><updated>2022-09-28T17:29:37.809-0700</updated><title>Wednesday, September 28, 2022</title><content type="html">Despite foggy conditions, the count team still managed to observe some great birds as they passed Hawk Hill from all angles and directions. We had decent visibility for the first couple of hours, as the edge of the fog stayed close to the hill and was thin enough to spot some Broad-winged Hawks, American Kestrels, Merlins, and many Sharp-shinned Hawks as they rose and barreled over our heads. It was a rare sighting to spot one Sharpie at a time, as they all seemed to be trailed by two...three...or six more accipiter's; tumbling with talons out at times. Rapid barrel rolls and aerial rivalry, we love the drama and display up above!  &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;We were greeted this morning by a group of students from USF who were on a field trip with their ornithology class. As much as we are fascinated by raptor ecology and movement, we are also thrilled to see how young biologists navigate and grow. Come see us up on Hawk Hill again sometime! &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;-Krista Fanucchi, GGRO Assistant Biotechnician &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Dayleaders: Don Bartling, Jon Altemus &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Count Team: Linda Sudduth, John Davis, Sue Morgan, Jan Ambrosini, Krista Fanucchi &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 175&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 43.75&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 7&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 33&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 83&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 24&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 9&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 13&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20220928" rel="alternate" title="Wednesday, September 28, 2022" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20220928" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Krista Fanucchi</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20220927</id><published>2022-09-27T17:46:22.409-0700</published><updated>2022-09-27T17:46:22.409-0700</updated><title>Tuesday, September 27, 2022</title><content type="html">Tuesday morning started with a high gray canopy of clouds over the Marin Headlands, a definite improvement over the dense fog of the last 2 days as the hilltops were actually visible. Winds started NE today but floated to NW by late afternoon, and mostly 64- 70 degrees and few clouds by 3 pm.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Sharp-shinned Hawks were contour-flying around the cars as we arrived at 930 am, so we made the call to get up and start counting pronto.  But not until after a moment of silence and acknowledgement for the heroic event of 60 years ago today: Rachel Carson's hugely impactful book, Silent Spring, was published.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Silent Spring links directly to the world of raptor migration as Rachel Carson used data from Hawk Mountain, PA, to provide evidence of the human and environmental disaster that was (and is) DDT.  The migration counts from Hawk Mt - given to Rachel by Maurice Broun in 1960 - showed a clear decline of Bald Eagle numbers post-1948 (year 1 of DDT use in the Northeast) and primarily a decline in juvenile birds.  Why juveniles?  Because DDT specifically attacks the reproductive system of female birds. So juveniles declined faster than adults.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Today, the Marin Headlands raptors came out in honor of Silent Spring and Rachel Carson - we had an incredible flight on Hawk Hill: 640 raptor-sightings, with 14 different species including four falcon spp. The flight began immediately this morning - Broad-winged and Sharp-shinned Hawks especially numerous, but also Cooper's, Redtails, and some Redshoulders started appearing among the patchy clouds under a light NE breeze.  &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Falcons showing up gradually with many direct south-bound flybys of Merlins and Kestrels. Twenty Kestrel sightings for the day!  A pair of adult Peregrines chasing the accipiters around, but a few juv Peregrines as well. A few Osprey and two Ferruginous Hawks plus four Harriers and a White-tailed Kite gave us a great range of species.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;- Allen Fish&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Dayleaders: Andrew Bradshaw, Mary Kenney&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Count Team: Woody Woodbury, Jody Newman, Chris Tarr, Dan Foldes, Rich Eliason, Allen Fish - special thanks to NPS biologists Ana Arce and Morgan Barnes for joining us today and contributing some awesome spotting.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 640&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 128&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 14&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 135&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 2&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 168&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 75&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 10&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 39&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 144&lt;br/&gt;
Ferruginous Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 20&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 10&lt;br/&gt;
Prairie Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 16&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 22&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20220927" rel="alternate" title="Tuesday, September 27, 2022" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20220927" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Allen Fish</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20220926</id><published>2022-09-26T17:22:04.120-0700</published><updated>2022-09-26T17:22:04.120-0700</updated><title>Monday, September 26, 2022</title><content type="html">Foggy conditions on Hawk Hill this morning sent the count team down to mingle with the many Yellow Warblers at Rodeo Lagoon. We returned to the hill around noon to check the weather status and enjoy our lunch downslope from the East quadrant, and we were pleasantly surprised to see many passing Accipiter's and a Broad-winged Hawk. We considered these observations as a good sign that we could get a couple hours of counting in for the day. So, that is exactly what we did!  &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;And what a rich and productive couple of hours it was... Sharp-shinned Hawks were catapulting up over our heads, through every quadrant, then fading into the mist. A few Merlins' buzzed Hawk Hill, also trailing off into the clouds and quickly out of sight. Though the count team was on their toes and busy with the Raptor display above, we still had a moment to spot and observe the yellow-green crown and back contrasting with the gray face/chest/belly of a Chestnut-sided Warbler as it foraged in and out of the Coyote brush near the North quadrant. As the count team was descending the hill, a Northern Harrier teetered our way and accompanied us on our way out. Looking forward to whatever comes our way next time...    &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;-Krista Fanucchi, GGRO Assistant Biotechnician &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Dayleaders: Deborah Crooks, Linda Schneider &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Count Team: Linda Chambers, Patty Lessard, Peter Sapienza, Wade Eakle, Denise Peck, Krista Fanucchi &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 95&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 47.5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 7&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 11&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 57&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 9&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 7&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20220926" rel="alternate" title="Monday, September 26, 2022" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20220926" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Krista Fanucchi</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20220925</id><published>2022-09-25T16:55:52.835-0700</published><updated>2022-09-25T16:55:52.835-0700</updated><title>Sunday, September 25, 2022</title><content type="html">The fog layer hovered over the Marin Headlands all day, but the velvet white lifted enough for us to start the raptor count by 11AM. Temps started and ended at 59-degrees F, reaching a max of 62F at noon. However, the early morning breeze quickly turned to 15-mph gusts that catapulted Sharpies overhead while the team scrambled for their puffy layers.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Even though the fog never fully lifted, we had many decent opportunities at viewing some incredible behaviors. To start off the day, a flock of ~40 Band-tailed Pigeons rushed over Kirby Cove, when an adult Redtail slowly descended upon them, feet down, and snatched a pigeon mid-air! What a feast that must have been for the Redtail! That was not the only raptor with prey on its mind though. We also observed a Peregrine Falcon swooping on potential prey -it dove straight towards the ground before making sharp U-turns in its attempts.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The strong winds fast-forwarded birds from our view, not only the Sharpies, but Kestrels and Merlins as well. Even the larger species were no match against the turbulent air. Whether they meant to or not, a handful of Cooper's Hawks zipped by today, while a young Northern Harrier rode the wind as it gracefully seesawed towards the south. We hope for sunnier days on their journey and on the hawkwatch days ahead!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;- Laura Echávez, GGRO Senior Biotech&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Dayleader: Becky Olsen &amp; Ken Wilson&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Count Team: Ana Maria Olivar, Kinley Renger, Carol Weinstein, Allen Fish, Laura Echávez&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 90&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 22.5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 8&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 14&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 27&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 34&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 3&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20220925" rel="alternate" title="Sunday, September 25, 2022" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20220925" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Laura Echavez</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20220924</id><published>2022-09-24T16:45:27.889-0700</published><updated>2022-09-24T16:45:27.889-0700</updated><title>Saturday, September 24, 2022</title><content type="html">Was today a day...or was it really 3 days in one?  While it stayed right around 68-72 degrees F throughout the count time, the sunshine, wind, and fog brought us distinct phases of weather conditions with varying raptor flow. With dry air, bright sunshine, and zero wind it seemed like we could be in for a hot day with few raptors. An early sighting of a dark morph Broad-Winged Hawk that sailed in from the north and soared above the bay was a delight for all!  &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Thankfully, the west wind finally woke up in the early afternoon with a gentle 3 mph breeze and absolutely clear skies. Red-tailed Hawks and Turkey Vultures began moving in small kettles over the Golden Gate and into the East Bay. Accipiters trickled through mixing in with the soaring kettles. As the breeze picked up, we were surprised to see 3 Merlins in a single hour each flapping fast (as MERLs do!) around the hill and across the bay. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Later in the afternoon, those in North had clear skies while thick fog crept through the lagoon and loomed below the hill. As pillowy fog replaced our views of the ocean and bay in the southwest, the wind picked up to 10 mph. While visibility was limited in some areas, the fog seemed to push a flow of accips with Sharp-shinned Hawks fluttering fast in the wind and banking through the fog around the hill. We were excited to compare sharpies and coops side by side and get to finish the day with a fairly active hour. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Broadwing and Sharpie fans- we see you! Keep an eye on the skies and visit the hill often. Every day is its own adventure in nature.  &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;-Carmen DeLeon, Conservation &amp; Community Science Program Coordinator and Krista Fanucchi, GGRO Biotech &lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;Dayleader: Jane Rudebusch &lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;Count Team: Lora Roame, Michael Voeltz, Maryrose Kulick, Sam Hontalas &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 350&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 70&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 10&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 59&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 85&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 68&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 109&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 7&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 9&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20220924" rel="alternate" title="Saturday, September 24, 2022" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20220924" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Carmen DeLeon &amp; Krista Fanucchi</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20220923</id><published>2022-09-23T16:59:33.033-0700</published><updated>2022-09-23T16:59:33.033-0700</updated><title>Friday, September 23, 2022</title><content type="html">A gentle NE breeze in the AM hours turned to a light east wind, then nearly dead air after 2 pm. By 230 pm, we had a rousing west wind, and with it, some more accips to finish the day with. AM temps started at 72-deg and finished at 80-deg at 3 pm.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;In our first half-hour an adult female Peregrine chose to alight on the railing at the west end of Hawk Hill and study the waters of the Golden Gate 900 feet below. She allowed us to watch her for some 10 mins before making an intercepting flight to catch up with the adult male travelling by at, well, falcon speed.  The two soared, flapped, and glided around the sky for a good 15 mins, forcing us to watch their every wingbeat, their flight configurations, and the various colors shone by the angle of the sun.  It was a terrible ordeal, but what can you do? Finally they flew off, allowing for a few more Sharp-shinned Hawks to fly cautiously across the sky.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This wasn't a fast migration today. And much of it was quite high up. And never dull. We had great close looks at a juvenile Osprey (with white scalloped-edging on every back feather), and an adult Osprey (also a dorsal view showing multiple shades/ages of primaries and secondaries).  &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;A bunch of Red-shouldered Hawks appeared throughout the day, and a few Merlin and Kestrel flybys kept our eyes sharp.  Many dragonflies riding high thermals seemed to keep the Merlins engaged. A three-falcon day is always good. One distant, high Broad-winged at the end of the day was a nice bit of frosting on the cake. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;-	Allen Fish&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Dayleaders: Horacio Mena, Holly Thomas&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Count Team: Will Ludan, Tomas McKay, Connor Cimmiyotti, Allen Fish&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 309&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 61.8&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 11&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 114&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 49&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 27&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 9&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 78&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 16&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 17&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20220923" rel="alternate" title="Friday, September 23, 2022" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20220923" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Allen Fish</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20220922</id><published>2022-09-22T18:05:16.979-0700</published><updated>2022-09-22T18:05:16.979-0700</updated><title>Thursday, September 22, 2022</title><content type="html">Standing at the Hawk Hill parking area before making our way up to the count site, the team enjoyed a stream of Sharp-shinned Hawks. They carried the promise of a more "normal" peak day for the program -and regardless of whatever normal means, we certainly had an amazing day on the Hill.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The warmer temps and southern winds brought a wide array of raptors, and we finished the day at 11 species! In addition to the numerous Redtails and Turkey Vultures, a few other species were also sighted various times. Broadwings, Redshoulders, Ospreys, and Merlins were among the most exciting events! Oftentimes, many of the birds we see are far away, but maybe because of the slow winds today, a lot of them soared right over the team. Even a juvenile Golden Eagle circled right above, showing off the beautiful chocolatey colors and white patches!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Other highlights also include some non-raptor migrants. Large flocks of Band-tailed Pigeons fluttered south within the first couple of hours of the count, and Vaux's Swifts zoomed by in big numbers throughout the entire day. Finally, 21 Monarch Butterflies also dashed across the Headlands, often being initially confused for a gliding Sharpie and impressing the team with their speedy flight! Overall, a fun day of counting for the Thursday Hawkwatch team!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;- Laura Echávez, GGRO Senior Biotech&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Dayleader: Christine Carino &amp; Gretchen Zantzinger&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Count Team: Bob Blumberg, Pat Contaxis, Michaela Figari, Jim Yampolsky, Pauline Yeckley, Laura Echávez&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 378&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 75.6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 11&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 151&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 62&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 22&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 107&lt;br/&gt;
Golden Eagle: 1&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 8&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20220922" rel="alternate" title="Thursday, September 22, 2022" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20220922" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Laura Echavez</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20220921</id><published>2022-09-21T17:01:39.585-0700</published><updated>2022-09-21T17:01:39.585-0700</updated><title>Wednesday, September 21, 2022</title><content type="html">Another day of magnificent cumulus clouds! The gentle southwest wind averaged around 5-mph and the cool temperatures did not rise above the mid-70s. Despite the less-than-optimal winds, today's flight included a diverse array of species, and it appears that the Accipiters are finally arriving.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;After a steady trickle of Sharpies throughout the day, the final hour felt chaotic. For every pair of Redtails we saw, a Sharpie appeared... as if on cue. A total of 48 sightings of the smallest Accipiter were recorded today -more than doubling the season's numbers thus far! The Cooper's Hawks trailed behind by quite a bit, but enough to allow for opportunities to compare the two.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Some other highlights include Peregrines dive-bombing young Redtails; a Merlin flying fast past Slacker Ridge; an adult Osprey headed straight for Golden Gate Park; and finally, a handful of Broadwings -a couple of which circled high over the team before continuing along their lengthy migration route!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;- Laura Echávez, GGRO Senior Biotech&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Dayleader: Don Bartling &amp; Erica Harris&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Count Team: Sam Hontalas, John Davis, Holly Thomas, Laura Echávez&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 307&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 61.4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 10&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 110&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 48&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 9&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 122&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 4&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20220921" rel="alternate" title="Wednesday, September 21, 2022" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20220921" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Laura Echavez</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20220920</id><published>2022-09-20T18:20:22.843-0700</published><updated>2022-09-20T18:19:22.843-0700</updated><title>Tuesday, September 20, 2022</title><content type="html">&lt;br/&gt;Long lines of beefsteak clouds persisted in the Bay Area this morning, with east winds gusting to 12 mph in the Marin Headlands.  During the day, the wind crept to SW, then finished at 2-3 pm from the west. We even got a touch of rain after 3 pm.  Temps stayed in the 68-78 degree window, depending on the amount of cloud cover at any given moment.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;A fair day of Redtails, mostly flying the Slacker Hill/ridgeline over Sausalito, with some brief showings by Redshoulders, Peregrines, a Merlin, and a few Accipiters - although not many of the latter.  &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The insectivores were out in force today from Blue-gray Gnatcatchers to Vaux's Swifts, from Flame Skimmers to Blue Mosaic dragonflies. The rains plus sudden warmth kept the flying termite irruption today. A few Black Swifts were flying behind one of the Vaux's flocks this morning.  And many singing White-throated Swifts as well.  Hey, how about the Golden Gate Swift Observatory?&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;-	Allen Fish&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Dayleaders: Catherine Elliott, Mary Kenney&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Count Team: Tom Luster, Woody Woodbury, Maureen Grabowski, Dennis Davison, Allen Fish&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 149&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 4.75&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 31.4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 9&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 66&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 10&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 53&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 4&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20220920" rel="alternate" title="Tuesday, September 20, 2022" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20220920" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Allen Fish</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20220919</id><published>2022-09-19T16:02:59.350-0700</published><updated>2022-09-19T16:02:59.350-0700</updated><title>Monday, September 19, 2022</title><content type="html">&lt;br/&gt;Following yesterday's splendid storm, today's morning skies featured lines of cumulus that would make Andrew Wyeth jealous: forty-five variations on white, gray, pewter, and bruisy black clouds piled high over Mt. Tam, the GG Bridge, and the East Bay Hills. Gorgeous.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The wind started at SE and turned to SW by late morning.  Temps stayed between 64 and 70-deg for the day.  A full-on west wind didn't take form until after 1 pm, but the hawks were intermittent all day long. A little quiet for September 19th - but the diversity was wonderful.  Close looks at Merlin, Peregrine, Redshoulders - and a half dozen accips.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Dayleader: James McDermott&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Count Team: Deborah Crooks, Roy Pisetsky, Linda Schneider, Jan Ambrosini, Kimberlie Moutoux, Allen Fish&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 196&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 4.75&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 41.3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 8&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 98&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 80&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 4&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20220919" rel="alternate" title="Monday, September 19, 2022" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20220919" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Allen Fish</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20220918</id><published>2022-09-18T12:53:28.846-0700</published><updated>2022-09-18T12:53:28.846-0700</updated><title>Sunday, September 18, 2022</title><content type="html">It is hard to believe I am sitting here, writing about something other than the fog. Hawkwatch was cancelled today due to... rain! Though we typically expect a flooding of Accipiters at this point in the season, we do welcome any form of precipitation we can get around here. And I must say, the approaching storm clouds contrasting with the ocean blue-green at Rodeo Beach was truly beautiful this morning.   &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;-Krista Fanucchi, GGRO Assistant Biotechnician &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20220918" rel="alternate" title="Sunday, September 18, 2022" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20220918" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Krista Fanucchi</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20220917</id><published>2022-09-17T17:03:39.594-0700</published><updated>2022-09-17T17:03:39.594-0700</updated><title>Saturday, September 17, 2022</title><content type="html">Beautiful distant clouds, blue skies, gentle 5-mph winds... oh, and a Broad-winged Hawk! What better start to the day? In addition to the Broadie, the first hour of the count brough a series of exciting raptors! A Red-shouldered Hawk rose from Gerbode Valley and quickly flap-flap-glided southwards. Two Peregrine Falcons guarded the entrance to the Bay as they sat atop the suspension cables of the Golden Gate Bridge. Cooper's Hawks fought the steady western winds as they rose in unison with the Redtails over the valley.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The rest of the day was sprinkled with moments when a hawkwatcher would yell for an interesting bird and the entire team ran from different corners of the Hill -binoculars ready- to catch sight of the visitor. Soon after each of these occurrences, periods of little activity followed, allowing discussions on what we had just observed. One of these was not long after midday, when a juvenile Ferruginous Hawk appeared behind a handful of Redtails circling directly over Hawk Hill! Another highlight was the brief appearance of a Prairie Falcon spotted from the west low near the old rifle range and zipping out of the Headlands.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;During the last hour, the fog crept back into the Bay and around the Hill, and strong gusts of cold wind reminded the team of the looming storm. It may be quiet on the raptor front for the next couple of days...&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;- Laura Echávez, GGRO Senior Biotech&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Dayleader: Mary Malec &amp; Brian O'Laughlin&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Count Team: Alex Cox, Rasia Holzman Smith, JJ Harris, Melissa Hero, Carmen DeLeon, Laura Echávez&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 195&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 39&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 10&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 56&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 15&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 95&lt;br/&gt;
Ferruginous Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Prairie Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 13&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20220917" rel="alternate" title="Saturday, September 17, 2022" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20220917" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Laura Echavez</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20220916</id><published>2022-09-16T16:43:14.898-0700</published><updated>2022-09-16T16:43:14.898-0700</updated><title>Friday, September 16, 2022</title><content type="html">This morning welcomed us with dense fog, but we saw the sun shining on the ocean and knew that it could shape up to be an excellent day on the hill. Our team observed a gopher excavating on the hillside, causing small rocks to slide down, as we waited for the sky to clear. With the fog becoming patchy and the wind picking up, we headed to the hill and started counting at 10:30 AM. The temperatures ranged from 62-73 degrees F with patchy fog clearing to warm, blue skies around 1:30 PM. A steady wind from the west around 8-12 mph brought the beginning of the raptor flow we were most excited to see. &lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;Though we were off to a slow start, we were delighted to see accipiters rising in the north and west with some great looks at Sharp-shinned Hawks side by side. An osprey gliding across Angel Island to the Golden Gate and several Red-shouldered Hawks made for a very fun afternoon!  &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;A special shout out to the students of Downtown High School from the Wilderness Arts and Literacy Collective. We wish you happy birding trails and appreciate you coming to the hill to learn about raptors. Don't hesitate to fly our way again soon! We'd love to have you on the team one day as you continue to explore the world of birds and photography.  &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;- Carmen DeLeon, Conservation and Community Science Program Coordinator &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Dayleaders: Libby Rouan and Holly Thomas &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Count Team: Laura Thomas, Sonja Raub, Conner Cimmiyotti, Horacio Mena, Yvette MacDonald, Allen Fish&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 351&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 4.5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 78&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 9&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 79&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 13&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 233&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 7&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20220916" rel="alternate" title="Friday, September 16, 2022" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20220916" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Carmen DeLeon</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20220915</id><published>2022-09-15T17:08:23.474-0700</published><updated>2022-09-15T17:08:23.474-0700</updated><title>Thursday, September 15, 2022</title><content type="html">A wispy fog capped Hawk Hill this morning, but it slowly drifted upwards throughout the day, giving way to a 360-degree view of the San Francisco Bay and the Marin Headlands. A steady 10-mph gust persisted for a couple of hours but slowed down after noon as the temps settled in the low to mid 60F.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Even though we are entering the peak of Accipiter migration, we have not observed them in their usual numbers. Fortunately, today's team had a streak of luck and saw the highest number of Accipiters seen so far as both Sharp-shinned and Cooper's Hawks graced the Hill -a total of seven of each! However, the day got even more exciting right before lunchtime when a Broad-winged Hawk, our smallest Buteo, materialized out of the fog directly over the count site. Around that same time, a juvenile and an adult Peregrine Falcon perched on the north tower of the Golden Gate Bridge, but the adult quickly chased the young bird off the bridge and into the city.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;That would not be the only falcon species seen today though... A Merlin was spotted from the south as it pursued a White-throated Swift before making a straight line into San Francisco. Just as the day was coming to a close, our fearless leader, Christine, spotted an ephemeral Kestrel over Gerbode Valley, making this a three falcon species day!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The cap to the day was a juvenile Bald Eagle that appeared over Mount Tamalpais and flew right over us before disappearing into the glare of the city.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;- Laura Echávez, GGRO Senior Biotech&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Dayleader: Christine Cariño&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Count Team: Pat Bacchetti, Bob Blumberg, John Davis, Susan Greef, Carmen DeLeon, Laura Echávez&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 268&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 53.6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 10&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 72&lt;br/&gt;
Bald Eagle: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 167&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 5&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20220915" rel="alternate" title="Thursday, September 15, 2022" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20220915" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Laura Echavez</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20220914</id><published>2022-09-14T15:10:22.875-0700</published><updated>2022-09-14T15:10:22.875-0700</updated><title>Wednesday, September 14, 2022</title><content type="html">Well, it came rolling in from the West and did not give way. We got fogged out!  &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Hawkwatchers met on the South side of Rodeo Lagoon to discuss Accipiter ID, hoping that the conversation and consideration would summon them our way. We then took a slow walk along the lagoon, stopping to peak at everything that flickered and flew from Willow to Cypress and back again. As we stood in the middle of a Eucalyptus grove, attempting to get a closer look at a couple of Warblers, a Great-horned Owl spread its wings and flew right above our heads before disappearing behind dense vegetation. We had been standing there for a few minutes or so, and had not noticed our feathered friend perched out on a limb, though it was surely watching us...  &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;-Krista Faucchi, GGRO Assistant Biotechnician &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Dayleaders: Don Bartling &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Count Team: Linda Sudduth, John Davis, Sue Morgan, Jan Ambrosini, Joan Duffield, Krista Fanucchi &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Outreach Support: Tim Stroshane &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20220914" rel="alternate" title="Wednesday, September 14, 2022" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20220914" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Krista Fanucchi</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20220913</id><published>2022-09-13T16:36:53.369-0700</published><updated>2022-09-13T16:36:53.369-0700</updated><title>Tuesday, September 13, 2022</title><content type="html">A thick fog lifted from Hawk Hill just about 9 am this morning, but it was not in a hurry to leave.  The fog wrap lingered throughout the day occasionally obscuring Tamalpais from view, and San Francisco as well.  Gusts from 8 to 20 mph out of the west, and temps from the mid 60's to 70-deg.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Not the break-out Accipiter day we have been waiting for but we did watch a steady stream of Red-tailed Hawks flap, glide, truck, cavort and careen across the sky mostly toward the SW. Other species highlights included 2 Sharp-shinned Hawks, 1 Merlin (first of the year for this little falcon), and an Osprey. In the morning, an adult Peregrine made several long sweeping stoops on the center summit of Hawk Hill trying to budge a too-sturdy covey of California Quail out of their coyote brush. Hats off to prey and predator for doing their best in this million-year-old dance.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Thanks to GGRO banding manager Teresa Ely, banding dayleader Anne Ardillo, and bander Cricket Raspet, we enjoyed a mid-day banded Red-tailed Hawk release in honor of George Eade, the beloved GGRO volunteer, raptor conservationist and photographer who died in late July.  George's hawk was a intricately field-marked lighter-light morph juv Redtail that calmly rose from Teresa's release into the eye-level of the Hawkwatch, then spent some 5-10 mins just stilling next to Hawk Hill, eight binocular pairs transfixed.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Dayleaders: Andy Bradshaw, Mary Kenney&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Count Team: Chris Tarr, Rich Eliason, Dan Foldes, Woody Woodbury, Jody Newman, Allen Fish&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 167&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 4.5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 37.1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 7&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 35&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 121&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20220913" rel="alternate" title="Tuesday, September 13, 2022" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20220913" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Allen Fish</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20220912</id><published>2022-09-12T16:50:44.927-0700</published><updated>2022-09-12T16:50:44.927-0700</updated><title>Monday, September 12, 2022</title><content type="html">Hawk Hill was cloaked in fog this morning, leading hawkwatchers to begin the day with the familiar discussion of "I think it is just about to lift" ... "We must be right on the edge of the fog" ... "It will definitely clear out soon" ... and my personal favorite "I really have no clue what the fog is about to do". &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;West winds eventually picked up around noon and we enjoyed a solid 4-hour count. Red-tailed Hawks were seen hovering above Slacker ridge, stooping beyond middle kingdom, and soaring high overhead before trailing off in the direction of the Golden Gate Bridge. A Peregrine falcon was spotted in the Slacker saddle, and three Osprey gave hawkwatchers quite the show as they soared steadily in wide circles over Hawk Hill and beyond.  &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The last bird of the day was also the only Accipiter we saw today! Coops, Sharpies, where are you at?  &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;-Krista Fanucchi, GGRO Assistant Biotechnician &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Dayleaders: Deborah Crooks, Linda Schneider &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Count Team: Linda Chambers, Peter Sapienza, Denise Peck, Wade Eakle, Krista Fanucchi &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 223&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 55.75&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 75&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 140&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 3&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20220912" rel="alternate" title="Monday, September 12, 2022" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20220912" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Krista Fanucchi</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20220911</id><published>2022-09-11T17:08:42.756-0700</published><updated>2022-09-11T17:08:42.756-0700</updated><title>Sunday, September 11, 2022</title><content type="html">What a beautiful day it was on the Hill today. The day started with an easy breeze and fog mantled over the entrance to the San Francisco Bay. For the first couple of hours, our Hawkwatch team saw a steady trickle of Redtails and Turkey Vultures, but we were hoping for some species variety -and, geez, did the raptors deliver!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This has been an unusually low year for Accipiters, particularly Cooper's and Sharp-shinned Hawks. So when a juvenile Cooper's Hawk flew in a from the west and then rose over the north quadrant, all those atop Hawk Hill cheered with excitement. Then, not ten minutes after, a Swainson's Hawk rose from Gerbode Valley and circled higher with a few juvenile Redtails. Lastly, to top off the hour, a distant Osprey flew over Alcatraz Island, decidedly making its way south for the winter. The final hour of the count brought more highlights, including Peregrine Falcons and a misty Northern Harrier.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;As the team was leaving Hawk Hill, an adult Cooper's Hawk flew right over us -could this be a sign of the Coops and Sharpies yet to come?&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;- Laura Echávez, GGRO Senior Biotech&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Dayleader: Becky Olsen &amp; Ken Wilson&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Count Team: Paul Meadow, Maggie Montenegro, Ana Maria Olivar, Kinley Renger, Carol Weinstein, Laura Echávez&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 121&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 30.3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 7&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 28&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Swainson's Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 82&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 5&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20220911" rel="alternate" title="Sunday, September 11, 2022" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20220911" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Laura Echavez</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20220910</id><published>2022-09-10T17:05:12.269-0700</published><updated>2022-09-10T17:05:12.269-0700</updated><title>Saturday, September 10, 2022</title><content type="html">Dense fog kept hawkwatchers from Hawk Hill this AM, so we spent the morning among the Wilson's Warblers and river otters along the south side of Rodeo Lagoon until the fog began to lift around noon.  &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Back up on Hawk Hill, gusts of 15-20 mph sent Red-tailed Hawks up and over Slacker ridge, down into Gerbode Valley, summersaulting over our heads, and trailing off into the mist. A couple of Cooper's Hawks, steady in flight and somewhat unfazed by the wind, were seen among a group of Red-tailed hawks and tumbling Ravens.  &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;One distant falcon was seen only moments before disappearing into a veil of heavy mist... Out of sight, but surely not out of mind... &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;-Krista Fanucchi, GGRO Assistant Biotechnician &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Dayleader: Jane Rudebusch &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Count Team: Mary Malec, Lora Roeme, Michael Voeltz, Jennifer Miller, Maryrose Kulick, Krista Fanucchi &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 123&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 2.17&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 56.7&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 36&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 83&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 2&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20220910" rel="alternate" title="Saturday, September 10, 2022" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20220910" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Krista Fanucchi</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20220909</id><published>2022-09-09T18:44:56.266-0700</published><updated>2022-09-09T18:44:56.266-0700</updated><title>Friday, September 09, 2022</title><content type="html">Hazy and brown-tinged fog in the AM turned to big blustery west winds in the PM, and with the bluster came a steady parade of Redtails.  Temps peaked at 70-degrees. Winds at 15 mph.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Hawkish highlights included: Peregrines and Kestrels, a juv Redshoulder against the GG Bridge, a close beak-to-nose view of an Osprey contouring Hawk Hill, two more mile-away Ospreys circling each other against the backdrop of the Pacific Ocean. And lots and lots of juv Redtails. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Accipiters are still few and far far far between - hoping that the next few days the weather will be set up for a breakout Coop + Sharpshin flight.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Today was a five Osprey day. Wonderful for us, bad for the fish.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;- Allen Fish&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Dayleaders: Horacio Mena, Holly Thomas&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Count Team: Connor Cimmiyotti, Will Ludan, Tomas McKay, Mitch Green, Paulette Sherry, Allen Fish&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 150&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 4.75&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 31.6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 7&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 30&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 105&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 2&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20220909" rel="alternate" title="Friday, September 09, 2022" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20220909" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Allen Fish</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20220908</id><published>2022-09-08T16:27:14.053-0700</published><updated>2022-09-08T16:27:14.053-0700</updated><title>Thursday, September 08, 2022</title><content type="html">It was another stifling morning for the Hawkwatch crew. At 10 am, the temperature atop Hawk Hill wavered just below 90-degrees F, and the wind was nonexistent. We were convinced our count would be cut short. Fortunately, the wind slowly picked up after an hour or so, and the temperature ranged from the upper 70s to mid 80s for the rest of the day.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;However, not even the 10-mph winds could lift enough raptors today. After an exciting look at a distant Cooper's Hawk over Slacker Ridge, we only saw Redtails and Turkey Vultures the entire day. We can only look forward to the birds to come!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;- Laura Echávez, GGRO Senior Biotech&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Dayleader: Gretchen Zantzinger&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Count Team: Bob Blumberg, Pat Contaxis, Michaela Figari, Jim Yampolsky, Pauline Yeckley, Laura Echávez&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 108&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 21.6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 53&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 52&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 2&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20220908" rel="alternate" title="Thursday, September 08, 2022" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20220908" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Laura Echavez</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20220907</id><published>2022-09-07T16:06:08.365-0700</published><updated>2022-09-07T16:06:08.365-0700</updated><title>Wednesday, September 07, 2022</title><content type="html">The Hawkwatch team began the count with temps in the upper sixties and fog draping over San Francisco -a welcomed break in the heat after the wicked heat of the last few days! The steady 10mph wind brought a constant stream of Red-tailed Hawks and Turkey Vultures. We thought we would not see other species, but in the second half of the day we saw a couple of Cooper's Hawks, Red-shouldered Hawks, and American Kestrels (male &amp; female)!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Another highlight was a young couple from San Francisco that was visiting Hawk Hill for the first time and so excited to learn about the migration happening right in their backyard! Have you had a chance to enjoy the raptor migration? Peak is just around the corner so it's about to get even better!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;- Laura Echávez, GGRO Senior Biotech&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Dayleader: Don Bartling&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Count Team: Stefanie Arthur, John Davis, Sue Morgan, Laura Echávez&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 347&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 69.4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 126&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 212&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 2&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20220907" rel="alternate" title="Wednesday, September 07, 2022" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20220907" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Laura Echavez</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20220906</id><published>2022-09-06T14:19:11.560-0700</published><updated>2022-09-06T14:19:11.560-0700</updated><title>Tuesday, September 06, 2022</title><content type="html">GGRO Hawkwatch was cancelled today due to high temps. The team was ready for a solid early-season migration this morning, but the "Dome of Heat" had other plans for the California Coast.  At 10 am, the temp on Hawk Hill was hovering around the 94-degree mark, with increasing (and very hot) wind from the East. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Dayleaders: Mary Kenney, Catherine Elliott&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Count Team: Maureen Grabowski, Woody Woodbury, Tom Luster, Allen Fish&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20220906" rel="alternate" title="Tuesday, September 06, 2022" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20220906" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Allen Fish</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20220905</id><published>2022-09-05T13:07:27.585-0700</published><updated>2022-09-05T13:07:27.585-0700</updated><title>Monday, September 05, 2022</title><content type="html">Well, we can consider a highlight of the day being the fact that we ended the count early in order to stay safe and escape the scorching heat. Temperatures on Hawk Hill were hovering around 86F-87F at 11am, and reached 90F before noon.  &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;However, we still enjoyed some bird sightings! Vaux's Swifts, White-throated Swifts, and Black Swifts were seen flying, dancing, high up into the sky and trailed off as specks. I am hoping everyone can find some refuge in a cool, shady, breezy location as we move through more days of harsh heat. Until next time!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;-Krista Fanucchi, GGRO Assistant Biotechnician &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Dayleaders: James McDermott &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Count Team: Linda Schneider, Roy Pisetsky, Deborah Crooks, Jan Ambrosini, Kimberlie Moutoux, Krista Fanucchi &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 11&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 1.5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 7.3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 3&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20220905" rel="alternate" title="Monday, September 05, 2022" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20220905" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Krista Fanucchi</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20220904</id><published>2022-09-04T17:23:52.365-0700</published><updated>2022-09-04T17:23:52.365-0700</updated><title>Sunday, September 04, 2022</title><content type="html">There was little to no escape from the stifling, unforgiving heat of the day. Alright, alright - it was only 85F, but there was no denying that it...was...hot... Today's weather conditions were an excellent reminder to take it slow, stay in tune with your body, and hydrate!  &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The birds seemed to be hunkered down for the late morning/early afternoon when the wind speed was very minimal, but we did observe a couple or Red-shouldered Hawks riding Slacker ridge before they trailed off further south. Things did start to pick up with the breeze around 1:00pm; some notable species being an adult male Northern Harrier (or "grey ghost"), a few Cooper's Hawks, a couple of Osprey, and a Peregrine Falcon. Although, to be fair, we consider all bird sightings to be alluring and special! Oh, and monarch butterflies! Looking forward to whatever comes our way...  &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;-Krista Fanucchi, GGRO Assistant Biotechnician &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Dayleaders: Sam Hontalas &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Count Team: Laura Coatney, Melissa Hohner, Rod Santos, Courtney Buechert, Ryan Overhiser, Krista Fanucchi, Allen Fish &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 188&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 37.60&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 7&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 61&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 104&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 14&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20220904" rel="alternate" title="Sunday, September 04, 2022" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20220904" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Krista Fanucchi</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20220903</id><published>2022-09-03T17:24:04.141-0700</published><updated>2022-09-03T17:24:04.141-0700</updated><title>Saturday, September 03, 2022</title><content type="html">We started the day with a distant haze carried by a barely-there 1.4-mph northerly breeze -though the sky was clear and blue all around us. At around 70F, the top of Hawk Hill felt balmy, but fortunately, temperatures did not rise over 80F, and cool winds kept us comfortable as we watched the Red-tailed Hawks passing through.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Today's flight was somewhat slow and the hawkwatch team wondered if all raptors had decided to boycott the migration. However, we did have some exciting highlights. We had a great view of an Osprey that flew at eye-level and hugged the north-northeast side of the Hill. We also saw a couple of Kestrels, one of which was showing off its acrobatic abilities while swooping over a young Redtail. Lastly, after rumors of Sharp-shinned Hawk sightings around the Headlands, we finally saw a Sharpshin during the official count! The accipiters are arriving to the Hill!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;- Laura Echávez, GGRO Senior Biotechnician&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Dayleaders: Mary Malec &amp; Brian O'Laughlin&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Count Team: Jeff Boissier, Alex Cox, Rasia Holzman Smith, JJ Harris, Melissa Hero, Allen Fish, Laura Echávez&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 134&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 26.8&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 36&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 89&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 4&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20220903" rel="alternate" title="Saturday, September 03, 2022" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20220903" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Laura Echavez</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20220902</id><published>2022-09-02T16:15:54.585-0700</published><updated>2022-09-02T16:15:54.585-0700</updated><title>Friday, September 02, 2022</title><content type="html">Threats of heat never materialized today in the Marin Headlands as the fog clung to the west-facing ridges til noon. The hawkwatch team was right there at the point of clearing for a ridiculous and spectacular break-out flight of juvenile Red-tailed Hawks. Essentially one per minute for the first two hours.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;A few other species rounded out the day - several great Red-shouldered Hawk views, a handful of Coopers. We have still no Sharpshins on the official count, although a few have been seen around the valley this week. And today, 15 mins after closing the count, a Redtail and Osprey thermaled up together over the Rifle Range and shot the gap east of Hawk Hill heading for parts far to the south.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;-	Allen Fish&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Dayleaders: Libby Rouan, Holly Thomas&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Count Team: Horacio Mena, Sonja Raub, Yvette MacDonald, Laura Thomas, Connor Cimmiyotti, Allen Fish&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 187&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 62.3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 24&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 154&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20220902" rel="alternate" title="Friday, September 02, 2022" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20220902" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Allen Fish</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20220901</id><published>2022-09-01T17:49:55.158-0700</published><updated>2022-09-01T17:49:55.158-0700</updated><title>Thursday, September 01, 2022</title><content type="html">As we made our way up to Hawk Hill, a blanket of fog enveloped Gerbode Valley and the mouth of the San Francisco Bay, the still air trapping the velvety inversion layer.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;It was a quiet morning. During the first hour of the count, we had more non-raptor sightings than anything else as flocks of Band-tailed Pigeons, White-throated Swifts, and Blue-gray Gnatcatchers rushed by. We enjoyed a handful of Turkey Vultures, several Red-tailed Hawks, and a sprinkle of novelty species for the team: one Cooper's Hawk, one Northern Harrier, and an American Kestrel. The second hour of the day brought flurries of Redtails, mostly juveniles that zigzagged back and forth over Slacker Ridge -foreshadowing the theme of the day... However, it also brought an exciting bird and a first for the 2022 season: a Swainson's Hawk! It hugged the count site and lingered around the Hill for quite a while, giving the team plenty of time to "Ooh" and "Ahh" at its fascinating field marks. A cool and gentle northwesterly breeze picked up around noon, and for the rest of the day we mainly saw Redtails, interrupted by a distant Osprey, a Red-shouldered Hawk on a mission, and the occasional Turkey Vulture.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;A handful of visitors enjoyed the sight of the migrating hawks as well -some folks local to California and a small family from as far away as Poland! All in all, it was a beautiful day to be on Hawk Hill!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;- Laura Echávez, GGRO Senior Biotech&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Dayleader: Christine Cariño&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Count Team: Pat Bacchetti, Bob Blumberg, Arden Bucklin-Sporer, John Davis, Susan Greef, Laura Echávez&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 179&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 35.8&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 8&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 39&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Swainson's Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 126&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 4&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20220901" rel="alternate" title="Thursday, September 01, 2022" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20220901" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Laura Echavez</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20220831</id><published>2022-08-31T17:51:05.797-0700</published><updated>2022-08-31T17:51:05.797-0700</updated><title>Wednesday, August 31, 2022</title><content type="html">While the count team was wrapping up the morning meeting, a Sharp-shinned Hawk rose above Hawk Hill and flickered off into the Golden Gate. Did we consider this sighting an early indicator that it would be a great day of Hawk counting? YES we did and it was, truly...  &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Hot weather and light, NW winds put birds high in blue skies for most of the afternoon. A sub-adult Bald Eagle accompanied by two Red-tailed Hawks, a swift Peregrine Falcon, a teetering Northern Harrier, and a high energy American Kestrel reminded me of how incredibly lucky we are to witness migrating raptors.    &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;As I was packing up the gear and heading out for the day, I noticed a person looking intently at the sky with a smile stretched across their face. I turned to see a Juvenile Red-tailed Hawk soaring in a wide circle right above our heads, tilting its wings slightly to catch the breeze as two Ravens positioned themselves right behind the Hawk. This person asked what we were looking at, still smiling wide, and after learning that it was a Red-tail they simply responded "wow, this must be my lucky day", as they stood there staring until the bird lifted and disappeared out of sight. What a gift, to be overcome with gratitude. To be awestruck by a fleeting moment... &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;-Krista Fanucchi, GGRO Assistant Biotechnician &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Dayleaders: Don Bartling, Jon Altemus &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Count Team: Linda Sudduth, John Davis, Sue Morgan, Jan Ambrosini, Joan Duffield, Krista Fanucchi &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 243&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 48.6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 9&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 51&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Bald Eagle: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 10&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 158&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 10&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 11&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20220831" rel="alternate" title="Wednesday, August 31, 2022" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20220831" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Krista Fanucchi</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20220830</id><published>2022-08-30T16:22:58.987-0700</published><updated>2022-08-30T16:22:58.987-0700</updated><title>Tuesday, August 30, 2022</title><content type="html">A near-full wrap of fog at 10 am turned to wide open skies by 1130, and a continual flyby of Red-tailed Hawks for the whole day - with a great assortment of other characters.  Highlights included a juv Peregrine which made several visits and flashed its sooty colors, a stunningly close juv Bald Eagle with tiny little Redtails escorting it from Hawk Hill out over Kirby Cove.  Eight species in all. Temps stayed at or under 70-degrees, and gusts up to 15 mph never relented.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Awesome to have Brian Westlund (NatureBridge) and Francis Taroc (Parks Conservancy) up on Hawk Hill today with 23 new NatureBridge instructors for the annual 2022 teacher training in the Middle Platform. Nature Bridge has been a 40-year partner with GGRO, having brought kids up to Hawk Hill since the early 1980s to teach them about migration, raptor ecology and conservation, species identification, and community science.  &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Dayleader: Mary Kenney&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Count Team: Dan Foldes, Woody Woodbury, Rich Eliason, Jody Newman, Allen Fish&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 135&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 4.5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 30&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 8&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 40&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Bald Eagle: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 87&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20220830" rel="alternate" title="Tuesday, August 30, 2022" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20220830" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Allen Fish</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20220829</id><published>2022-08-29T17:59:59.402-0700</published><updated>2022-08-29T17:59:59.402-0700</updated><title>Monday, August 29, 2022</title><content type="html">We started off the day with a high fog ceiling that dispersed around noon, revealing some of the familiar geographic features and landmarks that have been obstructed from our view over the past few days. As the wind started to pick up, so did the birds!  &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The count team enjoyed the opportunity to observe a few Cooper's Hawks and a Northern Harrier, as well as the familiar Red-tailed Hawks and Turkey Vultures. Birds were spotted in distant kettles over Mount Tam and Hill 88, then dispersed into glides overhead and swiftly disappeared over Lands End and beyond.   &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;-Krista Fanucchi, GGRO Assistant Biotechnician &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Dayleaders: Deborah Crooks, Linda Schneider &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Count Team: Linda Chambers, Patty Lessard, Peter Sapienza, Denise Peck, Krista Fanucchi &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 171&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 34.2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 58&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 108&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20220829" rel="alternate" title="Monday, August 29, 2022" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20220829" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Krista Fanucchi</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20220828</id><published>2022-08-28T17:25:27.796-0700</published><updated>2022-08-28T17:25:27.796-0700</updated><title>Sunday, August 28, 2022</title><content type="html">A magical sight from Hawk Hill: pockets of blue sky! After holding our breath while submerged in fog for 5 days, the western winds pushed the rolling mist high above the Hill.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Although some of the fog swirled around us -threatening to completely obstruct our view- for nearly 4 hours, our team enjoyed the teetering Turkey Vultures and soaring Red-tailed Hawks. Around 1pm, an adult Redtail rose in front of Angel Island and quickly turned, stooping for a critter too small for our team to see. When it took flight again, its talons held proof of its hunting attempt!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The end of August (and Fogust) approaches, and the warmer weather that follows will surely bring many raptors on their south-bound journey. Stay tuned!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;- Laura Echávez, GGRO Senior Biotech&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Dayleader: Becky Olsen &amp; Ken Wilson&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Count Team: Paul Meadow, Maggie Montenegro, Kinley Renger, Carol Weinstein, Laura Echávez&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 43&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 3.83&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 11.2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 24&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 18&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20220828" rel="alternate" title="Sunday, August 28, 2022" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20220828" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Laura Echavez</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20220827</id><published>2022-08-27T16:26:59.930-0700</published><updated>2022-08-27T16:26:59.930-0700</updated><title>Saturday, August 27, 2022</title><content type="html">I am sitting here, reaching for another way to describe the dense white mist; that creeping and persistent "thing". It is as if Hawk Hill has been so wrapped up in fog that it simply refuses to let go. I believe there is some sort of hidden shackle, binding these two. Or perhaps it is just... Foggy!  &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Retreat to East Rodeo Lagoon! The Hawk count team observed Red-necked Phalaropes swimming in tight circles and Black Phoebes darting out to catch insects' midair. We watched Common Yellowthroats bounce around through thick vegetation as we mulled over the familiar question of "I wonder what the weather is looking like up on the hill"... Am I bitter? No, still feeling lucky to be immersed in it all. Looking forward to more birds overhead soon! &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;-Krista Fanucchi, GGRO Assistant Biotechnician &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Dayleaders: Jane Rudebusch &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Count Team: Mary Malec, Lora Roeme, Michael Voeltz, Maryrose Kulick, Krista Fanucchi &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20220827" rel="alternate" title="Saturday, August 27, 2022" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20220827" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Krista Fanucchi</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20220826</id><published>2022-08-26T18:10:56.820-0700</published><updated>2022-08-26T18:10:56.820-0700</updated><title>Friday, August 26, 2022</title><content type="html">Today gave us another Marin Headlands fog-drape of Hawk Hill and the surrounding peaks; a white-out complete with authentic, wet moisture on the ground.  &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The Friday GGRO count team passed some time at Rodeo Lagoon and had great looks at River Otters (6), Red-necked Phalaropes (26), Common Yellowthroats (6), Marsh Wrens (2), and singles of many other species: Long-billed Curlew, Greater Yellowlegs, Red-tailed Hawk, a fabulous Peregrine Falcon flyby, and lots of the regulars: egrets, herons, scrub habitat songbirds, cormorants.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The hawkwatchers did make it up to Hawk Hill by noon and we did every dance imaginable to get the fog to retreat, but temperature, wind, and ocean are far greater powers, and we called it an official fog-out at 1 pm. Perhaps a clear Hill tomorrow?&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I am thinking today of the thickest fog and the wildest birds. I am thinking of one of my oldest and dearest Marin Headlands naturalist friends, Laura Pettibone, who died earlier this week. Feeling still and alert to old things, I re-found this Robinson Jeffers poem, aptly titled "Fog":&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Invisible gulls with human voices cry in the sea-cloud&lt;br/&gt;"There is room, wild minds,&lt;br/&gt;Up high in the cloud; the web and the feather remember&lt;br/&gt;Three elements, but here&lt;br/&gt;Is but one, and the webs and the feathers&lt;br/&gt;Subduing but the one&lt;br/&gt;Are the greater, with strength and to spare."&lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;-	Allen Fish&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Dayleaders: Horacio Mena &amp; Holly Thomas&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Count Team: Will Ludan, Paulette Sherry, Conner Cimmiyotti, Tomas McKay, Mitch Green, Allen Fish&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20220826" rel="alternate" title="Friday, August 26, 2022" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20220826" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Allen Fish</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20220825</id><published>2022-08-25T15:49:52.785-0700</published><updated>2022-08-25T15:49:52.785-0700</updated><title>Thursday, August 25, 2022</title><content type="html">Fog stretched 500 feet down the flanks of Hawk Hill at 9 am.  And still at 11 am.  And still at 1 pm.  Yes, this was a NO-GO for GGRO hawkwatching today.  We had no hawk count due to no visibility.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The count team enjoyed a birding trip up the Rodeo Valley Trail, picking up territorial Allen's Hummers, Lesser Goldfinches, grumpy Song Sparrows, at least one juv Cooper's Hawk, a few Redtails, and a Peregrine.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;- Allen Fish&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Dayleaders: Christine Carino, Gretchen Zantzinger&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Count Team: Bob Blumberg, Pauline Yeckley, Jim Yampolsky, Michaela Figari, Patricia Contaxis, Allen Fish&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20220825" rel="alternate" title="Thursday, August 25, 2022" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20220825" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Allen Fish</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20220824</id><published>2022-08-24T15:49:57.532-0700</published><updated>2022-08-24T15:49:57.532-0700</updated><title>Wednesday, August 24, 2022</title><content type="html">It was a great day for a detour! With Hawk Hill submerged in fog well after 1pm, we took our binoculars to a more active location: East Rodeo Lagoon! The usual Brown Pelican pod bobbed on the surface while the Red-necked Phalaropes foraged in the pungent waters of the lagoon. Meanwhile, a river otter weaseled its way around the raft of pelicans as it gnawed on some shelled creatures. Great Egrets, Snowy Egrets, a Great Blue Heron, Barn Swallows, a Black Phoebe, and Common Yellowthroats were also a part of the show.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This is a hawkwatch team, however, and raptors were indeed the highlight for today! Hoping to see signs of clearer skies on Hawk Hill, our team ventured into Gerbode Valley, and came across a family of Great Horned Owls! We heard begging calls from the juveniles, but the parents did not entertain their requests.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;- Laura Echávez, GGRO Senior Biotech&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Dayleader: Don Bartling&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Count Team: Stefanie Arthur, John Davis, Sue Morgan&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20220824" rel="alternate" title="Wednesday, August 24, 2022" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20220824" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Laura Echavez</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20220823</id><published>2022-08-23T18:34:38.743-0700</published><updated>2022-08-23T18:34:38.743-0700</updated><title>Tuesday, August 23, 2022</title><content type="html">Big Pacific winds gusting to 15 mph and a persistent fog in the west kept us on our toes today.  The juvenile Red-tailed Hawks owned the skies over Hawk and Slacker Hills.  We were thrilled to catch sight a few Cooper's Hawks following the Redtails up in the thermals. And glimpsed in turn at least one Kestrel that dive-bombed everyone within 50 meters out of Slacker Ridge.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Still waiting for the Sharp-shinned Hawk flight which usually kicks in the first week of September. Come visit Hawk Hill for some raptor watching in early September!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;-	Allen Fish&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Dayleaders: Catherine Elliott &amp; Mary Kenney&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Count Team: Tom Luster, Woody Woodbury, Maureen Grabowski, Dennis Davison, Allen Fish&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 86&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 3.5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 24.6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 38&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 44&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20220823" rel="alternate" title="Tuesday, August 23, 2022" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20220823" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Allen Fish</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20220822</id><published>2022-08-22T17:50:35.127-0700</published><updated>2022-08-22T17:50:35.127-0700</updated><title>Monday, August 22, 2022</title><content type="html">The morning started clear on Hawk Hill then fogged, then clear then - you get the idea.  We started the day's count at 11 am with mostly clear skies. The juvenile Red-tailed Hawks came slowly at first then picked up with the heat and wind after 1 pm.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Highlights of the day included two Osprey that ran the length of Slacker Ridge, circling and flying above and side by side each other. They hit glides high above Battery Spencer and sailed into San Francisco, and - who knows how far south?  Some Pacific NW Osprey fly to Chile!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Highlight #2: an adult Peregrine skimmed the West Quadrant at the end of the count day. Thank you very much.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;-	Allen Fish&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Dayleader: James McDermott&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Count Team: Linda Schneider, Roy Pisetsky, Deborah Crooks, Jan Ambrosini, Kimberlie Moutoux, Cheryl Lentini, Allen Fish&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 123&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 30.75&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 55&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 54&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 7&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20220822" rel="alternate" title="Monday, August 22, 2022" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20220822" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Allen Fish</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20220821</id><published>2022-08-21T16:05:38.984-0700</published><updated>2022-08-21T16:05:38.984-0700</updated><title>Sunday, August 21, 2022</title><content type="html">The hawkwatchers' abilities to be flexible, patient, and "go with the flow", really rang true today. Hawk Hill was capped in a thick layer of fog for most of the morning, and only around noon did we get some glimpses of life beyond the white blanket.  &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Today's count consisted of Turkey Vultures and Red-tailed Hawks at a rate of 7.2 birds per hour. A couple of ravens on Slacker ridge had us wondering, but their acrobatic flight and tumbling play gave them away... Until next time! &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;-Krista Fanucchi, GGRO Assistant Biotechnician &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Dayleaders: Dennis Davison, Sam Hontalas &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Count Team: Laura Coatney, Melissa Kohner, Rod Santos, Courtney Buechert, Ryan Overhiser, Krista Fanucchi, Allen Fish &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 12&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 1.67&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 7.2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 5&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20220821" rel="alternate" title="Sunday, August 21, 2022" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20220821" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Krista Fanucchi</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20220820</id><published>2022-08-20T15:38:07.369-0700</published><updated>2022-08-20T15:38:07.369-0700</updated><title>Saturday, August 20, 2022</title><content type="html">The drive into the Marin Headlands this morning, foggy with pockets of blue skies peeking through, gave our counters optimism for the hours to come -it did not last long.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;We began our count at 11am. Despite the wall of fog creeping up to the north and west of the Hill, an adult Red-tailed Hawk flew out of the haze and within 50 meters of the team, showing off a beautiful red tail with varying feather lengths that had not finished molting yet. We got fleeting looks at several other redtails and a handful of Turkey Vultures, but by 1:30pm the fog drove us out when it completely enveloped the Hill. In the words of one of our Saturday dayleaders: "Our team took the prize for the most fog seen on Hawk Hill this week!"&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;- Laura Echávez, GGRO Senior Biotech&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Dayleaders: Mary Malec &amp; Brian O'Laughlin&lt;br/&gt;Count Team: Jeff Boissier, Alex Cox, Laura Echávez, Rasia Holzman Smith, JJ Harris, Melissa Hero&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 11&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 2.5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 4.4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20220820" rel="alternate" title="Saturday, August 20, 2022" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20220820" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Laura Echavez</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20220819</id><published>2022-08-19T17:00:36.273-0700</published><updated>2022-08-19T17:00:36.273-0700</updated><title>Friday, August 19, 2022</title><content type="html">Thick fog with a ceiling of about 10 feet wrapped around Hawk Hill from top to bottom this AM.  We attempted to wait out the fog by checking out birds at Rodeo Lagoon, but the Hill stayed socked in til after 1 pm, rendering this day the first "fog out" of 2022 fall migration count.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;A good smattering of species down at East Rodeo Lagoon including: the endlessly entertaining Red-necked Phalaropes, (no Wilson's today), Northern Rough-winged and Barn Swallows Great Blue Heron, Black-crowned Night-Heron, Snowy and Great Egrets, Wilson Warbler, Black Phoebe, Common Yellowthroat, Lesser Goldfinch, Purple Finch, Pygmy Nuthatch, Nuttall's and Hairy Woodpeckers, and many many many Brown Pelicans crowded onto the GB Heron Peninsula and generally making a ruckus.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;-	Allen Fish&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Dayleaders: Libby Rouan, Holly Thomas&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Count Team: Sonja Raub, Conner Cimmiyotti, Horacio Mena, Yvette MacDonald&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20220819" rel="alternate" title="Friday, August 19, 2022" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20220819" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Allen Fish</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20220818</id><published>2022-08-18T16:32:20.680-0700</published><updated>2022-08-18T16:32:20.680-0700</updated><title>Thursday, August 18, 2022</title><content type="html">Today's westerly winds reached ~20 miles per hour gusts that pulled the fog in and out all around us. The limited visibility rendered a somewhat slow day, however, even on the slowest of days, you can always count on Turkey Vultures and Red-tailed Hawks to make an appearance.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Around midday, the teetering fog allowed us to get good views east of the Hill, where we spotted a dark morph juvenile Redtail circling high over Angel Island! Not too long after that, a Red-shouldered Hawk and a Cooper's Hawk also came into view. The highlight of the day was an adult Peregrine Falcon that materialized out of nowhere and stayed long enough for us to appreciate its beautiful slate-colored plumage. All in all, we had the highest number of species for our 2022 Hawkwatch day thus far and we're excited for the migrants that are slowly but surely making their way down the Pacific Flyway!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;- Laura Echávez, GGRO Senior Biotech&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Dayleader: Christine Cariño&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Count Team: Pat Bacchetti, Bob Blumberg, Arden Bucklin-Sporer, Laura Echavez, Allen Fish&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 59&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 3.67&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 16.1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 34&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 21&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20220818" rel="alternate" title="Thursday, August 18, 2022" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20220818" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Laura Echavez</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20220817</id><published>2022-08-17T17:21:28.826-0700</published><updated>2022-08-17T17:21:28.826-0700</updated><title>Wednesday, August 17, 2022</title><content type="html">Rain! Sunshine! Fog! A flash of Blue Sky! Hawks! The weather up on Hawk Hill today was erratic, at one moment you had your eyes fixed on something, and the next your view was obstructed by a dense layer of fog. Strong, steady winds had some of us questioning our decision to only bring a few extra layers up to Hawk Hill for the day. One thing is for sure, the gusts shook us to our core and reminded us that migration is on.  &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;For today's count, we observed 20.5 birds per hour. Red-tailed Hawks and Turkey Vultures appeared in kettles of up to 7 birds at a time over Slacker ridge and rose steadily beyond the Golden Gate bridge. A Cooper's Hawk blew up and over the hill and disappeared in a glide and into a veil of fog. A Northern Harrier, with its fluid and relaxed wingbeats, was seen carrying off a western fence lizard.  &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Dayleaders: Don Bartling, Jon Altemus &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Count Team: Linda Sudduth, John Davis, Sue Morgan, Jan Ambrosini, Joan Duffield, Krista Fanucchi &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Outreach Support: Tim Stroshane &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 82&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 20.5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 34&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 44&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20220817" rel="alternate" title="Wednesday, August 17, 2022" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20220817" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Krista Fanucchi</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20220816</id><published>2022-08-16T18:42:23.342-0700</published><updated>2022-08-16T18:42:23.342-0700</updated><title>Tuesday, August 16, 2022</title><content type="html">Today's GGRO hawkwatch was greeted by warm, still skies, but gradually turned to a fog-wrap with a 300 ft-ceiling on three sides of us and gusts up to 13 mph. The great finger of Pacific fog extended into the Golden Gate and had piled up against the center span by 2 pm.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;We had a decent count day with more than 26 raptors per hour (rph) driven by gangs of juvenile Redtails, as many as six in a kettle at once.  A few Cooper's Hawks made early-season appearances, and an adult Peregrine capped the day at just 5 mins before quitting time. This blue-backed falcon zoomed onto the Pt. Diablo slope and then soared above Kirby Cove for a long 3 mins, before disappearing to the south. Lots of Blue-Gray Gnatcatchers about as well.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Hawk Hill visitors today were from Oakland; Berkeley; Davis; Toronto, Canada; Toulouse, France; London, UK; and Moscow, Russia. One morning highlight was meeting Ricardo, a Parisian man riding his motorcycle from NW Territories to Argentina in 5 months. We marveled that he was matching the migration of our longest distance species - the Peregrine Falcons. He was happy to attach a GGRO sticker to the back of his bike. The Golden Gate People Observatory.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;-	Allen Fish&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;Dayleaders&lt;/b&gt;: Mary Kenney, Andy Bradshaw&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;Count team&lt;/b&gt;: Christine Tarr, Dan Foldes, Rich Eliason, Wayne Woodbury, Jody Newman&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 103&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 25.75&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 38&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 60&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20220816" rel="alternate" title="Tuesday, August 16, 2022" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20220816" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Allen Fish</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20220815</id><published>2022-08-15T18:14:18.260-0700</published><updated>2022-08-15T18:14:18.260-0700</updated><title>Monday, August 15, 2022</title><content type="html">A great first day of the 2022 season with a casual flight of "regulars" including  one of each Kestrel. Thick fog clung to the western face of Hawk Hill til 1 pm, then kept the Headlands a cool 70-degrees while the 360-degree view opened up in the afternoon. Nice to catch an Osprey riding down Slacker Ridge heading for the Golden Gate and parts south....&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;We collectively dedicate this 2022 Golden Gate migration season to the memory of George Eade, beloved friend, conservationist, photographer, outdoor educator, and raptor ecologist. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;- Allen Fish&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;Dayleaders&lt;/b&gt;: Deborah Crooks, Linda Schneider&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;Count Team&lt;/b&gt;: Linda Chambers, Patty Lessard, Peter Sapienza, Wade Eakle, Denise Peck, Cheryl Lentini, Krista Fanucchi, Allen Fish&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;Outreach support&lt;/b&gt;: Holly Thomas&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 73&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 3.5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 20.9&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 42&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 28&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 2&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20220815" rel="alternate" title="Monday, August 15, 2022" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20220815" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Allen Fish</name></author></entry>

</feed>