<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><?xml-stylesheet href='http://www.blogger.com/styles/atom.css' type='text/css'?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/">
    <id>hydromatic-ggro</id>
    <updated>2019-10-01T17:54:44.093-0700</updated>
    <title type="text">GGRO daily hawkwatch update</title>
    <link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml" rel="next" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml" rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#feed" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <author>
      <name>GGRO</name>
      <uri>http://www.ggro.org</uri>
      <email>ggro@parksconservancy.org</email>
    </author>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20191001</id><published>2019-10-01T16:53:41.372-0700</published><updated>2019-10-01T16:53:40.372-0700</updated><title>Tuesday, October 01, 2019</title><content type="html">The skies were clear of fog and raptors as we started our count this morning. A noisy flock of Cedar Waxwings buzzed over the hill, entertaining the hawkwatchers with their boisterous chatter. The Accipiter flight picked up in the early afternoon, along with some other exciting species. Soaring between a group of Turkey Vultures loomed an enormous, plank-winged raptor. With the whole team working the mystery bird, it suddenly banked and flashed its clean white tail with a dark subterminal band - it was a juvenile Golden Eagle! Within the last half an hour of the count, a White-tailed Kite appeared over Rodeo Lagoon and soared with two young Sharp-shinned Hawks. Moments later, a flash of blue and orange caught our eye: a male American Kestrel swooped through the West Quadrant and became our first falcon sighting of the day. Even though we only saw sparse flurries of birds at a time, we were thrilled to get a diversity of species over the course of the day.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 257&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5.83&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 44.08&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 11&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 102&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 2&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 9&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 49&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 54&lt;br/&gt;
Golden Eagle: 1&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 18&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 31&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20191001" rel="alternate" title="Tuesday, October 01, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20191001" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Veronica Pedraza &amp; Emma Regnier</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190930</id><published>2019-09-30T17:20:35.395-0700</published><updated>2019-09-30T17:30:35.395-0700</updated><title>Monday, September 30, 2019</title><content type="html">We caravanned up to Hawk Hill with the banding teams bright and early to begin our raptor count shortly after 9am. Visibility was excellent in all quadrants, and there was a refreshing breeze blowing off the ocean. A young Broad-winged Hawk nearly slipped past us, until a keen-eyed hawkwatcher noticed it lacked a Red-tail's dark patagial marks. Around mid-morning, South Quadrant spotted a large whale feeding in the Golden Gate. The whale's shorter and more rounded dorsal fin clued us in to the species: Humpback! Seabirds swarmed the water's surface every time the whale emerged until eventually the whale had its fill and disappeared. Just as the afternoon flight of raptors seemed to be slowing down, two juvenile Golden Eagles soared into view from over Sausalito Ridge! We got some incredible looks at the white patches in their primaries and clean white tails with dark subterminal bands. Moments later, another eagle appeared over Angel Island and cruised along Slacker Ridge. However, this eagle sported a dirty white head and tail, large yellow beak, and lacked white in its primaries - a sub-adult Bald Eagle! We felt very lucky to have the chance to compare the plumages and features of these two impressive raptor species as we wrapped up another great day of hawkwatching.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 322&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 6.33&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 50.87&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 12&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 104&lt;br/&gt;
Bald Eagle: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 28&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 58&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 92&lt;br/&gt;
Golden Eagle: 2&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 11&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 17&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190930" rel="alternate" title="Monday, September 30, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190930" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Maggie Brown &amp; Emma Regnier</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190929</id><published>2019-09-29T16:53:35.871-0700</published><updated>2019-09-29T16:53:35.871-0700</updated><title>Sunday, September 29, 2019</title><content type="html">Clear skies and a breeze from the south welcomed the Sunday I team up to Hawk Hill for a busy morning of counting. The hill was visited by many birds and people, as multiple bird-watching groups joined us for part of the day. An Osprey came out of the North Quadrant and flew close over the hill, giving both the hawkwatchers and visitors a wonderful view of this large raptor. Within the next hour, 3 adult Peregrine Falcons gave a close show for visitors waiting for the Sunday hawk talk, at which a juvenile male Cooper's Hawk wowed the crowd during a raptor release. The day slowed down into the afternoon, but a far juvenile Golden Eagle closed the day out perfectly. We are excited to see what the next days hold!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 448&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 74.67&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 12&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 136&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 55&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 73&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 15&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 119&lt;br/&gt;
Golden Eagle: 1&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 30&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 35&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190929" rel="alternate" title="Sunday, September 29, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190929" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Veronica Pedraza &amp; Paula Eberle</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190928</id><published>2019-09-28T16:28:44.856-0700</published><updated>2019-09-28T16:28:44.856-0700</updated><title>Saturday, September 28, 2019</title><content type="html">There was a lot of hustle and bustle on Hawk Hill today - tons of people and birds were on the move. We were joined on the hill by several local birding groups, who gave us some extra pairs of eyes on a busy day of hawkwatching. The first highlight of the day was a partially leucistic adult Red-tailed Hawk, whose dorsal side resembled the keys on a piano. We were also lucky enough to see two juvenile Ferruginous Hawks today, one of which came overhead in the middle of today's hawk talk! The bird's clean white undersides and "three points of light" were on clear display for all to see. Today was also a busy day for falcons - a dozen Merlins and 8 Peregrine Falcons were sighted throughout the day. We also had a decent movement of Broad-Winged Hawks today, including a dark morph juvenile. All in all, it was a great day of hawkwatching, with more than 500 birds of 13 different species seen today. Both of those figures are seasonal highs thus far. May the good weather and abundant migration continue for many days to come!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 525&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 87.5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 13&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 178&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 44&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 91&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 20&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 121&lt;br/&gt;
Ferruginous Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 12&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 8&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 18&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 29&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190928" rel="alternate" title="Saturday, September 28, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190928" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jeremy Pallant and Paula Eberle</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190927</id><published>2019-09-27T14:15:45.325-0700</published><updated>2019-09-27T14:15:45.325-0700</updated><title>Friday, September 27, 2019</title><content type="html">Despite foggy skies in the early morning, the Friday I team still got up to the hill early with hopes of having a productive day of hawkwatching. For the first hour of counting, conditions looked promising - the low-hanging fog in the valley lifted and there was good visibility in the East, South, and West quadrants. Unfortunately, at about 10:30, winds from the West blew the fog back in and it didn't end up clearing for the remainder of the day. While we waited for the fog to clear, we were lucky enough to see a couple of American Kestrels that made quick passes over the hill before disappearing into the fog again. We also saw a few adult Red-tailed Hawks hugging the low brush beneath the southern platform, looking for prey below. Though our day of counting ended up being short, we still had a great time up on the hill and we're optimistic about having better conditions in two weeks!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 14&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0.83&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 16.87&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 7&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190927" rel="alternate" title="Friday, September 27, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190927" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jeremy Pallant</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190926</id><published>2019-09-26T17:31:10.994-0700</published><updated>2019-09-26T17:31:10.994-0700</updated><title>Thursday, September 26, 2019</title><content type="html">Hawk Hill was surrounded by fog when we arrived this morning, so we patiently waited for the sun to bring us enough visibility to begin our count. The birds must have shared our patience, because just as the fog lifted, our first raptor appeared from the mist: a Merlin! Shortly after, we spotted our first of many flocks of nomadic Band-tailed Pigeons - we ended up counting almost 300 Band-tails over the course of the day. Multiple juvenile Northern Harriers bobbed and weaved their way around the Headlands, adding a little pumpkin spice to this blustery autumn day. We watched as two young harriers snaked their way below Rocky Ridge, just barely skimming the top of the Coyote Brush as they concentrated on hunting. We invited several Nature Bridge school groups to watch for raptors with us and discussed the significance of long-term ecological studies. The students were eager to spot passing birds, and even got a close look at a male American Kestrel as it flew overhead. The team had a fun day and we can't wait to get back up on the hill next time!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 295&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5.5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 53.64&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 8&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 91&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 14&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 15&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 155&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 4&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190926" rel="alternate" title="Thursday, September 26, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190926" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Emma Regnier and Paula Eberle</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190925</id><published>2019-09-25T15:02:27.395-0700</published><updated>2019-09-25T15:02:27.395-0700</updated><title>Wednesday, September 25, 2019</title><content type="html">We started our raptor count with clear skies and a light breeze from the east. Within only a few minutes, we heard the distinctive, raspy calls from two pairs of adult Red-tailed hawks that were circling above Kirby Cove. Among the Red-tails was a juvenile Broad-winged Hawk that soared at eye-level along the hill before gliding overhead and giving everyone great looks at its pale underwings and streaky breast. It was a premonition of what was to come... We were delighted by the appearances of several more Broad-winged Hawks throughout the day, including a dark morph and an adult - sporting its signature black and white tail! To our surprise, we spotted multiple adult birds of several species, including a Swainson's Hawk, Red-shouldered Hawk, dark morph Red-tailed Hawk, Northern Harrier, Cooper's Hawk, and Sharp-shinned Hawk. It was a great learning opportunity for the team to compare the plumages of the adult birds with our usual flight of juveniles. By the early afternoon, we lost our cool breeze and had to end our count early due to the heat. Nonetheless, we are grateful for an exciting day of hawkwatching and wish tomorrow's team some cooler weather!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 307&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 76.75&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 10&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 63&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 19&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 61&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Swainson's Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 129&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 13&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190925" rel="alternate" title="Wednesday, September 25, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190925" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Maggie Brown &amp; Emma Regnier</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190924</id><published>2019-09-24T16:47:03.142-0700</published><updated>2019-09-24T16:47:03.142-0700</updated><title>Tuesday, September 24, 2019</title><content type="html">It was a hot day up on Hawk Hill today, as temperatures wavered in the upper 80's for most of the day. Wind was scarce in the morning, but picked up in the afternoon, which both cooled us off and brought in more birds for us to count. Visibility was excellent all day, as we could even see the ocean beyond the Farallon Islands. There was a fair amount of Accipiter movement to keep us on our toes. Both Sharp-shinned and Cooper's Hawks flew in close to the hill and gave us great looks. We also had a relatively good day for Merlins and Red-shouldered Hawks, of which we saw a handful of each species. We were hoping to see Broad-winged Hawks, but we didn't spot a single one today. In addition to the migrating raptors, there were flocks of migrating passerines flying overhead, including: Vaux's and Black Swifts, Lesser Goldfinches, Band-tailed Pigeons, Cedar Waxwings, Say's Phoebes, and Blue-gray Gnatcatchers. Hoping for an equally busy and productive day for our next time hawkwatching!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 392&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 65.33&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 10&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 129&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 46&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 91&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 83&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 18&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 19&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190924" rel="alternate" title="Tuesday, September 24, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190924" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jeremy Pallant &amp; Emma Regnier</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190923</id><published>2019-09-23T17:08:13.820-0700</published><updated>2019-09-23T17:08:13.820-0700</updated><title>Monday, September 23, 2019</title><content type="html">After a foggy start to our morning, the Monday I team was eager to count some raptors. Once on the hill, we immediately jumped into action since there were many hawks already flying in the clear skies surrounding Hawk Hill. The day was filled with plenty of Accipiters that would pass through in subsequent bursts. We were excited to observe several Broad-winged Hawks, and even got to see a dark morph individual! Another highlight of the day occurred in the early afternoon when hawkwatchers in the West Quadrant spotted a Merlin zoom right over the hill. It came in close and gave us a great view before quickly flying towards the Golden Gate Bridge. While the day was fast-paced, the team stayed on top of everything with good communication and determination. We are grateful for another productive day of hawkwatching!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 404&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 4.25&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 95.06&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 9&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 57&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 87&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 138&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 90&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 13&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 15&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190923" rel="alternate" title="Monday, September 23, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190923" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Maggie Brown &amp; Veronica Pedraza</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190922</id><published>2019-09-22T13:47:05.906-0700</published><updated>2019-09-22T13:47:05.906-0700</updated><title>Sunday, September 22, 2019</title><content type="html">Fog surrounded Hawk Hill today and did not release its grip in time for the Sunday II team to make a count. While initially hopeful after the sunny days of this past week, the team drove up to the Hill to wait out the fog. Small patches of sun greeted us, but Southern winds brought more fog that enveloped the Hill. As we drove back down to the office, a small group of raptors flew next to the road, allowing the team to see a Red-tailed Hawk and some Accipiters. Hopefully the sun returns and this next week is full of raptors!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190922" rel="alternate" title="Sunday, September 22, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190922" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Paula Eberle</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190921</id><published>2019-09-21T16:42:19.973-0700</published><updated>2019-09-21T16:42:19.973-0700</updated><title>Saturday, September 21, 2019</title><content type="html">It was a hot one on the hill today and the raptors were on the move. The Saturday II team had a busy day on the hill, with our total number of raptor sightings approaching 500. We were lucky enough to see ten species, including three species of falcon. Three Merlins were seen from the hill today, and there were also sightings of Peregrine Falcons and American Kestrels of both sexes. Other highlights from the day include two Osprey, two juvenile Red-shouldered Hawks and several juvenile Northern Harriers. All in all, it was a solid day of counting and the Saturday II team was kept on our toes all day long after being fogged out during the first two cycles. Best of luck to all of the hawk watchers as peak ramps up!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 493&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5.92&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 83.28&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 10&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 109&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 74&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 114&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 157&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 12&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 15&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190921" rel="alternate" title="Saturday, September 21, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190921" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jeremy Pallant and Paula Eberle</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190920</id><published>2019-09-20T16:37:27.610-0700</published><updated>2019-09-20T16:37:27.610-0700</updated><title>Friday, September 20, 2019</title><content type="html">Today held clear skies across the bay, giving the Friday II team a warm and wonderful day up on Hawk Hill. Starting off strong, the team saw a Merlin around 9:45 that flew right over the top of the hill and then dove after some prey! While it did not catch what it was aiming for, it was exciting to see the fierce little hunter in action. An adult Red-shouldered Hawk was seen flying low in the North Quadrant, with its vibrant red body and stark black-and-white patterning on its wings. The most exciting bird of the day, however, was an adult Swainson's Hawk. It flew right over the silhouettes, giving the whole team a clear view of the bird's dark flight feathers and dark bib. Hoping for another great day tomorrow!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 343&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5.83&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 58.83&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 11&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 117&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 34&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 57&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Swainson's Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 100&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 13&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190920" rel="alternate" title="Friday, September 20, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190920" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Paula Eberle &amp; Taylor Barnes</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190919</id><published>2019-09-19T16:49:12.046-0700</published><updated>2019-09-19T16:49:12.046-0700</updated><title>Thursday, September 19, 2019</title><content type="html">It was a gorgeous day on Hawk Hill - great visibility, temperatures in the 60s and 70s, and a slight breeze. Because of the excellent conditions, we had plenty of neat avian visitors, both raptor and non-raptor. Our very first sighting of the day was a White-tailed Kite, which hung out for a few minutes over Middle Kingdom before making a very close pass over the hill. It ended up being the first of four kites we saw today, all of which came in relatively close to the hill, much to the delight of the Thursday II hawkwatchers. Later in the morning, we got a terrific view of two adult Peregrine Falcons, which came over the hill chattering and stooping upon one another. Our morning also brought some excellent non-raptor migrants, including three Black Swifts. Our day was capped off by a small flurry of falcons, including a male American Kestrel, which made a quick pass over the hill on his way south and a late afternoon Merlin, which spent several minutes circling the North Tower of the Golden Gate Bridge. All in all, it was a great day of hawkwatching! We're looking forward to meeting again in two weeks, when the heart of peak should be upon us!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 305&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 50.83&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 11&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 119&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 36&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 32&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 86&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 7&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 13&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190919" rel="alternate" title="Thursday, September 19, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190919" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jeremy Pallant and Maggie Brown</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190918</id><published>2019-09-18T13:44:06.930-0700</published><updated>2019-09-18T13:44:06.930-0700</updated><title>Wednesday, September 18, 2019</title><content type="html">To the surprise of both the Hawkwatch and Banding teams, we found ourselves caught in a light rain shower right as we were preparing to leave. Donning raincoats and binoculars, we braved the rain and started birding around the lagoon while waiting for the weather to improve. We spotted a Great Egret fishing alongside a Snowy Egret as we crossed the footbridge onto the beach. A family of Western Bluebirds flitted around the sand, stopping to snatch up small insects. The interns returned to the office to host a visiting group of 5th graders from St. Andrew's School and gave them a presentation on the GGRO's mission and the science of raptor migration. Meanwhile, the rest of the Wednesday II team hiked around the lagoon looking for more birds. They saw one Turkey Vulture, two Red-tailed Hawks, and a Great Horned Owl sleeping in a nearby Eucalyptus tree! The fog refused to lift from Hawk Hill, so we ended our day early, but we have our fingers crossed for better weather in two weeks.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190918" rel="alternate" title="Wednesday, September 18, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190918" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Emma Regnier &amp; Veronica Pedraza</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190917</id><published>2019-09-17T16:59:04.568-0700</published><updated>2019-09-17T16:59:04.568-0700</updated><title>Tuesday, September 17, 2019</title><content type="html">We had clear skies today for the Tuesday II team thanks to a break from the recent fog. Although the morning started off calm and quiet, the breeze soon picked up from the west and carried all types of raptors with it. From Point Bonita, a bright and flashy raptor caught our attention - our team's first White-tailed Kite sighting this season. Several juvenile Red-shouldered Hawks were spotted soaring up above the North Quadrant in the company of Cooper's Hawks and Red-tailed Hawks. We were fortunate to participate in 6 raptor ID studies over the course of the day, which challenged our Accipiter ID skills and generated great discussions. Students from George Moscone Elementary School visited Hawk Hill today as part of their Migratory Story program. The students practiced hawkwatching, experienced a raptor release, and left the hill buzzing with enthusiasm. As the day wound down, the birds kept on coming right up until the end of the official count. Overall, we had a great day of hawkwatching on the hill!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 302&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5.92&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 51.01&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 11&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 99&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 28&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 40&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 12&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 93&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 14&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 18&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190917" rel="alternate" title="Tuesday, September 17, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190917" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Veronica Pedraza &amp; Emma Regnier</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190916</id><published>2019-09-16T16:55:28.978-0700</published><updated>2019-09-16T16:55:28.978-0700</updated><title>Monday, September 16, 2019</title><content type="html">With a decent amount of fog covering the Marin Headlands this morning, we prepared to start watching for hawks near the roundabout on Conzelman Road. Once we reached the base of Hawk Hill, we realized that the sky was clearing overhead, so we made our way to the top to begin our official raptor count. The day was windy with mostly clear skies and plenty of Accipiters to test our ID skills. Fog rolled in a little after noon and completely engulfed the hill by 1:30 pm, which caused us to suspend our count. Feeling defeated by the seemingly never-ending fog, we began preparing to pack up for the day. Just as we were debriefing on the day's hawkwatch, we noticed a small break in the fog that expanded over the course of a few minutes and allowed us to see Rodeo Lagoon in the west and Slacker Hill in the north. With hopeful hearts, we decided to start our count again for the remaining hours of the afternoon. Our perseverance was rewarded with a late-afternoon flurry of raptors, including two Peregrine Falcons! We were glad to finish strong, despite the brief fog intermission.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 241&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 60.25&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 112&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 14&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 16&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 86&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 10&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190916" rel="alternate" title="Monday, September 16, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190916" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Maggie Brown &amp; Emma Regnier</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190915</id><published>2019-09-15T17:02:11.289-0700</published><updated>2019-09-15T17:02:11.289-0700</updated><title>Sunday, September 15, 2019</title><content type="html">Today started off extremely foggy with limited visibility. The hawk watchers remained patient and the fog lifted at 1pm leaving nothing but clear and sunny skies. The Sunday I team was greeted with 215 passing raptors which included two dark morph Broad-winged Hawks! We also had another successful raptor release this weekend at Hawk Hill. An enthusiastic crowd was delighted by the release of a male Cooper's Hawk. It was a great way to end the weekend and we're hopeful this upcoming week will be clearer. &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 215&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 2.5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 86&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 9&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 61&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 41&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 22&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 71&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 11&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190915" rel="alternate" title="Sunday, September 15, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190915" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Taylor Barnes</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190914</id><published>2019-09-14T16:02:30.767-0700</published><updated>2019-09-14T16:02:30.767-0700</updated><title>Saturday, September 14, 2019</title><content type="html">With the sunshine over the past few days initially giving Saturday I high hopes, the weather ultimately changed, causing the team to have a short day out on Hawk Hill. Low fog in the morning hung over Fort Cronkhite, and the team went hiking around Rodeo Lagoon. A couple of Fox Sparrows delighted us with a close viewing as they jumped around in the bushes near the trail. The River Otters were out today as well, playing in the lagoon and splashing around. Around noon the team headed up to the hill as the clouds lifted, giving visibility to each of the quadrants. The fog stayed away long enough to give us the first docent-lead raptor release of the season with a female Cooper's Hawk! She flew off into the fog as it enveloped Hawk Hill once again, cutting the day short. Hopefully the sun shines bright for tomorrow's team!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 120&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 1.67&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 71.86&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 51&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 12&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 47&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 5&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190914" rel="alternate" title="Saturday, September 14, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190914" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Paula Eberle</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190913</id><published>2019-09-13T13:15:23.458-0700</published><updated>2019-09-13T13:15:23.458-0700</updated><title>Friday, September 13, 2019</title><content type="html">It was a scorcher up on Hawk Hill today. By the time we arrived on the hill at about 9:30 AM, temperatures at the hill's summit had climbed past 85 degrees and there was little wind to speak of. By noon, we were experiencing temperatures in excess of 90 degrees, so the Friday I team made a unanimous decision to call off our count early to avoid dehydration and heat stroke. The birds were feeling the heat too - many of our sightings were kettles of birds rising on thermals high above the hill. However, despite our relatively brief count, we still saw more than 120 birds of 6 different species, including a distant Osprey in the middle of the morning and an-eleventh hour Merlin that circled over Mt. Tamalpais as we were getting ready to call it a day. Here's to hoping that temperatures chill out soon so that we can be comfortable during our peak season hawk watches! Until then, stay cool and drink lots of water! &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 122&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 2.67&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 45.69&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 58&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 46&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190913" rel="alternate" title="Friday, September 13, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190913" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jeremy Pallant and Taylor Barnes</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190912</id><published>2019-09-12T16:51:08.873-0700</published><updated>2019-09-12T16:51:08.873-0700</updated><title>Thursday, September 12, 2019</title><content type="html">Clear skies gave the hawkwatchers of Thursday I a 360-degree view around Hawk Hill as far out as the Farallons. The temperature steadily climbed as the day went on, and the raptors followed the warm updrafts high into the sky, making the "fifth" quadrant overhead busy all day. The steady flight of Accipiters continued from yesterday, as we spotted more Sharp-shinned Hawks. A light breeze from the South brought a young Broad-winged Hawk into view in front of the Golden Gate Bridge. A high-flying Northern Harrier snuck in among a small kettle of Red-tailed Hawks overhead. Not used to seeing Northern Harriers from so far below, the team relied on the bird's long tail, pointed wings, and deep wingbeats to identify it. Raptors were not the only exciting part of the day, as a Townsend's Solitaire breezed over Hawk Hill. Tomorrow's forecast calls for even warmer temperatures, so if you are planning on joining us on the hill, pack extra water and dress for success!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 360&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 60&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 9&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 137&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 22&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 36&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 140&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 12&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190912" rel="alternate" title="Thursday, September 12, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190912" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Paula Eberle &amp; Emma Regnier</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190911</id><published>2019-09-11T16:45:45.538-0700</published><updated>2019-09-11T16:45:45.538-0700</updated><title>Wednesday, September 11, 2019</title><content type="html">The morning was slow for raptor sightings, but the insects and other bird species were already on the move around Hawk Hill. We were thrilled to see two Monarch Butterflies within our first hour on the hill. We also spotted several Blue-gray Gnatcatchers, White-throated Swifts, Vaux's Swifts, a Great Egret, and a Red-breasted Nuthatch! Suddenly, a male American Kestrel appeared out of the fog in South Quadrant and soared overhead, showing off the bright white "string of pearls" on the trailing edge of his wings. Throughout the day, several distant mixed-species kettles tested our raptor ID knowledge and gave us the opportunity to use teamwork to successfully identify and pass the birds from quadrant to quadrant. A White-tailed Kite dropped in for a visit around lunchtime, and we watched it soar above the Golden Gate Bridge and disappear into the San Francisco skyline. With a westerly wind came an abundance of accipiters, which rekindled the age-old "Sharpie or Coop?" dilemma, but also provided an excellent learning experience for everyone on the hill. We had a busy and exciting day today and are looking forward to even more raptors as the migration picks up in the coming weeks!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 260&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 43.33&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 10&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 64&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 35&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 41&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 93&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 8&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 7&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190911" rel="alternate" title="Wednesday, September 11, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190911" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Maggie Brown &amp; Emma Regnier</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190910</id><published>2019-09-10T16:30:37.661-0700</published><updated>2019-09-10T16:30:37.661-0700</updated><title>Tuesday, September 10, 2019</title><content type="html">Today was sunny and warm, with clear views as far as the Geysers in the North and Mt. Diablo in the East. Shortly after unpacking at the hill, we were greeted by fleeting glimpses of a bobcat that disappeared into the chaparral around Fish Rock. As the morning went on, the birds took to the skies, and we saw Osprey, a few juvenile Sharp-shinned Hawks, Cooper's Hawks, and even a gliding adult Peregrine Falcon. A large group of energetic young students from Petaluma stopped at the Wingspans for a lesson on raptor biology and identification, and they had excellent questions about the current conservation status of raptor species, especially Peregrine Falcons. The students marveled at an extremely cooperative young Cooper's Hawk as it made several low passes just overhead. Towards the tail end of the count, we watched as two juvenile Red-tailed Hawks, one of which was a dark morph, dive-bombed each other, grappling talons over Kremin's Crag. Eventually the hawks settled their differences and flew across the Golden Gate together.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 201&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 33.5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 7&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 78&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 20&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 86&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 2&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190910" rel="alternate" title="Tuesday, September 10, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190910" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Emma Regnier and Jeremy Pallant</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190909</id><published>2019-09-09T16:36:35.511-0700</published><updated>2019-09-09T16:36:35.511-0700</updated><title>Monday, September 09, 2019</title><content type="html">The Monday I team enjoyed an awesome day of hawkwatching with clear skies, plenty of sunshine, and some exciting raptor activity! When we first arrived at Hawk Hill this morning, we started counting the usual Red-tailed Hawks and Turkey Vultures that circle the hill. As the wind picked up speed and the number of birds in the sky increased, we started seeing a greater variety of raptor species. In the afternoon, the team got a great view of a juvenile Broad-winged Hawk that flew directly over the hill. The most exciting moment of the day occurred when the team noticed a small raptor with pointed wings zooming around in the North Quadrant. We quickly gathered together and determined that it was a Merlin! About an hour later, we were lucky enough to get a glimpse of another Merlin flying high towards the Golden Gate Bridge. Since these were the first Merlin sightings of the season, we were super excited to have a second look at the flight style and characteristics of these quick, little falcons.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 184&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 30.67&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 11&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 61&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 9&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 93&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Merlin: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 5&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190909" rel="alternate" title="Monday, September 09, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190909" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Maggie Brown &amp; Veronica Pedraza</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190908</id><published>2019-09-08T16:47:59.780-0700</published><updated>2019-09-08T16:47:59.780-0700</updated><title>Sunday, September 08, 2019</title><content type="html">Today was a clear and sunny day up at Hawk Hill! We had a full day of counting raptors as the fog finally decided to stay away. The sunny skies brought visitors to our first Sunday hawk talk and we were delighted when an Osprey flew over for a close viewing. This was Sunday II team's first day on the hill after being fogged out two weeks ago. They were happily rewarded with this season's second Ferruginous Hawk sighting! With the fog finally clearing, we encourage future hawk watch teams to prepare for warmer weather, pack extra sunscreen, and get ready for an exciting peak!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 317&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 52.83&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 9&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 130&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 19&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 139&lt;br/&gt;
Ferruginous Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 10&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190908" rel="alternate" title="Sunday, September 08, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190908" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Taylor Barnes</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190907</id><published>2019-09-07T13:41:14.179-0700</published><updated>2019-09-07T13:41:14.179-0700</updated><title>Saturday, September 07, 2019</title><content type="html">For the second week in a row, the fog was not forgiving to the Saturday II team. In the morning, we spent about an hour birding on Rodeo Beach. Although there weren't many bird species of note, we were lucky enough to see two porpoises playing in the waves. In the late morning, the fog had risen and it looked like there was potential for the summit of Hawk Hill to clear, but we had no such luck. As we got to the top of the hill around lunch time, the fog rolled in again, obscuring visibility and preventing us from doing a count. However, despite the suboptimal hawkwatching conditions, we still had several dedicated visitors who stuck around to watch the season's first Hawk Talk. As the talk was finishing, they were rewarded with a great view of two juvenile Red-tailed Hawks and a juvenile Cooper's Hawk, who came to the hill undeterred by the fog. Here's to hoping for better weather when peak rolls around in a couple weeks! &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190907" rel="alternate" title="Saturday, September 07, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190907" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jeremy Pallant and Paula Eberle</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190906</id><published>2019-09-06T14:04:06.724-0700</published><updated>2019-09-06T14:04:06.724-0700</updated><title>Friday, September 06, 2019</title><content type="html">The hawk watchers did not make it up to the hill today to do an official count as the fog was too thick. That didn't stop the Friday II team from getting outside and taking a walk around Rodeo Lagoon. While out, the team spotted an Osprey flying over with its wings in the classic "M" shape. We're looking forward to clearer skies in our upcoming September hawk watching days. &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190906" rel="alternate" title="Friday, September 06, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190906" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Taylor Barnes</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190905</id><published>2019-09-05T15:30:47.583-0700</published><updated>2019-09-05T15:30:47.583-0700</updated><title>Thursday, September 05, 2019</title><content type="html">Despite some initial fog high above the hill, the Thursday II team started the day with good visibility in the lower areas of each quadrant. By the late morning, our visibility improved further, and we had clear skies above with a decent amount of raptor activity. We got a nice long look at an adult Red-shouldered Hawk that circled above Kirby Cove, and later observed an Osprey flying near the Golden Gate Bridge. By mid-afternoon the fog crept back in, but just as we were preparing to end our count, a flurry of four American Kestrels emerged from the fog and sped directly over Hawk Hill. It was an exciting way to end the day, and our team looks forward to what the rest of the season has in store!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 220&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 4.25&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 51.76&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 8&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 68&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 131&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 4&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190905" rel="alternate" title="Thursday, September 05, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190905" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Maggie Brown &amp; Jeremy Pallant</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190904</id><published>2019-09-04T13:58:26.779-0700</published><updated>2019-09-04T13:58:26.779-0700</updated><title>Wednesday, September 04, 2019</title><content type="html">Fog, fog, and more fog. Even though we're now into September, the August fog is still lingering. Unfortunately, the fog was too thick to make it up to the hill today, but the Wednesday II team still  made the best of the inopportune weather. We spent the morning birding around Rodeo Lagoon as we typically do on foggy days, and though visibility in the surrounding hills was poor, we still observed some neat birds. Our morning started off with a sighting of a juvenile Cooper's Hawk, which flew over Fort Cronkhite en route to Rodeo Beach, where it landed in the brush. Thanks to an excellent photo from a volunteer, we were able to see that the bird had a metal leg band, meaning it was probably banded recently at one of our blinds! We were also lucky enough to see a pair of Osprey surveying the water, although neither elected to dive into the lagoon in search of a late-morning snack. On our way back from the lagoon, we observed a small kettle of Red-tailed Hawks rising into the fog before disappearing from view. We also observed several interesting non-raptors, including recently fledged Common Yellowthroats, an Orange-Crowned Warbler, and a pair of vocalizing Virginia Rails which we were unable to find skulking in the marsh grass. Though we never made it up to the hill, we still had a great morning of birding and we're hoping for better luck next time around! Cheers from the Wednesday II team!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190904" rel="alternate" title="Wednesday, September 04, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190904" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Veronica Pedraza; Emma Regnier; and Jeremy Pallant</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190903</id><published>2019-09-03T14:31:09.132-0700</published><updated>2019-09-03T14:31:09.132-0700</updated><title>Tuesday, September 03, 2019</title><content type="html">Tuesday II's Fogwatch team spent the morning birding around Rodeo Lagoon waiting for the fog in the valley to lift. Armed with two scopes, we spotted a Killdeer and a Great Blue Heron foraging on the bank. Suddenly, a flash of brown wings drew our attention to a newcomer flying low over the lagoon. Luckily for us, this mystery bird perched on the fence line between the lagoon and the beach, and through the scope we saw its long, banded tail with a white terminal band and brown body - a juvenile Cooper's Hawk! We watched the young hawk until it took off into the brush and disappeared. Further along the lagoon, a flock of Red-necked Phalaropes was mingling with a trio of Pied-billed Grebes. Some notable mammalian sightings today included a Coyote crossing Bunker Road and two River Otters swimming among the reeds around the perimeter of the lagoon. Blues skies beckoned us up to Hawk Hill, but upon arriving, we discovered that the South and West Quadrants were still completely socked in with fog, so we did not start an official count. We've got our fingers crossed for better weather next time!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190903" rel="alternate" title="Tuesday, September 03, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190903" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Emma Regnier &amp; Veronica Pedraza</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190902</id><published>2019-09-02T14:15:33.702-0700</published><updated>2019-09-02T14:15:33.702-0700</updated><title>Monday, September 02, 2019</title><content type="html">The day started with clear skies and lots of enthusiasm from the Monday II team! We got up to the hill and were soon greeted by a juvenile Northern Harrier along with a few Turkey Vultures. Shortly after, we were also excited to see a dark morph juvenile Red-tailed Hawk glide past Hawk Hill and join a kettle of Red-tailed Hawks soaring above Kirby Cove. In the late morning, we got a nice look at the bright white crescents on the wings of a juvenile Red-shouldered Hawk. With it being Labor Day weekend, we enjoyed the company of many interested park visitors on the hill today. We were able to help them spot raptors around us and answer their thoughtful questions. Unfortunately, the fog began quickly rolling in to surround the hill around noon and we lost almost all visibility in each quadrant. Right before packing up for the day, we had an American Kestrel break through the fog and fly directly overhead. Although we ended our raptor count early due to the thick and persistent fog, everyone was still grateful for the opportunity to hawkwatch today.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 90&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 3.42&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 26.32&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 7&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 40&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 36&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 3&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190902" rel="alternate" title="Monday, September 02, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190902" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Maggie Brown &amp; Emma Regnier</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190901</id><published>2019-09-01T16:09:29.672-0700</published><updated>2019-09-01T16:09:29.672-0700</updated><title>Sunday, September 01, 2019</title><content type="html">The morning started off foggy but cleared enough for the team to start just before 11am. Hawk Hill was high enough to get us above the fog.  We got a few good hours of counting in before the fog rolled back over and surrounded us in the late afternoon. While visibility limited our bird sightings in the distance, some individuals decided to give us a closer look. These included a Cooper's Hawk, three American Kestrels, and many Red-tailed Hawks. An Osprey was also seen crossing the bridge towards the peninsula. &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 160&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 3.75&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 42.67&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 7&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 39&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 17&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 85&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 10&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190901" rel="alternate" title="Sunday, September 01, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190901" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Veronica Pedraza</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190831</id><published>2019-08-31T16:28:50.981-0700</published><updated>2019-08-31T16:28:50.981-0700</updated><title>Saturday, August 31, 2019</title><content type="html">While some fog in the morning started the Saturday 1 team with a walk around the lagoon, the sun won out and the team made it up to Hawk Hill for a full day of counting. The day turned out to be full of Red-tailed Hawks and Turkey Vultures, as well as the occasional Cooper's Hawk zooming by. By mid afternoon the team was lucky to see some more rare species, with three American Kestrels flying in for a close view right over the top of the quadrants. A Broad-winged Hawk also made a visit quickly after the Kestrels; a full two weeks before our first expected sighting! The day was closed out nicely with two Humpback Whales cruising through the bay, giving the team plenty of chances to spot them spouting. Here's to a successful start to the long weekend!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 231&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 4.75&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 48.63&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 7&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 79&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 13&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Broad-winged Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 112&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 12&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 21&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190831" rel="alternate" title="Saturday, August 31, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190831" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Paula Eberle</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190830</id><published>2019-08-30T14:07:39.591-0700</published><updated>2019-08-30T14:07:39.591-0700</updated><title>Friday, August 30, 2019</title><content type="html">It was another foggy day in the Marin Headlands. The Friday I team was hopeful for clear skies and waited patiently for the fog to move away but no such luck occurred. The team did make their way around Rodeo Lagoon where a juvenile Peregrine Falcon whizzed by at an incredible speed. The team also visited the Conzelman road roundabout where Turkey Vultures, Red-tailed Hawks, and a Cooper's Hawk all made an appearance. The hawk watchers got a glimpse of the banders at poak blind catch a juvenile Red-tailed Hawk which was an exciting sight. As Fog-ust comes to a close in just one day, we're hopeful that September will bring us clearer skies with many more bird sightings!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190830" rel="alternate" title="Friday, August 30, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190830" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Taylor Barnes</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190829</id><published>2019-08-29T16:29:20.765-0700</published><updated>2019-08-29T16:29:20.765-0700</updated><title>Thursday, August 29, 2019</title><content type="html">The sun was shining on Thursday I's team today! Partly cloudy skies and a breeze from the West made for good hawkwatching today on Hawk Hill. We started off the morning right with a flashy young Northern Harrier that worked its way around the hill, giving everyone a good look at its pumpkin-colored collar and flanks. A juvenile Cooper's Hawk also put on a show, circling in close above the hawkwatchers. Today was a great day for Red-tailed Hawks with 109 sightings, including #LH31L, who sports a lavender color band on its left leg. LH31L even joined us for lunch, as it was seen eating a snake in a dead snag on Hawk Hill! We're very grateful for this warm and sunny break from the fog, and we wish tomorrow's team the same luck!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 224&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5.5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 40.73&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 97&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 109&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 8&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190829" rel="alternate" title="Thursday, August 29, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190829" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Emma Regnier and Paula Eberle</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190828</id><published>2019-08-28T13:29:49.574-0700</published><updated>2019-08-28T13:29:49.574-0700</updated><title>Wednesday, August 28, 2019</title><content type="html">Today was another day of thick fog in the Marin Headlands which prevented the Wednesday I team from conducting an official raptor count on Hawk Hill. Instead, we spent some extra time inside working on our raptor ID skills so that we feel more prepared for peak migration to start in just a few weeks. We then went for a walk around Rodeo Lagoon, and saw Red-necked Phalaropes, Marbled Godwits, Great Egrets, a Great Blue Heron, a Pied-billed Grebe, and a Common Yellowthroat. We were also pleased to see several Turkey Vultures circling in and out of the foggy sky above us. Despite the low visibility, we still had a great day of birding and look forward to our next day on the hill!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190828" rel="alternate" title="Wednesday, August 28, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190828" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Maggie Brown</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190827</id><published>2019-08-27T13:05:34.395-0700</published><updated>2019-08-27T13:05:34.395-0700</updated><title>Tuesday, August 27, 2019</title><content type="html">This is Fog Blog Episode IV: A New Hope. Glimpses of blue sky above Rodeo Lagoon gave us hope for the hawkwatch today, but sadly, the fog atop Hawk Hill was here to stay. We turned our binoculars to the trees around the Headlands Center for the Arts and the lagoon, spotting several Red-necked Phalaropes, Pied-billed Grebes, and one Ruddy Duck. A couple of Yellow Warblers flitted by, reminding us that, despite the dismal weather conditions, there are still migrants on the move. Our first raptor of the day was a young Cooper's Hawk seen atop a telephone pole near the GGRO Office. We enjoyed a lovely team picnic outside of the Marin Headlands Visitor Center, where we spotted a few Red-tailed Hawks and Turkey Vultures soaring low through the valley. We can't wait to get back up on Hawk Hill next time!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190827" rel="alternate" title="Tuesday, August 27, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190827" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Emma Regnier</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190826</id><published>2019-08-26T16:16:04.154-0700</published><updated>2019-08-26T16:16:04.154-0700</updated><title>Monday, August 26, 2019</title><content type="html">Today was our first day back on the hill after three days of fog! The day started sunny and warm with clear skies above and some low fog in the distance. As the day continued, the wind picked up and the fog slowly started to creep up on us. However, we still managed to get in a full day of hawkwatching and got to see a Peregrine Falcon perched on the North Tower of the Golden Gate Bridge. During moments of slow raptor activity throughout the day, the Monday I team enjoyed watching other wildlife around Hawk Hill, including Blue-gray Gnatcatchers and Anise Swallowtail butterflies. It was a great way to start the second cycle of the season!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 103&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5.58&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 18.46&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 45&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 50&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190826" rel="alternate" title="Monday, August 26, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190826" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Veronica Pedraza</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190825</id><published>2019-08-25T13:31:09.119-0700</published><updated>2019-08-25T13:31:09.119-0700</updated><title>Sunday, August 25, 2019</title><content type="html">Welcome to fog blog day 3! Unfortunately, dense fog prevented the Sunday II team from hawk watching today. However, the team had a great morning of introductions and getting to know each other. Bird watching around Rodeo Lagoon did take place and many interesting species were seen including more Red-necked Phalaropes, Great Blue Herons, Turkey Vultures, and Red-tailed Hawks. The Sunday II team is hopeful for sunny and clear skies and remains positive for their future hawk watching days!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190825" rel="alternate" title="Sunday, August 25, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190825" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Taylor Barnes</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190824</id><published>2019-08-24T14:11:33.360-0700</published><updated>2019-08-24T14:11:33.360-0700</updated><title>Saturday, August 24, 2019</title><content type="html">Time for another Fog Blog! The Saturday II team got fogged out today but spent the day around the Headlands birding and getting to know each other. The Red-necked Phalaropes were still out in the eastern side of Rodeo Lagoon and were joined by some Pied-billed Grebes. While at the lagoon, the team got a wonderful surprise of hearing the calls of a Sora that was hiding deep in the reeds! Despite never making it out to Hawk Hill, the day was not devoid of raptors, with a close flyby from a beautiful rufous colored Red-Tailed Hawk and a sighting of a female American Kestrel. Here's hoping for some clear days to come!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190824" rel="alternate" title="Saturday, August 24, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190824" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Paula Eberle</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190823</id><published>2019-08-23T14:01:45.165-0700</published><updated>2019-08-23T14:01:45.165-0700</updated><title>Friday, August 23, 2019</title><content type="html">The fog was heavy today but that didn't stop the Friday II team from having a great morning of bird-watching. Although the hawk watchers did not make it up to the hill for the count, plenty of raptors were seen flying over Rodeo Lagoon. This included some Turkey vultures and Red-tailed hawks that flew just within eyesight below the fog. The team also spotted some Red-necked phalaropes, Baird's sandpipers, and even river otters! The fog could not keep down this team's positive attitude for a successful hawk watching season. &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190823" rel="alternate" title="Friday, August 23, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190823" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Taylor Barnes</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190822</id><published>2019-08-22T16:08:11.318-0700</published><updated>2019-08-22T16:08:11.318-0700</updated><title>Thursday, August 22, 2019</title><content type="html">It was a strange day on Hawk Hill, at least with respect to the weather. In the morning, fog was swirling all around the base of the hill, obscuring our sight lines in three of the four quadrants. However, visibility above the fog line was nearly perfect, with unobscured views of Mt. Diablo, Mt. Tamalpais, and the Sutro Tower. Because of the low-hanging fog, we didn't officially begin our count until just before noon, when the fog cleared enough to provide clear raptor viewing in the North and East quadrants. In the early afternoon, we got great views of a juvenile Northern Harrier, which circled Hawk Hill for several minutes before heading south across the Golden Gate. Several small kettles of Red-tailed Hawks were also seen high above the Golden Gate Bridge. In the middle of our afternoon hawkwatching, fog began to creep up the hill and our counting was again confined to small portions of the North and East quadrants. But with about an hour left before we called it quits for the afternoon, the skies cleared in all but the South quadrant, and we picked up several new species for the day, including an American Kestrel, a Sharp-Shinned Hawk, and a White-Tailed Kite. Considering the constraints placed upon us by the weather, our final tallies of 76 raptors and 8 species were very solid for a relatively short day of hawkwatching. &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 76&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 3.42&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 22.22&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 8&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 12&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 53&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190822" rel="alternate" title="Thursday, August 22, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190822" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jeremy Pallant</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190821</id><published>2019-08-21T16:33:12.019-0700</published><updated>2019-08-21T16:33:12.019-0700</updated><title>Wednesday, August 21, 2019</title><content type="html">It was another beautiful day on Hawk Hill! Although a bit warm, there was a light breeze and clear skies as far as the eye could see. The day of hawkwatching had ebbs and flows, with some stretches lacking birds and others showing lots of activity. In the late morning, we were fortunate enough to see a juvenile Osprey, a juvenile Red-shouldered Hawk sporting ivory crescents in its wings, and a few Northern Harriers, including a juvenile eating a vole on the wing. In the early afternoon, there was a lull characterized by low windspeeds and reduced bird movement. But in the last couple hours of the day, activity picked up significantly, with several excellent sightings just before day's end. These sightings included one more juvenile Red-shouldered Hawk, another Osprey, a female American Kestrel, a dark-morph Red-tailed Hawk, and a juvenile  Sharp-shinned Hawk being chased off the hill by a hummingbird. Our finally tally for the day was 8 total species, a very solid species diversity considering we're still in the middle of August. We can't wait to be out on the hill again in a couple weeks! Until then, all the best from the Wednesday II team! &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 128&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 25.6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 8&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 66&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 47&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 3&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190821" rel="alternate" title="Wednesday, August 21, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190821" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Veronica Pedraza</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190820</id><published>2019-08-20T15:17:24.967-0700</published><updated>2019-08-20T15:17:24.967-0700</updated><title>Tuesday, August 20, 2019</title><content type="html">The day started out promising, with strong winds from the North blowing in handfuls of young Red-tailed Hawks and one Northern Harrier over the ridgelines. Turkey Vulture #368 made another guest appearance and circled the Hawkwatchers several times before disappearing into the approaching fog. The fog began to creep up around the hill around 1 pm, but the East and South Quadrants remained clear, so we continued our raptor count. Despite our stubbornness, the fog completely closed in around us within the hour, and visibility dropped dramatically. Because none of the quadrants could reliably see nor count any raptors, the call to return to the GGRO office was made shortly thereafter, so we packed up our scopes and headed down the hill for the day. &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 51&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 2.83&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 18.02&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 4&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 28&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 19&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 2&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190820" rel="alternate" title="Tuesday, August 20, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190820" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Emma Regnier</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190819</id><published>2019-08-19T14:02:32.659-0700</published><updated>2019-08-19T14:02:32.659-0700</updated><title>Monday, August 19, 2019</title><content type="html">Fog-ust is here in full force, and unfortunately the thick fog and low visibility on Hawk Hill prevented our raptor count today. We spent some extra time in the office this morning working on our raptor ID skills and discussing tricky field marks with the hope that the fog would lift in the meantime. We trekked up to Hawk Hill for a short visit to practice identifying the nearby landmarks and get familiar with the rhythm of our team. Unable to see even the resident ravens through the fog, we descended the hill and hiked along the Coastal Trail to look for birds and other wildlife. Luckily, the fog didn't put a damper on the group's energy, and we can't wait to return and put our landmark and ID skills to the test!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190819" rel="alternate" title="Monday, August 19, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190819" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Emma Regnier</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190818</id><published>2019-08-18T17:44:17.404-0700</published><updated>2019-08-18T17:44:17.404-0700</updated><title>Sunday, August 18, 2019</title><content type="html">Today was a beautiful day up at the hill! The morning started off foggy but cleared up and left us with blue skies and clear sights. Our hawk watchers were filled with excitement and enthusiasm when an adult Peregrine Falcon zipped by 3 times! We saw a total of 95 birds today which is a great way to end the first week of the 2019 season. &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 95&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 4.25&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 22.35&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 44&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 41&lt;br/&gt;
Peregrine Falcon: 3&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Accipiter: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 2&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190818" rel="alternate" title="Sunday, August 18, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190818" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Taylor Barnes</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190817</id><published>2019-08-17T15:11:11.319-0700</published><updated>2019-08-17T15:11:11.319-0700</updated><title>Saturday, August 17, 2019</title><content type="html">Unfortunately, fog prevented the Saturday I team from counting raptors today. During the morning, we did a brief survey of the birds in Rodeo Lagoon. The highlights of our quick trip to the lagoon include  Snowy and Great Egrets, a Pied-Billed Grebe, a Great Blue Heron, a Willet, and a Caspian Tern. We did make the trek up to the top of Hawk Hill in the late morning, but by mid-afternoon the fog hadn't let up. There were a few Red-Tailed Hawks circling the hill that could be seen through the fog, but visibility was not good enough to conduct an official raptor survey. While we wish the weather could have been better today, we're also happy to hear how much success the teams earlier this week had! Hopefully in a couple weeks, we'll have a better chance to count some hawks! Until next time, cheers from the Saturday I team! &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190817" rel="alternate" title="Saturday, August 17, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190817" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jeremy Pallant</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190816</id><published>2019-08-16T17:42:46.244-0700</published><updated>2019-08-16T17:42:46.244-0700</updated><title>Friday, August 16, 2019</title><content type="html">It was a windy day up on the hill today! With winds gusting up to 25 miles per hour, we were definitely holding onto our hats while hawk watching today! However, despite the wind, visibility was great and there was still a fair amount of raptor movement. We saw a total of 126 birds today, representing 5 different species. While the vast majority of our birds were the usual suspects (i.e. Red-Tailed Hawks, Turkey Vultures, Northern Harriers, and Cooper's Hawks), we were lucky enough to have the season's first sighting of a Bald Eagle, a young juvenile that passed over the hill heading North. We've already seen 12 species so far this season, which is quite a few for the first week, so we're optimistic about what we'll see in the coming weeks! All the best from the Friday I team!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 126&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5.33&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 23.64&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 38&lt;br/&gt;
Bald Eagle: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 3&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 2&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 82&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190816" rel="alternate" title="Friday, August 16, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190816" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Jeremy Pallant</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190815</id><published>2019-08-15T16:37:20.359-0700</published><updated>2019-08-15T16:37:20.359-0700</updated><title>Thursday, August 15, 2019</title><content type="html">Another beautiful day out on Hawk Hill! The strong winds from the West blew in some interesting birds throughout the afternoon. Between a flurry of young Red-Tailed Hawks and a few elusive Cooper's Hawks, we spotted an Osprey cruising across the North Quadrant. One of Hawk Hill's celebrity tagged Turkey Vultures, number 368, breezed by the Hawkwatchers up close and personal. The distressed calls from a juvenile Red-Tailed Hawk hinted us to our first sighting this season of an adult Golden Eagle, circling over the Golden Gate Bridge. The whole team was able to get eyes on this large raptor and marvel at how it dwarfed the nearby Red-Tailed Hawks. Within the same hour, another enormous bird soared into view and flashed its white tail and primaries, indicative of yet another Golden Eagle, this time a juvenile. By the end of the day our Hawkwatch team had doubled in size, and every in between cardinal direction was covered. Thanks to everyone who came out today!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 131&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 26.2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 48&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 73&lt;br/&gt;
Golden Eagle: 2&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 2&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190815" rel="alternate" title="Thursday, August 15, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190815" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Paula Eberle</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190814</id><published>2019-08-14T17:28:45.690-0700</published><updated>2019-08-14T17:28:45.690-0700</updated><title>Wednesday, August 14, 2019</title><content type="html">Today was a hot day on Hawk Hill! The birds must have thought so too since we had a pretty slow morning. Raptor activity picked up in the early afternoon as the ocean breeze swept in. Thanks to the clear skies all day long we were able to count raptors in all quadrants, especially the South and East. While we saw plenty of our usual guests around the hill, such as Turkey Vultures and Red-tailed Hawks, we also counted several Cooper's Hawks, a Sharp-shinned Hawk, and a juvenile Red-shouldered Hawk. We were all taken by surprise when a brilliant adult Ferruginous Hawk appeared in our East Quadrant and soared above the north end of the Golden Gate Bridge for over 30 minutes! It is unusual to see an adult Ferruginous Hawk this early in the season, so it was an exciting surprise for our third day of hawkwatching!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 88&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 17.6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 6&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 44&lt;br/&gt;
Sharp-shinned Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 6&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 30&lt;br/&gt;
Ferruginous Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Buteo: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 4&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 5&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190814" rel="alternate" title="Wednesday, August 14, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190814" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Maggie Brown</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190813</id><published>2019-08-13T17:23:22.721-0700</published><updated>2019-08-13T17:23:22.721-0700</updated><title>Tuesday, August 13, 2019</title><content type="html">Another day of sunshine and mainly clear skies up on Hawk Hill! We started off the day right with two Osprey - the first of the season - spotted right as we began our count. A handful of Turkey Vultures and Red-tailed Hawks were spotted each hour, and one young Cooper's Hawk even treated us to a close flyover. We saw one juvenile Northern Harrier, one juvenile Red-shouldered Hawk, and two female American Kestrels (the first kestrels of the season!), but the real highlight of the afternoon was a White-tailed Kite! The migration is already off to a terrific start this year!&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 105&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 21&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 8&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 64&lt;br/&gt;
Osprey: 2&lt;br/&gt;
White-tailed Kite: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 7&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 26&lt;br/&gt;
American Kestrel: 2&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Unidentified...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Raptor: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Total unidentified: 1&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190813" rel="alternate" title="Tuesday, August 13, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190813" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Emma Regnier</name></author></entry>

<entry><id>hydromatic-ggro-20190812</id><published>2019-08-12T17:02:58.763-0700</published><updated>2019-08-12T17:02:58.763-0700</updated><title>Monday, August 12, 2019</title><content type="html">Happy first day of the 2019 raptor migration season! We had a (mostly) clear day on Hawk Hill with plenty of sunshine, which allowed us to stay out and count birds all day. We started off the season counting many Turkey Vultures and Red-tailed Hawks, some Cooper's Hawks, a few Red-shouldered Hawks, and even a Northern Harrier! With the great enthusiasm of our volunteers and staff, we know that we have an awesome season ahead of us.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Sightings:&lt;/strong&gt; 99&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Hours Counted:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;HPH:&lt;/strong&gt; 19.8&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Total Species:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Species Counts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Turkey Vulture: 64&lt;br/&gt;
Northern Harrier: 1&lt;br/&gt;
Cooper's Hawk: 9&lt;br/&gt;
Red-shouldered Hawk: 5&lt;br/&gt;
Red-tailed Hawk: 20&lt;br/&gt;
</content><link href="http://www.parksconservancy.org/conservation/plants-animals/raptors/research/daily-hawk-count.html#20190812" rel="alternate" title="Monday, August 12, 2019" type="text/html"/><link href="http://www.ggro.org/feed.xml#20190812" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><author><name>Maggie Brown</name></author></entry>

</feed>
